Bedreschein - Dec. 2d. 1907.      This little record of travel should have begun a month ago - as we sailed from <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> just a month ago - the 2d of Nov. on the Freiderick der Grosse. We had a rough unpleasant passage - there was no day on which I could have written with comfort. It was the worst passage I ever made. On some days, the best thing was to stay in bed - and that was a difficult thing to do. A friend of ours was thrown from his berth, and dislocated his shoulder - several accidents occured - sprains etc. Reached <LOCATION>Naples</LOCATION> finally the morning of the 15th. Dr. <PERSON>Baldwin</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Rome</LOCATION>, and Mrs. <PERSON>Beck</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Milwaukie</LOCATION>, were on the boat, and added much to the pleasure of the voyage - coming when possible to my sitting room for tea. We knew that <PERSON>Nettie</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> would be waiting for us at <LOCATION>Naples</LOCATION>, and we hoped to have at least a night and day with <PERSON>Nettie</PERSON> at the <LOCATION>Grand Hotel</LOCATION>. But we were so belated that we had only time to drive to the hotel and get them, and drive back to the dock - and that was so disappointing. <PERSON>David Costantini</PERSON> was there also - and Mrs. <PERSON>Baldwin</PERSON> who had come from <LOCATION>Rome</LOCATION> to meet her husband - the voyage across the <LOCATION>Mediterranean</LOCATION> was as charming as the other was horrid. We arrived at <LOCATION>Alexandria</LOCATION> at 8 o’clock on Monday the 18th, stopped at the <LOCATION>New Khedivial Hotel</LOCATION> long enough to have a lunch put up for us, then paid a visit to the Museum (our first) though it is hardly worth a visit, and were off for <LOCATION>Cairo</LOCATION> at noon - and found our old rooms ready for us, and were eating dinner on the evening of the 16th. A sister with them - a quiet, beautiful day from <LOCATION>N.Y</LOCATION>. A very good record. We got away from <LOCATION>Cairo</LOCATION> today - having settled ourselves on the Beduin the 1st. We tried to get through the bridge yesterday - but there was such a crowd of gyassas at the draw, that we waited for most of them, dreading the dangers of that shouting, reckless, unmanageable crowd - but the Bridge time was up before they had all passed, and the draw was shut in our faces. We tied up at the <ORGANIZATION>Kasr el Nil</ORGANIZATION> barracks, and waited for today. We were so near when the draw was opened at 1 o’clock that we started as soon as the down boats had got through - but there was a good wind, and the reckless gyassas in spite of orders and shreiks of the bridge officers crowded upon us in full sail - and it was a very nasty twenty mimrtes we had - such noise, such frantic efforts. One of them crashed her bow into us, fortunately broke her bow sprit, and left her anchor embedded in the landing stage, or she would have ripper our side open. She did break one of the window frames, but luckily spared the glass, knocked much of our nice new paint off us etc. One of our men took out the window frame, and we left him in <LOCATION>Cairo</LOCATION>, to take it to the carpenters and painters. He rejoined us at <LOCATION>Tourah</LOCATION> by rail and says the carpenters and painters will reach <LOCATION>Bedreshein</LOCATION> tomorrow at 8 o’clock. As <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> are to make a visit to <PERSON>Sakkarah</PERSON> we will not be detained.      We saw Capt. <PERSON>Trefusis</PERSON> and his sweet sister <PERSON>Evelyn</PERSON> who is out with him this winter. They lunched with us several times, and she came in to stay one night (they are staying at <LOCATION>Helouan</LOCATION>) and go with <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> early the next morning to see the ceremony of the Kishwa. He is now in a large business at <LOCATION>Cairo</LOCATION>. We also made the acquaintance of Lord [illegible]’s eldest son, <PERSON>Viscount Fielding</PERSON>. He is in the Coldstream Guards, who have lately been sent out here. He is a nice young fellow simple and natural. Mrs. <PERSON>Peck</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Milwaukie</LOCATION> was at <LOCATION>Shepheards</LOCATION> most of the time we were there, and we saw much of her. <LOCATION>Cairo</LOCATION>, and the whole of <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> is now in serious financial straits, following the absurd speculative craze of the last 2 years. Prices are incredibly high. Tuesday, Dec. 3rd.     I have had a busy day settling - while <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> went to <PERSON>Sakkarah</PERSON>. A lovely day. The <PERSON>Ramesis</PERSON> was lying by us all day - with a handful of passengers - but went off at 6 o’clock. The carpenter and painter have been here all day repairing damages. Wednesday, Dec. 4.      41 miles. 	We get away from <LOCATION>Bedraschein</LOCATION> at 7 o’clock this morning - and have had a lovely day - river like glass, both of our sails out much of the time. The river is enormously broad about here. When I went on deck about 4 o’clock, I found a scene of ravishing beauty - the broad smooth river, the distant cliffs and Mts. and desert, with the heliotrope shadows, and the soft brilliant sun. It was too entrancing. We had tea on deck - and are now lying opposite Wasta. Thursday, Dec. 5th.      29 miles. 	A quiet uneventful day - though the tug went on the sand once for a few minutes. It is a slow heavy tug, but was the only one cook had reoccupied. We are about a mile above <LOCATION>Ribbeh</LOCATION>. Friday, Dec. 6th.      25 miles. 	Our tug, Anubis by name, went on the sand soon after nine this morning, and got off at 10:25. The river is so very broad here, that it is difficult to find the channel. The gyassas seemed to be having as much trouble as we had. Such a wonderful sunset - the sky, crimson pink with one long narrow cloud near the horizon, above which shone Venus, quite resplendent, and the new moon, the veriest silver thread of a little crescent, just below the cloud. Saturday, Dec. 7.      44 miles. 	Made an early start - and tied up at 5:30 within 3 miles of <LOCATION>Minia</LOCATION>. Lovely day, and perfect evening. Second Sunday in Advent. Dec. 8th.      28-1/2 miles. 	A very heavy fog on the river this morning delayed our starting until 9:25 - spent about 2 hours at <LOCATION>Minia</LOCATION> waiting for mail and express parcels - a good sailing day - tied up at <ORGANIZATION>Redah</ORGANIZATION> about 6 o’clock. Monday. Dec. 9th.      41-1/2 miles. 	Started at 6 o’clock - a cloudy day - and cold wind. Passed <PERSON>Mellawi</PERSON>, <PERSON>Hadji Kandel</PERSON>, and the <PERSON>Gebel Abu Feda</PERSON> and pulled up opposite Menfalout at 6 o’clock. We missed our channel this afternoon and had to go back to find it. It was a wonderful sight passing the <PERSON>Gebel</PERSON>. In all the years I have been on the Nile, I have not see such a transcendently beautiful sunset - and the colour reflected from the rocks made a great effect. Tuesday, Dec. 10. <LOCATION>Asyut</LOCATION>.      8 miles. 	Arrived at 1 o’clock having had the tug one hour on the sand. <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> dismissed the tug at 2 o’clock and we sailed at 3:30 - quite a good wind until 6 p.m. at which hour we tied up for the night, 8 miles above <LOCATION>Asyut</LOCATION>. It seemed very good to get rid of the tug. They are only tolerable to make speed, and this one couldn’t do it. Last year the Thothmes took us in 10 days to <LOCATION>Luxor</LOCATION>. This year the <PERSON>Anubis</PERSON> took 9 days to go to <LOCATION>Asyût</LOCATION>. Wednesday, Dec. 11th.      19 miles. 	We had no wind until noon - but a very good one until 5:40 when we tied up and with the towing we did before noon we made our 19 miles - lovely and warm. Thursday, Dec. 12. <LOCATION>Sohag</LOCATION>. 	     41-1/2 miles. 	Started at 7 - the wind freshened finely at 8 o’clock and we came splendidly on until within a mile of the <LOCATION>Sohag</LOCATION> about 7 o’clock we struck the sand sharply - and were there 3/4 of an hour. Earlier in the afternoon we came near having a serious experience, - just as we approached the landing stage at <LOCATION>Tahta</LOCATION> which was crowded with gyassas and people, the wind shifted, and at that moment a gyassas, crowded with people, pushed out before our prow. We could give her no room - in spite of the yells and cries of our men she came on - and disaster seemed certain for if we had struck her we would have capsized here and gone over her. It is impossible to say why this kind of thing occurs so often - it is one of the greatest dangers on the Nile. A delightful day. Friday, Dec. 13.      28-1/2 miles. 	We waited at <LOCATION>Sohgg</LOCATION> this morning until 9:30 for mail and provisions. Stopped within 4 miles of <LOCATION>Balliana</LOCATION> at 6 P.M. A good wind, a heavenly day. The nights too, with the young moon and the resplendent <PERSON>Venus</PERSON>, are wonderful. Saturday, Dec. 14.      8-1/2 miles. 	A perfectly calm morning - but tracking and polling we made <PERSON>Balliana</PERSON> at 4:30 - no mail, so we were off at once, and with a light wind went on until 6 P.M.Sunday - Third in Advent. Dec. 15.     6 miles. 	A perfectly windless day - bright and hot. Our men have worked like Trojans every minute of the day - polling and tracking, we think we have made 6 miles. Monday, Dec. 16.       A repetition of yesterday - clear, hot, windless day. The men have been polling, tracking, pulling to anchor in the burning sun all day. <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> thinks we have made about 12 miles. We are now at <PERSON>Nagh Hamadi</PERSON>, waiting to pass the bridge tomorrow. Tuesday, Dec. 17.      30 miles. 	Keneh. We got quietly through the bridge at 8 o’clock this morning. Found the <ORGANIZATION>Istar</ORGANIZATION> lying there, closed, and with flags down. Her men said that Mr. <PERSON>Sayce</PERSON> had gone to <LOCATION>Cairo</LOCATION> to see his dentist. We have had a splendid day and fine wind, and are now lying at <LOCATION>Dendera</LOCATION>, as <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> wants <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> to see it tomorrow. Wednesday, Dec. 18.      18 miles. 	We got off as soon as T. and C. came back from the <LOCATION>Temple</LOCATION>, about 11 o’clock - and with good wind came to within 4 miles of <LOCATION>Nagadah</LOCATION>. Thursday, Dec. 19      21 miles. 	Started early, 6 o’clock, hoping to make <LOCATION>Luxor</LOCATION> tonight, but are tied up 4 miles below it. Very contrary and shifting wind - and cold - pulled to the anchor for hours. Beautiful night. Friday, Dec. 20.      <PERSON>Luxer</PERSON> at last, arriving at 10:30 this morning. Came to our usual mooring place opposite the Castle - and soon the men were busy settling us. A huge mail waiting for us. <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> went to <LOCATION>Karnac</LOCATION> this afternoon. Saturday, Dec. 21.     I was at home all day. <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> went to the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> to look at the pit tomb <PERSON>Ayrton</PERSON> wrote about. They opened it - it proved only a pit with large vases - some sealed - some more or less broken. They report our little house finished, but too damp to live in at present - though <PERSON>Ayrton</PERSON> is living in one room. The <PERSON>Miriam</PERSON>, with tug Thothmes got in about 5 P.M. I received a note from <PERSON>Madame Maspero</PERSON>. They leave early tomorrow morning - bound for <LOCATION>Aswân</LOCATION>, and Halfa. One of the most wonderful moon rises this evening. Fourth Sunday in Advent. Dec. 22nd.      Theor and <PERSON>Carri</PERSON> again to the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> - but <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> this time on a donkey - an exquisite day. I have had a beautiful quiet Sunday. This morning I was amused watching the loading of 2 camels with all our furnishings for our house in the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION>. One of the camels had the most delicious young camel with her - about a month old I should think, a lovely creature - so affectionate to its mother and so full of life and pranks. Monday, Dec. 23rd.      All went over to the town this morning - <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> and I to see Miss <PERSON>Buchanan</PERSON> - then to Mrs. <PERSON>Weigalls</PERSON> and saw the new baby - and I delivered the cup I brought over for <PERSON>Corinna Smith</PERSON>. Then I went to see poor Mrs. <PERSON>Murch</PERSON> - who is most sad - but very brave. Then we encountered <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> on our way home - and stopped at the Winter Palace to see the Iddings. Mr. <PERSON>Iddings</PERSON>, the girl, <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> and <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> went to <LOCATION>Karnak</LOCATION> at 4 o’clock and Mrs. <PERSON>Iddings</PERSON> came over and had tea with me. Tuesday, Dec. 24.      I have been busy all day in the boat, first getting my pots of bulbs into order - then the Christmas presents for the men - in which <PERSON>Jones</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> helped - and so did not go out - the morning lovely, but cold high winds this afternoon. <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> went at 3 o’clock to <PERSON>Medinet Habu</PERSON>. Dec. 25. Wednesday. Christmas.      A beautiful winters day - the distribution of presents to the men went off successfully. Mr. <PERSON>Ayrton</PERSON> came over to spend the night, and Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Iddings</PERSON> came to dine - and we had a concert from the men, which amused the <PERSON>Iddings</PERSON> very much. Thursday, Dec. 26.      <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> and I went over to the Winter Palace to lunch with the Iddings. They had such pleasant rooms - and the whole house looked very attractive. <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> and Theo to <LOCATION>Der el Bahari</LOCATION> in the afternoon. Friday, Dec. 27.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> went over to the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> for lunch, and had Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Iddings</PERSON> and their girls to lunch in the little house. They were delighted. Mr. <PERSON>Sayce</PERSON> called in the afternoon. Saturday, Dec. 28.      A quiet day, mostly at home. <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> at the Weigalls for tea, and afterwards met the <PERSON>Iddings</PERSON> at <LOCATION>Karnae</LOCATION>. Sunday, Dec. 29.      The <PERSON>Iddings</PERSON> came over this morning to say good-bye - were very nice and friendly. Mr. <PERSON>Sayce</PERSON> at dinner. Monday, Dec. 30.      Over in <LOCATION>Luxor</LOCATION> this morning - Theo and Mr. <PERSON>Sayce</PERSON> at shops. Tuesday, Dec. 31.      At last a windless day. The Misses <PERSON>Collins</PERSON> came to tea - such a pleasant visit. Jan. 1. 1908.      We went over to the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> this morning for the day - Theodore having invited Sir <PERSON>Malcolm McIlwraith</PERSON> and his wife to lunch with us. A sister was with them - a quiet, beautiful day. Jan. 2nd.      Another quiet fine day. <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> paid some visits in <LOCATION>Luxor</LOCATION>, and took <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> to the races this afternoon. Jan. 3rd.      Mr. <PERSON>Edmund Hayes</PERSON> and his daughter lunched with us, and <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> went with them after to <PERSON>Der el Medinet</PERSON>, and <PERSON>Medinet Habu</PERSON>. Jan. 4th     A warm wind - quiet day at home for me, <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and Carry to <LOCATION>Karnak</LOCATION>. Jan. 5th.      Mr. <PERSON>Erskine</PERSON> to dinner. <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> to the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> this morning - coming home he reports a promising tomb in sight - thinks it will take several days to clear the doorway. Jan. 6th.      At home all day. Theo at <LOCATION>Karnak</LOCATION>. Jan. 7th.      Mr. <PERSON>Haynes</PERSON> called to say goodbye. Jan. 8th.      Theo at the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> today - very hot. He thinks the tomb will prove only a pit tomb. Mr. <PERSON>Erskine</PERSON> lunched with us and <PERSON>Ayrton</PERSON> came over for the night. Jan. 9th.      The tomb proves to be a shaft 30 ft. long - with a room about 20 ft. Water has been in it. Jan. 10th.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> to <LOCATION>Karnac</LOCATION>. I had a delightful visit from Mrs. <PERSON>Gardner</PERSON>. Jan. 11th.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> a long ride into the country. Jan. 12th.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> at the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION>. The tomb proves to be filled with an accretion of gravel and dried mud 5 ft. deep - exceedingly hard. <PERSON>Ayrton</PERSON> began the clearing this morning - at the S.W. corner, and on reaching 2 ft. from the bottom, came upon a deposit of silver and gold objects of most unique importance and value. They were busy with these all afternoon - containing cartouches of Sety II and Tausert - all of which <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> brought home with him.      Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Weigall</PERSON>, and Mrs. <PERSON>Craggs</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ayrton</PERSON> to dinner. Jan. 13th.      <PERSON>Ayrton</PERSON> here all day - inexpressibly shocked to hear of dear Miss <PERSON>Frances Collins</PERSON>’ death in church last evening. She was playing the organ in the little chapel and was in the midst of the “Gloria” when she suddenly stood up and fell to the floor dead! It was a beautiful passing away of her lovely, useful spirit. Jan. 14. Tuesday.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> went to <PERSON>Barnac</PERSON> at 4 o’clock. Mr. <PERSON>Winlock</PERSON> called with letter of introduction from <PERSON>Harold Jones</PERSON>. Jan. 16. Wednesday.      Cold, cloudy day. <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> to the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION>. Several beads etc. had been found. Jan. 16th. Thursday.      Mr. <PERSON>Humphreys</PERSON> called and Miss <PERSON>Buchanan</PERSON> and friend. Cloudy cold day - strong S. W. wind. <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> and I went over to the <LOCATION>Luxor</LOCATION>, to see the two old Miss <PERSON>Collins</PERSON> - so sad. Jan. 17th. Friday.      Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Elliot Smith</PERSON> and her sister called soon after breakfast on their way to the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION>. We started ourselves after they left, as the Gorsts were to lunch with us. They arrived in time. Sir <PERSON>Eldon</PERSON>, <PERSON>Lady Gorst</PERSON>, his Sec. and Mrs. <PERSON>Weigall</PERSON>. It was a very pleasant lunch. I liked Sir <PERSON>Eldon</PERSON> very much - Lady G. exceedingly pretty and chic. <PERSON>Ayrton</PERSON> found a few more small gold objects yesterday. The Gorsts came to tea with us after we got home, to see all the gold. Jan. 18. Saturday.      We had the whole <LOCATION>Devonshire</LOCATION> party to tea this afternoon to see the find. The Duke, the Duchess, her daughter <PERSON>Lady Gasford</PERSON>, and Lord <PERSON>Gasford</PERSON> and their daughter <PERSON>Lady Theodora Guest</PERSON> - with Mr. <PERSON>Weigall</PERSON>. THey looked at the gold things with great interest - at all the things in the boat, and begged for photographs of the boat and other things. The <ORGANIZATION>Duke</ORGANIZATION>, now a very old and broken man, is of course a great personage - and I was very interested in meeting him. He seemed more interested in the boat and its fittings, and was much amused with our chicken yard out on the sand. The Duchess, so celebrated in her way, was a wonderful old woman - painted and enamelled, with reddish wig, an old black hat, with painted lips - very keen to see everything. Lady Gosford very different, as nice as possible, and her husband and daughter were very pleasant. I heard the Duchess talking to Mr. <PERSON>Davis</PERSON> about how the Gorsts enjoyed their lunch yesterday in the <ORGANIZATION>Valley House</ORGANIZATION>, and I know from what she said that she intended <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> should invited them also to lunch there, and I don’t think he will be able to escape it. 19th Sunday after Epiphany.	Jan, 19.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> was again in the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> today, with Mr. <PERSON>Winlock</PERSON>. <PERSON>M. Maspero</PERSON> and <PERSON>M. Lortet</PERSON> called and I showed them the gold things. Jan. 20, Monday.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> again in the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> with <PERSON>M. Lacau</PERSON> to lunch - quite cold. Jan. 21. Tuesday.      The 2 Miss <PERSON>McKewus</PERSON> called today. Ayrton to tea. Ayrton to tea. A note from “<PERSON>Louisa</PERSON>” Duchess of <ORGANIZATION>Devonshire</ORGANIZATION> tells <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> that they are going to the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> on Thursday, and will be happy to accept Mr. <PERSON>Davin</PERSON>’s invitation to lunch! Jan. 22. Wednesday.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> again to the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> to meet <PERSON>M. Maspero</PERSON>, <PERSON>Erakine</PERSON> and <PERSON>Weigall</PERSON>, and entered the new tomb. This was uncovered a few days since, but was shallow, and contained only some remains of workmens houses, and a number of large vases - filled with broken potsherds and small objects - the most important being a head about 7 in. high, which crowned the head of a mummied bird.      Major <PERSON>Watson</PERSON>, and Mrs. <PERSON>Graham</PERSON>, an English woman came to tea and were shown the find, when <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> was in the valley this A.M. they opened a jar found in the gold tomb. It contained a broken vase, which was beautifully enamelled and bearing the cartouche of Sety II. This can be restored - also an alabaster vase, broken, with cartouche of Rameses II, of very good work. A lovely warm day. Mr. <PERSON>Erskine</PERSON> dined with us. Jan. 23rd. Thursday.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> over in the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> all day, having the Devonshire party to lunch. <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> and I considerately stayed at home. Quite warm. Jan. 24. Friday.      A quiet day for all at home. This afternoon Mr. <PERSON>Erskine</PERSON> came to say goodbye. M. and <PERSON>Madame Maspero</PERSON> with their sons came to see the find. Jan. 25. Saturday.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> went to <LOCATION>Karnac</LOCATION> this P.M. Jan. 26. 	Third Sunday after Epiphany.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> went to the Valley - in a very cold wind storm - the dust quite frightful. Mr. <PERSON>Carter</PERSON> lunched with me and <PERSON>Harold Jones</PERSON>, who arrived this morning. Mr. <PERSON>Lythgoe</PERSON> in <LOCATION>Luxor</LOCATION>. Jan. 27. Monday.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> busy this morning with publication matter to send to <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Harold</PERSON> began his drawing of plates. Mr. <PERSON>Dalison</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lythgoe</PERSON> dined here. A very cold wind today. Jan. 28. Tuesday.      A quiet day - Theo paying some visits. Jan. 29. Wednesday.      Lovely and warm. Several people on boat today. <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> to “Tombs of the Queens” this afternoon. Jan. 30. Thursday.      A lot of people on the boat today - among them Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Smith</PERSON> of <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> - he is something at the Met. Museum, wand with them Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Patterson</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION>. <PERSON>M. Lortet</PERSON> also called - a pleasant and charming personage. Mr. <PERSON>Dallison</PERSON> dined here. Jan. 31. Friday.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> as usual in the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> with <PERSON>Lythgoe</PERSON> and <PERSON>Harold</PERSON>. Mr. <PERSON>Eric Villiers</PERSON> called this afternoon. Feb. 1. Saturday.      A day at home. Sir <PERSON>Ernest Cassal</PERSON> and his daughter Mrs. <PERSON>Ashley</PERSON> and the Princess <PERSON>Teano</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Rome</LOCATION> came to tea also Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Schiff</PERSON> of <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION>, Mr. <PERSON>Villiers</PERSON>, <PERSON>Weigall</PERSON> and others. Feb. 2. 4th after Epiphany.      In all day. <PERSON>Theo</PERSON>, <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> and <PERSON>Harold</PERSON> visited the interesting tombs in Sheik <PERSON>Abdul Gurnah</PERSON>. M. and Mme. <PERSON>Maspero</PERSON> and <PERSON>M. Loret</PERSON> dined with us. Very warm this afternoon. Feb. 3rd. Monday.      In <LOCATION>Luxor</LOCATION> this morning. Beautiful warm day. Feb. 4th. Tuesday.      A quiet day. Mr. <PERSON>Sayce</PERSON> arrived on the <ORGANIZATION>Istar</ORGANIZATION> and is lying near - came to see us. <PERSON>M. Loret</PERSON> and <PERSON>M. Le Grand</PERSON> came to tea and to see the find. <PERSON>Ayrton</PERSON> lunched and dined with us. Feb. 5th. Wednesday.      Mr. <PERSON>Sayce</PERSON> and <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> went to the Valley and lunched at the little house. Mr. <PERSON>Sayce</PERSON> also dined with us. Feb. 6th. Thursday.      Mr. <PERSON>Erskine</PERSON>, <PERSON>Nicol</PERSON> and Mr. <PERSON>Whymper</PERSON> called. We went back with them to their boat to see Mr. <PERSON>Nicol</PERSON>’s pictures. <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> bought a beauty for £50. We started for <LOCATION>Aswan</LOCATION> at 1 o’clock and having a light wind got within 3 miles of <LOCATION>Erment</LOCATION>, where we had to stop for the night. Feb. 7th. Friday.      A cold west wind blowing all day - a real gale - we towed and pulled to anchor, making 1-1/2 miles! Feb. 8th. Saturday.      30 miles. 	Towed from 7 A.M. to 10 o’clock. Then the gale began again and was so strong we furled the big sail and went on with the felucca sail, but struck a sand bank with such force that I was thrown off my feet - lamp overturned - ornaments etc. thrown. We then went on more slowly passing the Esneh bridge and sailing until 6 o’clock. Fifth Sunday after Epiphany. Feb. 9th.      31 miles. 	Started at 7 A.M. with light wind, growing stronger at 10 proving a gale. We again put up our felucca sail and went on with it until driven to the bank at 4 o’clock - afterwards going on until 5:30 - cold - and atmosphere filled with dust. Feb. 10. Monday.      A fine good sailing day - have made 41 miles, and are 3 miles above <LOCATION>Kom Ombo</LOCATION>. Feb. 11. Tuesday.      23 miles. 	A difficult day, light, variable winds - which have brought us our old “Sycamore tree”. Feb. 12. Wednesday.      We pulled to anchor around to our old place opposite the Cataract Hotel. Rowed around to the Savoy, and had tea in the lovely garden. Feb. 13. Thursday.      A great gale of wind - filling the air with dust from the excavations on the island. I never knew a more disagreeable day. <PERSON>Harold</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> went to <ORGANIZATION>Philae</ORGANIZATION>, in spite of it. The big boom was taken down this morning, and we are ready to go down tomorrow. Feb. 14. Friday.      The wind has prevented our starting. <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> and I and <PERSON>Harold</PERSON> tried to see the excavations today, but the dust and wind drove us home. Feb. 15. Saturday.      We started down at 9:40 this morning - but the north wind drove us to anchor very near the <LOCATION>Savoy</LOCATION>, where we have remained all day - wind, still strong. Feb. 16. Septuagesima Sunday.      Started at 7 A.M. but were driven immediately to the bank, where we have lain all day. Warm. Feb. 17. Monday.      5 miles. 	Difficult to make even this distance. Feb. 18. Tuesday.      13 miles. 	Hard wind all day - cold. Feb. 19. Wednesday.      16 miles. 	Ditto yesterday. Feb. 20. Thursday.      34 miles. 	<LOCATION>Edfu</LOCATION>, a good days sail. <PERSON>Theo</PERSON>, <PERSON>Harold</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> visited the temple. Feb. 21. Friday.      32 miles. 	Very hot all day - sailing all the time. Feb. 22. Saturday.      Hard gale. No miles. Feb. 23. 	Sexagesima Sunday.      7 miles. 	Strong wind. Feb. 24. Monday.      26 miles. 	We reached <LOCATION>Luxor</LOCATION> at 7 P.M. making 8 days from <LOCATION>Aswan</LOCATION>. Feb. 25. Tuesday.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Harold</PERSON> went over to the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> this morning to see the condition of the tomb <PERSON>Ayrton</PERSON> thinks he has found. They report that a stone stairway leading sharply down to a doorway has been found. Feb. 26. Wednesday.      All of us went to the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> this morning. The first door of the tomb is cleared - the corridor filled with rubbish. <PERSON>Ayrton</PERSON> crawled through with great difficulty and said he could see another door quite filled up. <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> thinks it an 18th dynasty tomb. Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Spreston</PERSON> called this evening, bringing a letter of introduction from <LOCATION>Everard Fielding</LOCATION>. She was a Miss de Trafford. The <PERSON>McKeever</PERSON> girls and Mr. <PERSON>Forbes</PERSON> called before dinner, and Mr. <PERSON>Dalison</PERSON> this evening. Feb. 27. Thursday.      A quiet day - <PERSON>Harold</PERSON> has stayed in the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> yesterday and today. Feb. 28. Friday.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> over in the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> all day - he reports that the door of the tomb is nearly free, and the at the men are clearing a passage through the debris in the corridor. Very hot today. Feb. 29. Saturday.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Harold</PERSON> went of course to the Valley this morning. They found <PERSON>Ayrton</PERSON>, <PERSON>Dalison</PERSON> and <PERSON>Weigall</PERSON> waiting for them, and in spite of their protestations <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> insisted upon entering the tomb, and going first. They found it very difficult and hot. It soon declared itself as the tomb of Heromheb - a very long tomb - with corridors, well, fully fresh, of Gods, a magnificent Sarcophagus, and figures in wood and marble - a few bones - no mummy - 200 ft. long. March 1st. Quinquagesima Sunday.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> met the Connaught party at <LOCATION>Karnac</LOCATION> this afternoon - and invited them to tea tomorrow! March 2. Monday.      The Connaughts arrived from the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> about 4:30 - quite an imposing array - several mounted guards arrived before them - and the Duchess and Princess <PERSON>Patricia</PERSON> arrived first. I took them to my room, and left them to tidy themselves. I found in the salon Miss <PERSON>Pelly</PERSON>, whom I had met before, Lady in waiting, then came the <PERSON>Duke</PERSON> with members of his staff - Major <PERSON>M. Murray</PERSON> - Lieut. the Hon. <PERSON>M. B. Ponsonby</PERSON> - Sir <PERSON>John Maxwell</PERSON>, whom we knew, <PERSON>Major Watson</PERSON>, an old friend, and Mr. <PERSON>Weigall</PERSON>. They looked first at the gold find, and then went on deck for tea. I thought I had never seen so many nice looking men together - and the Connaughts are delightful, simple people to entertain. After they went away the <ORGANIZATION>McKewers</ORGANIZATION> and Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Forbes</PERSON> came. They said they had been watching from the Hotel opposite the royal entourage on the sand, waiting until it was over. March 3rd. Tuesday.     Mr. <PERSON>Dalison</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ayrton</PERSON> came to lunch. <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carrie</PERSON> again [cut off--illegible] when they met the <ORGANIZATION>Duke</ORGANIZATION>’s party. Lovely day. March 4th. Ash Wednesday.      All the family at <LOCATION>Karnac</LOCATION> this afternoon. March 5th. Thursday.      <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Harold</PERSON> at the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> today. I went over to <LOCATION>Luxor</LOCATION> to say goodbye to Miss <PERSON>Buchanan</PERSON>. March 6th. Friday.      A really hot day. Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Roa</PERSON> and <PERSON>Mohamed Mohassib</PERSON> to tea. March 7th. Saturday.      <PERSON>Harold</PERSON> and <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> have been in the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION> all day with the photographer, who came up from <LOCATION>Cairo</LOCATION>, to do the tomb. March 8th. First Sunday in Lent.     I am the only member of the household who did not go to the Valley today. All went into the tomb. Mr. <PERSON>Dalison</PERSON> and Mr. <PERSON>Ayrton</PERSON> dined with us, and spent the night - sleeping on the dock divans - very jolly evening. March 9. Monday.      82-1/2 miles. <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> had engaged a sugar tug to take us down the river. We started at 9:10 and reached <PERSON>Nag Hamadi</PERSON> at 7:30 P.M. No wind, very warm, anchored just above the bridge. March 10. Tuesday.      51 miles.	Passed the bridge at 8 A.M. and then anchored until 25 M. before 11 - allowed the tug to cool. Very hot all day. The sunset was wonderfully beautiful. March 11. Wed. Asyt.      68 miles. 	A gale all day - tug on the sand for an hour this morning - afterwards sticking again for 3 hours - arrived in spite of all at <LOCATION>Asyût</LOCATION> at 6:30. March 12. Thursday. <PERSON>Beni Hassan</PERSON>.      Passed the lock at 8 o’clock, early. The sand is bad in this part of the river - we have to go carefully. March 13. Friday.      60 miles. 	Started at 6. Stopped at <LOCATION>Minia</LOCATION>, for mail one hour and 3 hours at <PERSON>Sheik Fadl</PERSON> to cool. Rather cool out of the sun. March 14. Saturday. near <LOCATION>Bedrescheyn</LOCATION>.      90 miles. 	Started again at 6, stopping about 10 to assist a dahabya sticking in the mud, to get off. It proved to be a party from <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> - Mr. <PERSON>Smith</PERSON> the father of <PERSON>Harold Smith</PERSON>. March 15th. 2nd Sunday in Lent.      Arrived at the <LOCATION>Ghezireh</LOCATION> bridge at 11 A.M. having made our 450 miles from <LOCATION>Luxor</LOCATION> in 7 days. Lord Fielding dined with us. March 16th. <LOCATION>Cairo</LOCATION>.      Came to our old place at the <LOCATION>Ghezireh Palace</LOCATION> this A.M. Spent the morning at the Museum and and had tea with the <PERSON>Iddings</PERSON> in the afternoon. A visit from Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Fraser</PERSON> this evening. March 17th. Tuesday.      Capt. <PERSON>Lyons</PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON>Lyons</PERSON> and Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Iddings</PERSON> came this A.M. to see the find. We took all the things to the Museum this morning. A good riddance. March 18th. Wednesday.      Morning at Museum - afternoon driving and visiting. March 19th. Thursday.      We were again at the Museum this morning. Dinner at the <PERSON>Iddings</PERSON> where we met some pleasant people:  Mr. and Miss <PERSON>Farnell</PERSON> - Major Skifeuton - Smythe - Sir <PERSON>John Beard</PERSON> and daughter, <PERSON>Lady Bathhurst</PERSON> and others. March 20th. Friday.      Driving and shopping this morning - Major <PERSON>Watson</PERSON> called this afternoon. March 21st. Saturday.      Lunched at the <ORGANIZATION>British Embassy</ORGANIZATION> - a charming visit - Sir <PERSON>Eldon</PERSON> was particularly interesting and agreeable. <PERSON>Lady Gorst</PERSON>, very pretty, chic and pleasant. Mr. <PERSON>Hall Caine</PERSON> and his wife were there among others. March 22nd. 3rd Sunday in Lent.      We have been staying at the Ghezireh Palace Hotel since Thursday. Rain all day. Mr. <PERSON>Sayce</PERSON> dined with us. March 23rd. Monday.      Very busy. Our last day. Went in the afternoon to <PERSON>Madame Artin Pashat</PERSON> to tea - interesting. Mr. <PERSON>Dalison</PERSON> and <PERSON>Joe Smith</PERSON> dined with us. Mr. <PERSON>Dalison</PERSON> has been with us for 2 days, and is crossing with us to <LOCATION>Naples</LOCATION> where we are to spend 3 days. Mr. <PERSON>Carter</PERSON> came to tea with us this afternoon. 1