PAGE 105Nov. 21. 1912.After a hurried and tiring week spent in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> at that perfect hotel, the <LOCATION>St. Dennis</LOCATION>, we sailed on Saturday the 16, for <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> via <LOCATION>Naples</LOCATION> on that ship well known to us, the “<LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION>”, on which we have crossed for two years.  Only, this time I was not upstairs in the Captain’s room as usual.  We have <PERSON>Mary Newberry</PERSON> and her daughter, <PERSON>Doris</PERSON>, with us, making their first acquaintance with these southern waters.  But we are unfortunate - for our second day out was bad - the wind and sea increasing in violence, and for 24 hours it was terrific - it is now better, but the rain and mist continue, and we have only caught a glimpse of the Azores - which we are now passing.Sunday. Nov. 24th.We dropped our anchor about 2 o’clock at <LOCATION>Gibraltar</LOCATION>.  Most of the passengers went ashore, <PERSON>Jones</PERSON> guiding <PERSON>Mary</PERSON> and <PERSON>Doris</PERSON>.  They were duly impressed and charmed.  We were soon off - it growing wilder as we got well into the <LOCATION>Mediterranean</LOCATION>.Tuesday. Nov. 26th.Reached <LOCATION>Algiers</LOCATION> after dark - many went ashore - mild and lovely.PAGE 106Wednesday. Oct. 27th. (<PERSON>Sarah</PERSON>’s note - it should be Nov. 27th. Either <ORGANIZATION>EBA</ORGANIZATION> or typist’s mistake)Arrived at noon today - found <PERSON>Harry</PERSON> waiting for us.  The pleasant old appartment at the <LOCATION>Grand Hotel</LOCATION> - a tea at <PERSON>Bertolini</PERSON>’s - and off in the <PERSON>Prinz Heinrick</PERSON> for <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> on Friday - a very smooth passage over a summer sea, and <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> at last, and once again.  How glad we were for <PERSON>Theodore</PERSON>’s sake - and he was so happy to find himself once more here!<PERSON>Dahabya Beduin</PERSON>. Dec. 11th.We are now established on our boat - waiting for our tug - which should arrive in the morning.  How pleasant it is! after a whole month from home spent in hotels and steamers! It has been a busy week in <LOCATION>Cairo</LOCATION> - <PERSON>Mary</PERSON> and <PERSON>Doris</PERSON> have been sightseeing and motoring about.  I have been once to the Museum making a visit to Sir <PERSON>Gaston Maspero</PERSON> with <PERSON>Theo</PERSON>.  We spoke of the magnificent cover to the so-called Tyii’s coffin which has never been shown to the public and is kept entirely apart in a private room.  A man capable of repairing it has been found, and has agreed to do the whole thing and to finish it within 5 months.  The gold work, as well as the exquisite inlay - it will be a grand addition to <PERSON>Theodore</PERSON>’s exhibit at the Museum.  We had quite a little tea party on Sunday afternoon, on the boat.  Mr. <PERSON>Sayce</PERSON>, <PERSON>Artin Pasha</PERSON>, <PERSON>Claudius Bey</PERSON> and the young <PERSON>Leavitts</PERSON>.  Mr. <PERSON>Sayce</PERSON> is on his way to <LOCATION>India</LOCATION>.  We gave a morning to the zoo - and generally a lot of sight seeing.PAGE 107Saturday. Dec. 21We arrived about noon today - after a pleasant and successful voyage of 10 days - one day of showers - clearing with most beautiful rainbow.  We have several fine new sailors - young men - making a fine crew - of course our tug was a good strong one, making a fast voyage.  We find several friends here - Mr. <PERSON>Whymper</PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION>Contessa di Villamarina</ORGANIZATION>, Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Pier</PERSON>, and their 2 heavenly little girls - Miss <PERSON>Buchanan</PERSON> fortunately for 2 days.  She is now at the head of the <ORGANIZATION>American College</ORGANIZATION> for girls in <LOCATION>Cairo</LOCATION>.  On the 24th the Serapis arrived with Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Tuck</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION>, Major <PERSON>Curley</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Newport</LOCATION>, Miss <PERSON>Nelson</PERSON> and Miss <PERSON>Morgan</PERSON>, niece of Mr. <PERSON>Tuck</PERSON>.  They and Mr. <PERSON>Nicol</PERSON> were here to tea on Christmas day, and <PERSON>Harry Burton</PERSON> and Mr. <PERSON>Crane</PERSON> to lunch.Friday. Dec. 27th.We all - four of us, and <PERSON>Jones</PERSON> went over to the <LOCATION>Valley</LOCATION>, and stayed 3 days - and had a jolly visit.  Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Arthur James of Newport</PERSON>, who sailed from there on their yacht, the “Aloha” just before we left, arrived on the “Hyksos” came to tea.  They were so pleased with our boat.  They are going to join their yacht again at <LOCATION>Mombasa</LOCATION> for the return home.Wednesday. Jan. 1st.Mr. <PERSON>Whymper</PERSON> came to breakfast and brought us all the news of <LOCATION>Luxor</LOCATION>.PAGE 108Thursday. Jan. 2nd.<PERSON>Contessa di Villamarina</PERSON> and Mr. <PERSON>Trevaine</PERSON> came to tea - Baron and <PERSON>Baroness</PERSON> v. Bissing are lying in their boat, just behind us - and <PERSON>Mary</PERSON> and I went to tea with them last evening.Saturday. Jan. 3rd.<PERSON>Mary</PERSON>, <PERSON>Doris</PERSON> and I crossed over and paid a visit to Mr. <PERSON>Nicol</PERSON>.  He has the very best picture I ever saw of his - the wonderful mountain range opposite <LOCATION>Luxor</LOCATION> - the finest view in all <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> I think.  He says he painted it for me - but Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Pier</PERSON> who were her to lunch, say that they are to have it.Monday. Jan. 6th.The v. Bissings were here to tea - and Mr. <PERSON>Nicol</PERSON> dined with us.Tuesday. Jan. 7th.We have all been over to see <PERSON>Harry</PERSON>’s diggings at <PERSON>Medinet Habu</PERSON>.Sunday. Jan. 12th.We have had <PERSON>Baron</PERSON> and <PERSON>Baroness</PERSON> v. Bissing to lunch, Miss Ferroir to tea and Miss <PERSON>Downie</PERSON> and the Piers to lunch this week.  We have paid a visit to the Fahnstocks, who are lying near.  The weather is at last clear and warm.PAGE 109Sunday. Jan. 19.We have had among other visitors this week, the <ORGANIZATION>Hardys</ORGANIZATION> to tea, Sir <PERSON>Gaston</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lady Maspero</PERSON>, and Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Carlstone Sprague</PERSON> sent by Mrs. <PERSON>Metcalf</PERSON>, and Mr. <PERSON>Allen Marquand</PERSON>, windy and cold.Sunday. Jan. 26.It has been warm and charming most of the week.  We have had the Contessa and Mr. <PERSON>Tremaine</PERSON>, Mr. <PERSON>Alan Gardner</PERSON> (<PERSON>Sarah</PERSON>:sic), Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Longyear</PERSON> and son on their homeward bound voyage from <LOCATION>India</LOCATION>, Mr. <PERSON>Fahnstock</PERSON> to tea, Mr. <PERSON>Tremaine</PERSON> to lunch, and Mr. <PERSON>Whymper</PERSON> to breakfast this week, to say nothing of a charming little white baby donkey, which one of the sailors brought on the lower deck, to amuse the Pier children.  We have had some warm days.Sunday. Feb. 2nd.Various visits from friends - we have lunched with the Fahnstocks and Masperos - visits to the diggings etc - cold and windy.Sunday. Feb 9th.It has been very warm - various visitors - among them the <LOCATION>Longyears</LOCATION> back from the <LOCATION>South</LOCATION> as far as <LOCATION>Khartoum</LOCATION>.  Mr. <PERSON>Whymper</PERSON> to breakfast this morning.Sunday. Feb. 16th.We dressed the ship on Wednesday - <ORGANIZATION>Lincoln</ORGANIZATION>’s birthday - thePAGE 110usual routine - this week - we have had light rain on one day and cold stormy weather since.  <PERSON>Contessa</PERSON> here for luncheon.Sunday. Feb. 23rd.Very warm.  Mr. <PERSON>Whymper</PERSON> to breakfast - the Piers to lunch.  Mrs. <PERSON>Aylener</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Morehouse</ORGANIZATION> to tea.  We have had Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Hardy</PERSON> to tea - Senator <PERSON>Aldrich</PERSON> also.  <PERSON>Mary N.</PERSON> and I have been over to the Winter Palace for tea - we looked very smart on <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION>’s birthday with all our flags.Sunday. March 2nd.On Monday <PERSON>Mary</PERSON> and I went to tea with the Contessa in the gardens of the <LOCATION>Luxor Hotel</LOCATION> - met <PERSON>Lady Baring</PERSON>, <PERSON>Miss Murray</PERSON>, and <PERSON>Contessa Pappenheim</PERSON> and daughter. Charming people all - yesterday we left for Aswân.Sunday. March 9th.This is our record for the week - very high wind from the time we left <LOCATION>Luxor</LOCATION>.  Stopped at <LOCATION>Edfou - Kom Ombo</LOCATION> - where we were held some time by furious wind - after leaving we passed the most wonderful mass of flamingoes - absolutely dense masses of them - attending a mile or two - very remarkable - reached <LOCATION>Aswan</LOCATION> the 4th.  The wind horridly bad. <PERSON>Mary</PERSON> and <PERSON>Doris</PERSON> went to Barrage - the next day we moved down opposite <PERSON>Grenfell</PERSON>’s tomb, and the girls visited them.  The 7th we left <LOCATION>Aswan</LOCATION>, the terrific wind still holding - so that we were tied up some timePAGE 111below <ORGANIZATION>Kom Ombo</ORGANIZATION> - the next day we struck upon 3 sand banks, or rather our tug did - and reached here this morning.Sunday. Mar. 16th.We spent the days Monday and Tuesday in <LOCATION>Luxor</LOCATION> - <PERSON>Doris</PERSON> and I went over to the town - and Mrs. <PERSON>Crispell</PERSON> and her niece came from the Mayflower to tea - I was so pleased with her.  Mr. <PERSON>Crane</PERSON> and <PERSON>Harry</PERSON> came to tea, and we left <LOCATION>Luxor</LOCATION> the 12th at noon - having had a nice visit from <LOCATION>Old Hagg Mahassib - Nag Hamadi</LOCATION> the 13 - <LOCATION>Balliana</LOCATION> the 14 - where we stopped for <PERSON>Mary</PERSON>, <PERSON>Doris</PERSON>, <PERSON>Amelie</PERSON>, <PERSON>Jones</PERSON> and <PERSON>Hassein</PERSON> to visit <LOCATION>Abydos</LOCATION> - very cold and terrific wind - very severe in the night and rough today.  We passed the <LOCATION>Arabia</LOCATION> stuck at 8:30 A.M. Cold, constant wind.Wednesday. April 2nd.We left the boat very reluctantly several days ago, that charming little home, and came to the Ghizereh Palace Hotel - and into our old rooms.  Hotel almost empty.  The new bridge is finished, and trains are running over it.  A very fine and long one - and a great convenience - but it spoils the garden somewhat. <LOCATION>Cairo</LOCATION> is fast changing and improving but losing its unique interesting eastern features.  Mrs. <PERSON>Graham</PERSON> called with Major <PERSON>Watson</PERSON> and asked us to tea on Friday and very pleasant it was, as always.  Mr. <PERSON>Tremaine</PERSON> and Mr. <PERSON>Carter</PERSON> called.PAGE 112Sunday. April 6th.Home all day - Baron v. <PERSON>Bissing</PERSON> called and stopped for tea.  <PERSON>Contessa Villamarina</PERSON> and Mlle. Johannis too.Monday. April 7th.<PERSON>Elena Rathbone</PERSON> and her friend Miss <PERSON>Cholanley</PERSON> just back from <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> came to tea, as well as Mr. <PERSON>Anthony</PERSON> and Mr. <PERSON>Lythgoe</PERSON>.Saturday. April 12th.Arrived in <LOCATION>Naples</LOCATION> at 7:30 this morning, landed in the hideous confusion characteristic of the N.G.L. steamers - rain and cold winds.Wednesday. April 16th.Came to <LOCATION>Florence</LOCATION> - a long days journey - very cold.  <PERSON>Vesuvius</PERSON> and the mountains all this way up, covered with snow. We came to the <LOCATION>Grande Bretagne</LOCATION> and to our old appartment  - we have had a little fire every day.  <PERSON>Theo</PERSON> has been almost every day motoring, with <PERSON>David Costantini</PERSON> and <PERSON>Harry Burton</PERSON>, and some one or two of the girls.  The season is very backward - the roses just beginning to show.  Have made some pleasant visits - Theo has made excursions to <PERSON>Faenza</PERSON>, <PERSON>Settignano</PERSON> - <LOCATION>Volterra</LOCATION> and enjoyed it keenly.  He has loved going to the Villino and hearing <PERSON>Nettie</PERSON> sing - and to drive to the Cascine for a walk along the little river, with its lovely entourage of blue mountains and green meadows and magnificent trees.  Above all I have enjoyed the companion-PAGE 113ship of the two dear nieces, <PERSON>Nettie</PERSON> and <PERSON>Mary</PERSON>.  We go tomorrow at 5 P.M. via the <LOCATION>Mt. Cenie</LOCATION> pass to <LOCATION>London</LOCATION>.1912-19136