PAGE	O
72	O
October	O
25	O
,	O
1910	O
SS	O
.	O

Kronprinz	PERSON
Wilhelm	PERSON
.	O

Sailed	O
this	O
a.m.	O
from	O
New	LOCATION
York	LOCATION
at	O
ten	O
o'clock	O
for	O
Cherbourg	LOCATION
and	O
Paris	LOCATION
.	O

It	O
seems	O
an	O
absurd	O
route	O
to	O
take	O
to	O
Cairo	LOCATION
--	O
but	O
the	O
service	O
of	O
the	O
Mediterranean	LOCATION
steamers	O
is	O
so	O
disorganized	O
because	O
of	O
the	O
cholera	O
in	O
so	O
many	O
infected	O
port	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
necessity	O
of	O
quarantine	O
,	O
that	O
we	O
cancelled	O
our	O
engagement	O
for	O
Naples	LOCATION
.	O

We	O
will	O
take	O
the	O
Schleswig	O
at	O
Marseilles	LOCATION
,	O
instead	O
of	O
Naples	LOCATION
.	O

Sunday	O
,	O
Oct.	O
30	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
had	O
an	O
uneventful	O
stupid	O
voyage	O
,	O
and	O
are	O
due	O
at	O
Cherbourg	LOCATION
tomorrow	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
had	O
rain	O
,	O
cold	O
winds	O
,	O
and	O
rough	O
seas	O
.	O

Very	O
pleasant	O
rooms	O
.	O

Paris	LOCATION
--	O
Oct.	O
31	O
.	O

Westminster	ORGANIZATION
Hotel	ORGANIZATION
.	O

We	O
made	O
Plymouth	ORGANIZATION
at	O
7	O
o'clock	O
this	O
morning	O
--	O
I	O
got	O
up	O
and	O
looked	O
out	O
at	O
the	O
interesting	O
coast	O
--	O
reached	O
Cherbourg	LOCATION
at	O
1	O
p.m.	O
and	O
were	O
off	O
at	O
3	O
.	O

We	O
felt	O
some	O
little	O
trepidation	O
at	O
committing	O
ourselves	O
to	O
a	O
French	O
railway	O
--	O
there	O
has	O
been	O
such	O
a	O
history	O
of	O
accidents	O
in	O
France	LOCATION
!	O

But	O
we	O
knew	O
that	O
this	O
line	O
had	O
been	O
thoroughly	O
repaired	O
--	O
as	O
was	O
shown	O
by	O
the	O
piles	O
of	O
the	O
old	O
sleepers	O
all	O
along	O
the	O
road	O
--	O
in	O
the	O
most	O
astounding	O
state	O
of	O
decay	O
--	O
utter	O
rottenness	O
--	O
they	O
gave	O
damning	O
evidence	O
of	O
neglect	O
.	O

I	O
had	O
never	O
seen	O
the	O
Brittany	PERSON
country	O
before	O
.	O

How	O
charming	O
those	O
wide	O
reaching	O
fields	O
were	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
late	O
afternoon	O
light	O
--	O
so	O
softly	O
green	O
--	O
and	O
the	O
characteristic	O
,	O
mostly	O
PAGE	O
73	O
pollarded	O
trees	O
in	O
their	O
tints	O
of	O
bronze	O
and	O
olive	O
green	O
and	O
russet	O
pink	O
,	O
made	O
a	O
picture	O
,	O
or	O
rather	O
a	O
succession	O
of	O
them	O
that	O
looked	O
as	O
if	O
they	O
might	O
have	O
been	O
painted	O
by	O
Troyen	PERSON
or	O
Coret	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
a	O
blissful	O
afternoon	O
--	O
and	O
we	O
so	O
enjoyed	O
it	O
.	O

Arrived	O
in	O
Paris	LOCATION
at	O
10	O
--	O
and	O
found	O
Mr.	O
Rathbone	PERSON
waiting	O
for	O
us	O
.	O

They	O
are	O
at	O
the	O
Bedford	LOCATION
.	O

Tuesday	O
.	O

Nov.	O
1st	O
.	O

It	O
has	O
poured	O
with	O
rain	O
all	O
day	O
--	O
have	O
not	O
been	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
house	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
All	O
Saints	O
Day	O
,	O
and	O
every	O
magasin	O
and	O
museum	O
is	O
closed	O
.	O

Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Rathbone	PERSON
and	O
Elèna	PERSON
came	O
to	O
lunch	O
,	O
and	O
are	O
to	O
turn	O
up	O
at	O
the	O
Gare	LOCATION
de	LOCATION
Lyon	LOCATION
at	O
10	O
.	O

Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
John	PERSON
E.	PERSON
Parsons	PERSON
are	O
in	O
this	O
hotel	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
went	O
to	O
their	O
rooms	O
to	O
have	O
tea	O
with	O
them	O
.	O

We	O
quite	O
enjoyed	O
our	O
little	O
dinner	O
up	O
in	O
our	O
sitting	O
room	O
.	O

Hotel	O
are	O
crowded	O
here	O
--	O
the	O
manager	O
told	O
us	O
there	O
were	O
more	O
than	O
200	O
people	O
in	O
Paris	LOCATION
waiting	O
for	O
a	O
chance	O
to	O
cross	O
the	O
Mediterranean	LOCATION
.	O

N.	PERSON
G.	PERSON
Lloyd	PERSON
SS	PERSON
.	O

Schleswig	O
.	O

Wednesday	O
.	O

Nov.	O
2nd	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
a	O
rough	O
night	O
on	O
our	O
funny	O
Wagon-Lit	O
--	O
and	O
jolted	O
through	O
it	O
with	O
what	O
patience	O
we	O
could	O
--	O
felling	O
as	O
if	O
we	O
were	O
travelling	O
in	O
a	O
card-board	O
box	O
--	O
arrived	O
by	O
9	O
o'clock	O
--	O
found	O
our	O
old	O
rooms	O
ready	O
for	O
us	O
--	O
did	O
not	O
get	O
off	O
until	O
nearly	O
5	O
o'clock	O
--	O
there	O
being	O
so	O
many	O
passengers	O
and	O
such	O
piles	O
of	O
luggage	O
.	O

PAGE	O
74	O
Friday	O
.	O

Nov.	O
4th	O
.	O

Passed	O
the	O
straits	O
at	O
1.30	O
--	O
a	O
lovely	O
day	O
--	O
warm	O
and	O
calm	O
.	O

The	O
dreadful	O
ravages	O
on	O
either	O
hand	O
,	O
were	O
a	O
piteous	O
contrast	O
to	O
the	O
beauty	O
of	O
the	O
day	O
.	O

Sunday	O
.	O

Nov.	O
6th	O
.	O

Due	O
at	O
Alexamdria	LOCATION
tomorrow	O
at	O
6	O
am	O
--	O
a	O
warm	O
,	O
lovely	O
passage	O
.	O

I	O
have	O
been	O
writing	O
letter	O
busily	O
.	O

Monday	O
.	O

Nov.	O
7th	O
.	O

Shepheards	O
Hotel	O
.	O

Arrived	O
at	O
12:30	O
and	O
were	O
soon	O
eating	O
lunch	O
on	O
the	O
13th	O
day	O
out	O
from	O
New	LOCATION
York	LOCATION
!	O

Surprising	O
when	O
one	O
reflects	O
that	O
our	O
steamers	O
to	O
Naples	LOCATION
always	O
take	O
13	O
days	O
for	O
the	O
voyage	O
!	O

Are	O
in	O
our	O
pleasant	O
-LSB-	O
1	O
-RSB-	O
old	O
rooms	O
,	O
overlooking	O
the	O
garden	O
--	O
the	O
weather	O
is	O
perfect	O
.	O

Monday	O
.	O

Nov.	O
14th	O
.	O

Rather	O
a	O
busy	O
week	O
,	O
settling	O
ourselves	O
and	O
things	O
on	O
the	O
boat	O
,	O
seeing	O
sights	O
--	O
visiting	O
and	O
receiving	O
friends	O
--	O
consulting	O
Mr.	O
Draper	PERSON
about	O
the	O
little	O
mooring	O
garden	O
.	O

Lunched	O
one	O
day	O
with	O
the	O
Gorsts	O
,	O
and	O
another	O
day	O
went	O
to	O
a	O
reception	O
there	O
.	O

Capt.	O
Trefusis	PERSON
,	O
and	O
Mr.	O
Carter	PERSON
Bonham	PERSON
,	O
Elèna	PERSON
's	O
friend	O
,	O
dined	O
with	O
us	O
one	O
night	O
,	O
and	O
Mr.	O
Lovatt	PERSON
and	O
son	O
--	O
another	O
night	O
--	O
and	O
Mr.	O
Lovatt	PERSON
and	O
son	O
and	O
Mr.	O
Walter	PERSON
Gay	PERSON
came	O
to	O
tea	O
on	O
our	O
first	O
afternoon	O
on	O
the	O
boat	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
tea	O
with	O
the	O
Gays	O
one	O
afternoon	O
--	O
Mrs.	O
Gay	O
very	O
attractive	O
.	O

PAGE	O
75	O
Monday	O
.	O

Nov.	O
21st	O
.	O

We	O
came	O
on	O
board	O
to	O
stay	O
on	O
the	O
16th	O
and	O
sailed	O
the	O
next	O
day	O
at	O
10	O
a.m.	O
passed	O
the	O
Ghizeh	LOCATION
bridge	O
about	O
10.20	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
a	O
good	O
strong	O
tug	O
.	O

Tied	O
up	O
at	O
5	O
P.M.	O
.	O

We	O
find	O
a	O
tremendously	O
big	O
,	O
wide	O
river	O
,	O
with	O
very	O
trong	O
current	O
and	O
made	O
35	O
miles	O
the	O
first	O
day	O
,	O
42	O
the	O
second	O
,	O
51	O
the	O
third	O
,	O
39	O
the	O
fourth	O
,	O
47	O
the	O
5th	O
,	O
37	O
the	O
6th	O
,	O
51	O
the	O
seventh	O
,	O
43	O
the	O
eighth	O
,	O
38	O
the	O
ninth	O
,	O
50	O
-	O
1/2	O
the	O
tenth	O
--	O
arrived	O
at	O
Luxor	LOCATION
the	O
27th	O
.	O

We	O
tied	O
up	O
much	O
in	O
our	O
usual	O
place	O
--	O
to	O
a	O
mite	O
of	O
a	O
sand	O
bank	O
,	O
opposite	O
the	O
castle	O
.	O

Second	O
Sunday	O
in	O
Advent	O
.	O

Dec.	O
4th	O
.	O

A	O
pleasant	O
two	O
weeks	O
we	O
have	O
had	O
--	O
fine	O
,	O
good	O
weather	O
.	O

Elèna	PERSON
busy	O
and	O
enchanted	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
been	O
over	O
to	O
the	O
Valley	LOCATION
for	O
lunch	O
.	O

The	O
Buckley	PERSON
family	O
here	O
for	O
tea	O
one	O
afternoon	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Carter	PERSON
and	O
Mr.	O
Weigall	PERSON
for	O
lunch	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Nicol	PERSON
also	O
for	O
lunch	O
.	O

Theo	PERSON
several	O
times	O
to	O
the	O
Valley	LOCATION
.	O

Third	O
Sunday	O
in	O
Advent	O
.	O

Dec.	O
11th	O
.	O

A	O
rather	O
busy	O
week	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Weigall	PERSON
and	O
his	O
sister	O
Mrs.	O
Butler	PERSON
to	O
tea	O
one	O
day	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Nicol	PERSON
to	O
dine	O
--	O
Mrs.	O
Butler	PERSON
and	O
Mr.	O
Weigall	PERSON
to	O
dine	O
.	O

Theo	PERSON
has	O
established	O
Harry	PERSON
Burton	PERSON
in	O
his	O
new	O
concession	O
the	O
`	O
Priest	O
Kings	O
'	O
Valley	LOCATION
.	O

M.	PERSON
Maspero	PERSON
was	O
anxious	O
Theo	PERSON
should	O
clear	O
this	O
but	O
Theo	PERSON
does	O
not	O
look	O
for	O
much	O
of	O
a	O
result	O
.	O

Harold	PERSON
Jones	PERSON
is	O
so	O
poorly	O
,	O
so	O
weak	O
,	O
quite	O
incapable	O
of	O
work	O
,	O
even	O
painting	O
.	O

Buth	PERSON
his	O
brother	O
Cyril	PERSON
keeps	O
a	O
certain	O
supervision	O
of	O
the	O
men	O
.	O

This	O
afternoon	O
Elèna	PERSON
,	O
Theo	PERSON
and	O
I	O
rode	O
over	O
to	O
see	O
Mr.	O
Carter	PERSON
and	O
see	O
some	O
of	O
Mr.	O
Nicol	PERSON
's	O
paintings	O
--	O
PAGE	O
76	O
Very	O
lovely	O
they	O
were	O
.	O

Theo	PERSON
bought	O
one	O
.	O

Fourth	O
Sunday	O
in	O
Advent	O
.	O

Dec.	O
18th	O
.	O

Harold	PERSON
Jones	PERSON
and	O
Cyril	PERSON
came	O
over	O
and	O
spent	O
3	O
days	O
at	O
the	O
Winter	LOCATION
Palace	LOCATION
,	O
lunched	O
twice	O
with	O
me	O
.	O

I	O
gave	O
tea	O
at	O
the	O
Palace	O
on	O
day	O
,	O
and	O
asked	O
a	O
few	O
of	O
Harold	PERSON
's	O
friends	O
--	O
the	O
poor	O
fellow	O
looked	O
very	O
tired	O
when	O
it	O
was	O
over	O
.	O

Baron	PERSON
v.	O
Mumm	PERSON
called	O
one	O
afternoon	O
--	O
he	O
is	O
on	O
his	O
way	O
back	O
to	O
China	LOCATION
--	O
he	O
is	O
the	O
German	O
minister	O
of	O
China	LOCATION
.	O

Mr.	O
And	O
Mrs.	O
Gibson	PERSON
Fahnstock	PERSON
came	O
to	O
tea	O
on	O
Wednesday	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
for	O
tea	O
Miss	O
Kelly	PERSON
and	O
her	O
brother	O
,	O
Mr.	O
Whitaker	PERSON
and	O
Mr.	O
Whymper	PERSON
were	O
here	O
for	O
tea	O
.	O

The	O
Kellys	ORGANIZATION
played	O
and	O
sang	O
.	O

Christmas	O
Day	O
--	O
Dec.	O
25th	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
the	O
usual	O
gifts	O
for	O
the	O
sailors	O
this	O
morning	O
--	O
Harry	PERSON
Burton	PERSON
came	O
this	O
evening	O
to	O
stay	O
until	O
Wednesday	O
morning	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
being	O
market	O
day	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
the	O
one	O
holiday	O
in	O
the	O
week	O
for	O
workmen	O
.	O

Theo	PERSON
spent	O
3	O
days	O
in	O
the	O
Valley	LOCATION
this	O
week	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Crane	PERSON
,	O
who	O
is	O
busy	O
painting	O
the	O
Horemheb	O
tomb	O
,	O
lunched	O
with	O
us	O
today	O
.	O

Capt.	O
Walter	PERSON
Trefusis	PERSON
dined	O
with	O
us	O
today	O
.	O

Saturday	O
.	O

Dec.	O
31st	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
had	O
a	O
cold	O
week	O
.	O

Theo	PERSON
spent	O
his	O
usual	O
3	O
days	O
in	O
the	O
Valley	LOCATION
--	O
nothing	O
has	O
yet	O
been	O
found	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
seen	O
a	O
good	O
deal	O
of	O
Mr.	O
Whitaker	PERSON
and	O
his	O
party	O
.	O

They	O
are	O
on	O
the	O
old	O
Cleopatra	O
--	O
but	O
he	O
has	O
done	O
a	O
great	O
deal	O
to	O
it	O
and	O
put	O
about	O
a	O
great	O
many	O
pretty	O
things	O
,	O
and	O
PAGE	O
77	O
It	O
looks	O
very	O
attractive	O
.	O

Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Newberry	PERSON
are	O
with	O
him	O
,	O
and	O
they	O
are	O
to	O
excavate	O
somewhere	O
near	O
Akmim	LOCATION
.	O

Saturday	O
Jan.	O
7	O
.	O

1911	O
The	O
``	O
Miriam	O
''	O
with	O
the	O
Masperos	PERSON
arrived	O
on	O
the	O
3rd	O
.	O

Theo	PERSON
and	O
I	O
called	O
on	O
them	O
the	O
next	O
morning	O
.	O

Madame	PERSON
Maspero	PERSON
has	O
been	O
very	O
ill	O
on	O
the	O
way	O
up	O
with	O
a	O
bronchial	O
attack	O
.	O

They	O
are	O
to	O
stay	O
3	O
weeks	O
.	O

Mrs.	O
McCormick	PERSON
and	O
Miss	O
Scott	PERSON
dined	O
here	O
tonight	O
.	O

Saturday	O
.	O

Jan.	O
14	O
.	O

Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Buckley	PERSON
to	O
lunch	O
on	O
Sunday	O
,	O
a	O
warm	O
fine	O
day	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Carter	PERSON
to	O
tea	O
one	O
day	O
.	O

Harry	O
as	O
usual	O
here	O
for	O
2	O
days	O
.	O

Theo	PERSON
as	O
usual	O
in	O
the	O
Valley	O
3	O
days	O
.	O

Many	O
visitors	O
.	O

Saturday	O
.	O

Jan.	O
21	O
.	O

The	O
usual	O
weekly	O
story	O
--	O
visitors	O
,	O
visits	O
,	O
teas	O
and	O
dinners	O
.	O

Lady	O
Gorst	PERSON
and	O
Miss	O
Gorst	PERSON
here	O
for	O
tea	O
one	O
afternoon	O
.	O

Saturday	O
.	O

Jan.	O
28th	O
.	O

A	O
rather	O
cold	O
stormy	O
week	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
little	O
rain	O
.	O

Mrs.	O
Hunter	PERSON
of	O
London	LOCATION
dined	O
on	O
Monday	O
--	O
Mrs.	O
And	O
Miss	O
Warner	PERSON
of	O
Boston	LOCATION
and	O
Miss	O
Webb	PERSON
,	O
a	O
Marquise	PERSON
Guadalmina	PERSON
and	O
her	O
son	O
,	O
Spaniards	O
,	O
here	O
to	O
tea	O
on	O
Wednesday	O
.	O

Theo	PERSON
and	O
I	O
at	O
Mohassibs	LOCATION
one	O
morning	O
--	O
met	O
Miss	O
Cassatt	PERSON
,	O
the	O
artist	O
who	O
lives	O
in	O
Paris	LOCATION
.	O

Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Kelekian	PERSON
came	O
with	O
her	O
afterwards	O
for	O
tea	O
.	O

Mr	O
Nicol	PERSON
dined	O
on	O
Friday	O
.	O

Cold	O
and	O
stormy	O
.	O

PAGE	O
78	O
Saturday	O
.	O

Feb.	O
4th	O
Among	O
our	O
visitors	O
this	O
week	O
was	O
the	O
Rev.	O
Endicott	PERSON
Peabody	PERSON
,	O
Head	O
Master	O
of	O
the	O
famous	O
school	O
for	O
boys	O
at	O
Groton	LOCATION
,	O
Mass.	LOCATION
.	O

Introduced	O
by	O
cable	O
from	O
Mr.	O
Fairfield	PERSON
Osborn	PERSON
.	O

A	O
very	O
interesting	O
man	O
.	O

Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Newberry	PERSON
dined	O
on	O
Tuesday	O
.	O

Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Nahmstock	PERSON
to	O
lunch	O
on	O
Wednesday	O
.	O

Theo	PERSON
as	O
usual	O
in	O
the	O
Valley	O
3	O
days	O
.	O

Saturday	O
.	O

Feb.	O
11	O
.	O

Among	O
our	O
visitors	O
this	O
week	O
were	O
Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Charles	PERSON
B.	PERSON
Alexander	PERSON
of	O
4	O
West	LOCATION
58	LOCATION
St.	LOCATION
New	LOCATION
York	LOCATION
on	O
the	O
Serapis	O
with	O
their	O
3	O
girls	O
;	O
Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Henry	PERSON
Hobhouse	PERSON
of	O
England	LOCATION
introduced	O
by	O
Gaspard	PERSON
Farrer	PERSON
;	O
Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Williams	PERSON
and	O
Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Langley	PERSON
P.W.D.	O
people	O
of	O
Cairo	LOCATION
;	O
Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Gerard	PERSON
Foster	PERSON
of	O
Lenox	LOCATION
,	O
Miss	O
Ives	PERSON
and	O
Mrs.	O
Alexander	PERSON
of	O
New	LOCATION
York	LOCATION
whose	O
daughter	O
lately	O
married	O
young	O
Theodore	PERSON
Roosevelt	PERSON
;	O
Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
John	PERSON
Collander	PERSON
Livingston	PERSON
-LSB-	O
2	O
-RSB-	O
on	O
the	O
``	O
Scarab	O
''	O
.	O

It	O
has	O
been	O
bitterly	O
cold	O
lately	O
--	O
and	O
constant	O
high	O
winds	O
--	O
we	O
have	O
been	O
covered	O
with	O
sand	O
--	O
as	O
the	O
wind	O
has	O
been	O
from	O
the	O
west	O
.	O

Theo	PERSON
came	O
home	O
from	O
the	O
Valley	O
,	O
after	O
4	O
days	O
there	O
.	O

Sunday	O
.	O

Feb.	O
13th	O
.	O

Another	O
bitterly	O
cold	O
day	O
--	O
Mr.	O
Whymper	PERSON
to	O
breakfast	O
--	O
so	O
delightfully	O
amusing	O
.	O

I	O
had	O
a	O
quiet	O
morning	O
.	O

Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Girard	PERSON
Foster	PERSON
,	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Graham	PERSON
,	O
who	O
is	O
up	O
from	O
Cairo	LOCATION
,	O
for	O
a	O
few	O
days	O
,	O
came	O
to	O
tea	O
.	O

PAGE	O
79	O
Sunday	O
.	O

Feb.	O
19th	O
.	O

A	O
rather	O
monotonous	O
week	O
of	O
constant	O
visitors	O
.	O

Amongst	O
the	O
most	O
pleasant	O
were	O
Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
John	PERSON
Collander	PERSON
Livingston	PERSON
,	O
and	O
daughter	O
sent	O
by	O
Mrs.	O
Hamilton	PERSON
Fish	PERSON
Webster	PERSON
.	O

Delightful	O
people	O
.	O

Our	O
neighbors	O
Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Anchincloss	PERSON
and	O
Miss	O
Jennings	PERSON
,	O
M.	O
and	O
Mme.	O
Naville	PERSON
and	O
M.	PERSON
Rodier	PERSON
to	O
dine	O
.	O

Mrs.	O
And	O
Miss	O
Cherry	PERSON
,	O
sisters	O
of	O
Mr.	O
Cust	PERSON
,	O
M.	O
and	O
Mme.	O
Maspero	PERSON
and	O
others	O
.	O

Theo	PERSON
and	O
I	O
had	O
a	O
charming	O
afternoon	O
with	O
Mr.	O
Carter	PERSON
in	O
his	O
new	O
house	O
--	O
so	O
well	O
built	O
and	O
arranged	O
and	O
pretty	O
--	O
it	O
looked	O
like	O
the	O
abode	O
of	O
an	O
artist	O
and	O
a	O
scholar	O
.	O

He	O
is	O
just	O
opening	O
a	O
large	O
tomb	O
or	O
cachette	O
for	O
Lord	O
Carnarvon	O
--	O
and	O
when	O
we	O
had	O
tea	O
,	O
he	O
went	O
back	O
at	O
once	O
to	O
his	O
work	O
.	O

The	O
Hon.	O
Henry	PERSON
and	O
Mrs.	O
Hobhouse	PERSON
-LRB-	O
from	O
G.	PERSON
Farrer	PERSON
-RRB-	O
dined	O
with	O
us	O
this	O
evening	O
.	O

Theo	PERSON
is	O
to	O
give	O
them	O
lunch	O
in	O
the	O
Valley	LOCATION
tomorrow	O
.	O

Sunday	O
.	O

Feb.	O
26th	O
.	O

We	O
telegraphed	O
for	O
tug	O
some	O
days	O
ago	O
--	O
but	O
have	O
no	O
satisfactory	O
answers	O
--	O
the	O
boat	O
has	O
been	O
in	O
proper	O
trim	O
for	O
going	O
down	O
for	O
some	O
time	O
.	O

Such	O
continued	O
cold	O
weather	O
and	O
uch	O
gales	O
--	O
we	O
have	O
no	O
deck	O
life	O
at	O
all	O
.	O

Telegram	O
from	O
Mr.	O
J.P.	PERSON
Morgan	PERSON
begging	O
Theo	O
to	O
wait	O
here	O
until	O
he	O
comes	O
.	O

Crowds	O
of	O
visitors	O
.	O

Lady	PERSON
Layard	PERSON
,	O
and	O
the	O
Countess	O
here	O
to	O
tea	O
today	O
.	O

I	O
have	O
been	O
to	O
Karnak	LOCATION
several	O
times	O
--	O
Nicol	PERSON
here	O
twice	O
to	O
dine	O
.	O

Mar.	O
1	O
.	O

Ash	O
Wednesday	O
.	O

Mr	O
Morgan	PERSON
with	O
his	O
sister	O
arrived	O
on	O
the	O
Khonsu	LOCATION
--	O
on	O
Monday	O
,	O
PAGE	O
80	O
and	O
lunched	O
in	O
the	O
Valley	LOCATION
with	O
Theo	PERSON
.	O

I	O
did	O
not	O
go	O
out	O
.	O

Had	O
tea	O
on	O
the	O
Sudan	LOCATION
with	O
Mrs.	O
Anchincloss	PERSON
and	O
Miss	O
Jennings	PERSON
.	O

Over	O
to	O
say	O
goodbye	O
to	O
Contessa	PERSON
Contardone	PERSON
who	O
was	O
ill	O
in	O
bed	O
with	O
bad	O
cold	O
.	O

Friday	O
.	O

Mar.	O
3rd	O
.	O

Elèna	PERSON
arrived	O
from	O
Khartoum	LOCATION
last	O
evening	O
.	O

Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Newberry	PERSON
and	O
Mr.	O
Johnson	PERSON
-LRB-	O
Père	O
-RRB-	O
Mr.	O
Whymper	PERSON
were	O
here	O
for	O
tea	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Nicol	PERSON
to	O
dine	O
.	O

We	O
started	O
10	O
minutes	O
to	O
11	O
o'clock	O
--	O
and	O
at	O
6	O
p.m.	O
were	O
at	O
Keneh	LOCATION
,	O
where	O
we	O
waited	O
for	O
Harry	PERSON
and	O
Elèna	PERSON
to	O
visit	O
Dendera	LOCATION
--	O
then	O
we	O
moved	O
on	O
2-3	O
miles	O
for	O
the	O
night	O
--	O
making	O
altogether	O
50	O
miles	O
.	O

Saturday	O
.	O

Mar.	O
4th	O
.	O

40	O
miles	O
.	O

Sailed	O
at	O
7	O
A.M.	O
--	O
reached	O
Nagh	PERSON
Hamadi	PERSON
at	O
12:15	O
,	O
passed	O
the	O
bridge	O
and	O
then	O
waited	O
until	O
3:30	O
,	O
waiting	O
for	O
the	O
tug	O
to	O
cool	O
--	O
and	O
reached	O
Balliana	LOCATION
at	O
5:30	O
where	O
we	O
wait	O
until	O
tomorrow	O
--	O
to	O
give	O
Elèna	PERSON
Rathbone	PERSON
a	O
chance	O
to	O
see	O
Abydos	LOCATION
--	O
and	O
we	O
promised	O
the	O
Navilles	LOCATION
to	O
lunch	O
with	O
them	O
.	O

It	O
has	O
been	O
a	O
fine	O
,	O
warm	O
day	O
--	O
and	O
our	O
brillian	O
young	O
moon	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
resplendent	O
Venus	PERSON
,	O
make	O
the	O
nights	O
too	O
beautiful	O
to	O
sleep	O
.	O

Monday	O
.	O

Mar.	O
6th	O
.	O

Started	O
about	O
10	O
for	O
Abydos	LOCATION
--	O
fearing	O
a	O
hot	O
day	O
--	O
had	O
2	O
carriages	O
--	O
we	O
found	O
a	O
cold	O
north	O
wind	O
blowing	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
really	O
suffered	O
with	O
cold	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
a	O
market	O
day	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
people	O
were	O
streaming	O
along	O
the	O
dusty	O
road	O
--	O
men	O
,	O
women	O
carrying	O
babies	O
,	O
camels	O
,	O
donkeys	O
,	O
sheep	O
and	O
PAGE	O
81	O
goats	O
--	O
making	O
the	O
air	O
thick	O
with	O
dust	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
such	O
a	O
pity	O
that	O
one	O
must	O
always	O
see	O
Abydos	LOCATION
in	O
the	O
glare	O
of	O
mid-day	O
!	O

Mme.	O
Naville	PERSON
came	O
up	O
from	O
their	O
little	O
house	O
in	O
its	O
nest	O
in	O
the	O
sandy	O
desert	O
,	O
to	O
see	O
us	O
--	O
and	O
we	O
all	O
went	O
back	O
with	O
her	O
--	O
I	O
sitting	O
on	O
a	O
man	O
's	O
saddle	O
on	O
a	O
wretched	O
donkey	O
,	O
-	O
the	O
cold	O
wind	O
almost	O
blowing	O
my	O
clothes	O
off	O
--	O
and	O
my	O
eyes	O
blinded	O
.	O

But	O
the	O
little	O
house	O
was	O
cheerful	O
and	O
comfortable	O
and	O
the	O
lunch	O
very	O
good	O
,	O
and	O
M.	O
and	O
Mme.	O
Naville	PERSON
very	O
nice	O
as	O
they	O
always	O
are	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Whitmore	PERSON
and	O
Mr.	O
Dixon	PERSON
,	O
young	O
men	O
working	O
with	O
the	O
Navilles	LOCATION
.	O

The	O
ride	O
home	O
was	O
away	O
from	O
the	O
wind	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
fields	O
so	O
green	O
and	O
fragrant	O
with	O
their	O
blossoming	O
crops	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
birds	O
singing	O
everywhere	O
.	O

The	O
people	O
were	O
in	O
their	O
straw	O
houses	O
,	O
which	O
they	O
build	O
for	O
watching	O
their	O
crops	O
--	O
and	O
it	O
was	O
very	O
pastoral	O
.	O

Found	O
a	O
huge	O
mail	O
waiting	O
for	O
us	O
.	O

We	O
steamed	O
down	O
to	O
Girga	PERSON
,	O
8	O
miles	O
,	O
and	O
are	O
here	O
for	O
the	O
night	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
.	O

Mar.	O
7th	O
.	O

Started	O
at	O
6	O
A.M.	O
and	O
went	O
on	O
until	O
6	O
P.M.	O
-	O
5	O
miles	O
from	O
Assiut	LOCATION
--	O
making	O
87	O
miles	O
.	O

Wednesday	O
.	O

Mar.	O
8th	O
.	O

52	O
miles	O
.	O

Arrived	O
at	O
Assiut	LOCATION
early	O
,	O
and	O
waited	O
for	O
various	O
things	O
--	O
4	O
hours	O
--	O
then	O
on	O
to	O
7	O
miles	O
of	O
Hadj	PERSON
Kandul	PERSON
.	O

Thursday	O
.	O

March	O
9th	O
.	O

Started	O
at	O
7	O
o'clock	O
--	O
stopped	O
at	O
Hagi	PERSON
Kondul	PERSON
for	O
an	O
hour	O
PAGE	O
82	O
so	O
that	O
Elèna	PERSON
should	O
see	O
the	O
Khuenaton	LOCATION
pavement	O
,	O
then	O
on	O
,	O
until	O
Beni	PERSON
Hassan	PERSON
was	O
reached	O
,	O
which	O
Elèna	PERSON
and	O
Harry	PERSON
visited	O
.	O

The	O
day	O
hot	O
--	O
wind	O
and	O
clouds	O
of	O
dust	O
.	O

43	O
miles	O
.	O

Friday	O
,	O
March	O
10th	O
.	O

53	O
miles	O
.	O

Started	O
at	O
7	O
o'clock	O
--	O
spent	O
2	O
hours	O
at	O
Minia	LOCATION
--	O
tied	O
up	O
at	O
6	O
o'clock	O
at	O
Maghaga	LOCATION
.	O

Saturday	O
.	O

Mar.	O
11th	O
.	O

87	O
miles	O
.	O

An	O
early	O
start	O
at	O
6	O
o'clock	O
--	O
and	O
reached	O
Bedreschein	PERSON
at	O
7	O
o'clock	O
.	O

The	O
river	O
has	O
been	O
rather	O
good	O
.	O

The	O
tug	O
has	O
been	O
on	O
the	O
sand	O
once	O
or	O
twice	O
for	O
a	O
short	O
time	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
dahabya	O
has	O
not	O
once	O
touched	O
it	O
--	O
a	O
strong	O
wind	O
all	O
day	O
and	O
cold	O
.	O

Second	O
Sunday	O
in	O
Lent	O
.	O

March	O
12th	O
.	O

Started	O
at	O
7	O
o'clock	O
--	O
and	O
made	O
the	O
bridge	O
at	O
9	O
o'clock	O
and	O
waited	O
an	O
hour	O
to	O
pass	O
.	O

Came	O
to	O
our	O
landing	O
at	O
11.30	O
--	O
and	O
found	O
the	O
mooring	O
garden	O
looking	O
very	O
pretty	O
.	O

We	O
arrived	O
the	O
10th	O
day	O
from	O
Luxor	LOCATION
.	O

Found	O
telegram	O
telling	O
of	O
Harold	PERSON
Jones	PERSON
'	O
peaceful	O
end	O
on	O
Thursday	O
,	O
the	O
9th	O
.	O

March	O
13th	O
.	O

Monday	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Draper	PERSON
to	O
lunch	O
yesterday	O
.	O

At	O
home	O
all	O
day	O
--	O
rather	O
warm	O
today	O
.	O

Elèna	PERSON
and	O
I	O
drove	O
into	O
town	O
this	O
morning	O
--	O
saw	O
a	O
number	O
PAGE	O
83	O
of	O
friends	O
--	O
met	O
Mr.	O
Newberry	PERSON
at	O
Deimers	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
he	O
went	O
with	O
us	O
to	O
Kolekians	LOCATION
and	O
to	O
Kasseras	LOCATION
--	O
there	O
Theo	PERSON
and	O
Harry	PERSON
joined	O
us	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
went	O
to	O
Nachmans	O
.	O

Elèna	PERSON
and	O
Harry	PERSON
went	O
after	O
lunch	O
to	O
the	O
Mena	ORGANIZATION
House	ORGANIZATION
,	O
and	O
Theo	PERSON
and	O
I	O
went	O
for	O
a	O
drive	O
--	O
and	O
finding	O
ourselves	O
,	O
in	O
spite	O
of	O
warm	O
wraps	O
,	O
freezing	O
in	O
the	O
cold	O
wind	O
,	O
we	O
came	O
home	O
.	O

March	O
14th	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
.	O

At	O
home	O
all	O
day	O
--	O
still	O
cold	O
and	O
windy	O
.	O

Wednesday	O
.	O

March	O
15th	O
.	O

Elèna	PERSON
and	O
Harry	PERSON
made	O
and	O
early	O
start	O
for	O
Sakkara	LOCATION
--	O
going	O
by	O
train	O
to	O
the	O
Mena	ORGANIZATION
House	ORGANIZATION
,	O
and	O
taking	O
donkeys	O
for	O
Sakkara	LOCATION
.	O

They	O
came	O
back	O
at	O
7	O
P.M.	O
after	O
a	O
joyful	O
day	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Winlock	PERSON
appeared	O
this	O
morning	O
at	O
10	O
--	O
and	O
made	O
quite	O
a	O
visit	O
--	O
then	O
he	O
,	O
Theo	PERSON
and	O
I	O
went	O
to	O
town	O
,	O
and	O
to	O
Kyticas	LOCATION
's	O
to	O
see	O
a	O
lovely	O
Greek	O
statuette	O
which	O
Theo	PERSON
thinks	O
of	O
buying	O
.	O

Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Newberry	PERSON
and	O
Mr.	O
Johnson	PERSON
came	O
to	O
lunch	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
had	O
such	O
a	O
pleasant	O
visit	O
.	O

I	O
went	O
at	O
5	O
o'clock	O
over	O
to	O
the	O
Cleopatra	O
to	O
tea	O
with	O
the	O
Whittakers	O
--	O
Lady	O
Layard	PERSON
,	O
and	O
the	O
2	O
ladies	O
staying	O
with	O
them	O
,	O
Mr.	O
Johnson	PERSON
and	O
Capt.	O
Trefusis	PERSON
there	O
.	O

Coming	O
home	O
,	O
I	O
overtook	O
Theo	O
walking	O
,	O
and	O
as	O
the	O
cold	O
,	O
cold	O
wind	O
had	O
much	O
moderated	O
,	O
and	O
he	O
got	O
into	O
the	O
carriage	O
,	O
we	O
drove	O
around	O
the	O
island	O
.	O

Thursday	O
.	O

Nov.	O
16th	O
.	O

In	O
town	O
this	O
morning	O
--	O
met	O
Artin	PERSON
Pasha	PERSON
,	O
and	O
Mr.	O
Sayce	PERSON
at	O
Kyticas	LOCATION
's	O
--	O
then	O
went	O
to	O
the	O
Museum	O
--	O
M.	PERSON
Daressy	PERSON
took	O
us	O
into	O
his	O
PAGE	O
84	O
working	O
room	O
,	O
to	O
show	O
how	O
he	O
was	O
succeeding	O
with	O
the	O
restoring	O
of	O
the	O
beautiful	O
coffin	O
found	O
in	O
Queen	O
Tiyi	PERSON
's	O
tomb	O
--	O
a	O
long	O
and	O
very	O
difficult	O
task	O
it	O
is	O
.	O

Friday	O
.	O

Mar.	O
17	O
.	O

The	O
morning	O
was	O
so	O
very	O
hot	O
,	O
that	O
we	O
did	O
nothing	O
but	O
drive	O
until	O
12	O
o'clock	O
--	O
when	O
I	O
left	O
Theo	PERSON
at	O
the	O
boat	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
went	O
to	O
the	O
Semeraine	O
's	O
Hotel	O
to	O
see	O
Mrs.	O
Duvar	PERSON
--	O
she	O
was	O
not	O
at	O
home	O
.	O

I	O
left	O
a	O
note	O
for	O
her	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
afternoon	O
,	O
Elèna	PERSON
went	O
with	O
Mr.	O
Bonar-Carter	PERSON
to	O
polo	O
--	O
Harry	O
and	O
Mr.	O
Whymper	PERSON
to	O
the	O
Zoo	O
,	O
where	O
Theo	PERSON
and	O
I	O
soon	O
followed	O
them	O
--	O
and	O
had	O
a	O
lovely	O
visit	O
.	O

Just	O
as	O
we	O
came	O
away	O
,	O
we	O
me	O
Artin	PERSON
Pasha	PERSON
,	O
and	O
Mr.	O
Sayce	PERSON
,	O
who	O
said	O
they	O
had	O
just	O
been	O
to	O
the	O
boat	O
hoping	O
to	O
find	O
us	O
,	O
so	O
they	O
came	O
back	O
all	O
of	O
them	O
for	O
tea	O
,	O
and	O
a	O
long	O
visit	O
,	O
and	O
much	O
pleasant	O
talk	O
.	O

Saturday	O
.	O

Mar.	O
18th	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
house	O
all	O
day	O
--	O
a	O
severe	O
gale	O
began	O
about	O
7	O
o'clock	O
--	O
and	O
grew	O
in	O
violence	O
--	O
making	O
a	O
great	O
knocking	O
about	O
of	O
the	O
boats	O
along	O
the	O
shore	O
--	O
a	O
small	O
yawl	O
disappeared	O
just	O
behind	O
us	O
--	O
and	O
a	O
gyassa	O
was	O
wrecked	O
near	O
the	O
bridge	O
.	O

Cairo	LOCATION
could	O
not	O
be	O
seen	O
across	O
the	O
river	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
clouds	O
of	O
dust	O
.	O

In	O
doors	O
all	O
day	O
.	O

Sunday	O
.	O

Mar.	O
19th	O
.	O

The	O
weather	O
quite	O
perfect	O
today	O
.	O

I	O
have	O
not	O
been	O
out	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Bonham	PERSON
Carter	PERSON
came	O
in	O
this	O
afternoon	O
--	O
and	O
Capt.	O
Trefusis	PERSON
--	O
looking	O
PAGE	O
85	O
so	O
well	O
,	O
and	O
announcing	O
his	O
engagement	O
to	O
Miss	O
Margery	PERSON
Graham	PERSON
--	O
the	O
marriage	O
to	O
take	O
place	O
in	O
May	O
.	O

She	O
is	O
a	O
daughter	O
of	O
Sir	O
John	PERSON
Graham	PERSON
and	O
a	O
niece	O
of	O
Lord	O
Northampton	LOCATION
.	O

Monday	O
.	O

Mar.	O
20th	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
house	O
all	O
day	O
,	O
except	O
for	O
a	O
short	O
visit	O
to	O
town	O
.	O

Mrs.	O
Dewar	PERSON
came	O
for	O
a	O
visit	O
at	O
12	O
o'clock	O
--	O
and	O
Miss	O
Coater	O
for	O
lunch	O
.	O

Since	O
then	O
I	O
have	O
been	O
busy	O
packing	O
.	O

The	O
day	O
has	O
been	O
decidedly	O
cool	O
.	O

Thursday	O
.	O

Mar.	O
23rd	O
Ghezireh	O
Palace	O
Hotel	O
We	O
came	O
here	O
this	O
afternoon	O
to	O
our	O
old	O
rooms	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
sad	O
to	O
leave	O
the	O
dahabya	O
--	O
but	O
the	O
garden	O
and	O
lawns	O
and	O
trees	O
are	O
so	O
lovely	O
here	O
,	O
and	O
our	O
big	O
windows	O
let	O
in	O
so	O
much	O
of	O
it	O
to	O
us	O
--	O
that	O
it	O
is	O
quite	O
lovely	O
.	O

Maspero	PERSON
to	O
Louise	PERSON
,	O
11/10/1910	O
``	O
Maspero	PERSON
Lettres	PERSON
to	O
Louise	PERSON
p	O
497	O
CAIRE	O
,	O
LE	O
10	O
NOVEMBRE	O
1910	O
Le	O
travail	O
commence	O
á	O
abonder	O
au	O
Musée	O
:	O
les	O
touristes	O
et	O
les	O
fouilleurs	O
rentrent	O
.	O

Davis	PERSON
est	O
arrivé	O
avant-hier	O
,	O
florissant	O
,	O
avec	O
Madame	PERSON
Andrews	PERSON
et	O
une	O
nièce	O
nouvelle	O
du	O
nom	O
de	O
Rathbone	O
,	O
une	O
grande	O
et	O
belle	O
fille	O
un	O
peu	O
fanée	O
-LRB-	O
wilted	O
-RRB-	O
,	O
mais	O
de	O
manières	O
très	O
supérieures	O
á	O
celles	O
des	O
nièces	O
des	O
années	O
précédentes	O
.	O

II	O
est	O
plus	O
bruyant	O
que	O
jamais	O
,	O
mais	O
toujours	O
brave	O
homme	O
,	O
et	O
nous	O
avons	O
été	O
contents	O
l'un	O
et	O
I	O
`	O
autre	O
de	O
nous	O
revoir	O
.	O

Ils	O
resteront	O
une	O
huitaine	O
de	O
jours	O
ici	O
,	O
le	O
temps	O
de	O
mettre	O
la	O
Bédouine	O
en	O
etat	O
de	O
naviguer	O
.	O

Parlant	O
de	O
dahabiéh	O
,	O
où	O
as-tu	O
mis	O
la	O
clef	O
de	O
notre	O
cabine	O
dans	O
la	O
Miriam	PERSON
?	O

Nous	O
en	O
avons	O
besoin	O
pour	O
faire	O
donner	O
une	O
couche	O
de	O
peinture	O
.	O

Je	O
vais	O
la	O
rechercher	O
encore	O
,	O
mais	O
dis-moi	O
de	O
toute	O
façon	O
si	O
tu	O
te	O
rappelles	O
où	O
elle	O
est	O
:	O
iI-est	O
possible	O
que	O
,	O
malgré	O
tout	O
,	O
je	O
ne	O
la	O
retrouve	O
point	O
par	O
mes	O
seules	O
lumieres	O
-LSB-	O
...	O
-RSB-	O
Callender	PERSON
Livingston	PERSON
?	O

Per	O
Pelham	O
history	O
website	O
11	O
1910-1911	O
11	O

