A	O
JOURNAL	O
ON	O
THE	O
BEDAWIN	O
1889	O
--	O
1912	O
The	O
Diary	O
kept	O
on	O
board	O
the	O
dahabiyeh	O
of	O
THEODORE	PERSON
M.	PERSON
DAVIS	PERSON
during	O
seventeen	O
trips	O
up	O
the	O
Nile	O
by	O
MRS.	PERSON
EMMA	PERSON
B.	PERSON
ANDREWS	PERSON
VOL	O
.	O

II	O
TYPEWRITTEN	O
BY	O
E.	PERSON
P.	PERSON
B.	PERSON
MCMXVIII	PERSON
Bedrescheyn	PERSON
--	O
Egypt	LOCATION
.	O

Dec.	O
12	O
,	O
1898	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
just	O
one	O
month	O
today	O
that	O
we	O
sailed	O
from	O
New	LOCATION
York	LOCATION
,	O
again	O
on	O
the	O
Kaiser	PERSON
Wilhem	PERSON
II	PERSON
.	O

The	O
voyage	O
was	O
a	O
slow	O
and	O
very	O
tiresome	O
one	O
.	O

The	O
weather	O
warm	O
,	O
grey	O
and	O
showery	O
.	O

We	O
reached	O
Gibraltar	LOCATION
the	O
evening	O
of	O
Monday	O
the	O
21st	O
about	O
8	O
o'clock	O
--	O
and	O
lost	O
that	O
ever	O
interesting	O
sight	O
of	O
the	O
approach	O
of	O
the	O
big	O
rock	O
.	O

A	O
fleet	O
of	O
seven	O
English	O
war	O
vessels	O
were	O
in	O
harbour	O
,	O
and	O
would	O
have	O
made	O
a	O
pretty	O
spectacle	O
by	O
daylight	O
.	O

Got	O
away	O
at	O
10	O
o'clock	O
,	O
and	O
reached	O
Naples	LOCATION
too	O
late	O
on	O
the	O
evening	O
of	O
the	O
24th	O
to	O
land	O
--	O
although	O
every	O
one	O
was	O
packed	O
and	O
ready	O
to	O
get	O
off	O
.	O

The	O
disappointment	O
was	O
all	O
the	O
greater	O
.	O

We	O
passed	O
the	O
usual	O
night	O
of	O
din	O
and	O
turmoil	O
,	O
incident	O
to	O
coaling	O
,	O
and	O
landed	O
at	O
8	O
o'clock	O
the	O
next	O
morning	O
,	O
finding	O
Andersen	PERSON
and	O
Mary	PERSON
Buttles	PERSON
waiting	O
for	O
us	O
.	O

A	O
day	O
and	O
night	O
at	O
the	O
Grand	LOCATION
Hotel	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
off	O
on	O
Saturday	O
in	O
the	O
very	O
comfortable	O
``	O
Regina	O
Margherita	O
''	O
for	O
Alexandria	LOCATION
which	O
we	O
reached	O
on	O
Tuesday	O
morning	O
at	O
9	O
o'clock	O
and	O
Cairo	LOCATION
in	O
the	O
evening	O
.	O

Mrs.	O
Edwin	PERSON
Parsons	PERSON
-LRB-	O
Lellie	PERSON
Swayne	PERSON
-RRB-	O
with	O
two	O
nieces	O
came	O
out	O
with	O
us	O
from	O
New	LOCATION
York	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
has	O
engaged	O
the	O
dahabeah	O
Sol	O
el-Nil	O
,	O
commonly	O
known	O
as	O
the	O
Hungarian	O
dahabeah	O
,	O
and	O
our	O
faithful	O
old	O
Salah	PERSON
and	O
we	O
all	O
started	O
together	O
this	O
morning	O
,	O
and	O
will	O
keep	O
together	O
.	O

She	O
is	O
delighted	O
with	O
everything	O
and	O
so	O
is	O
Bessie	PERSON
Whaling	PERSON
whom	O
we	O
brought	O
for	O
the	O
winter	O
.	O

There	O
is	O
the	O
usual	O
crowd	O
at	O
Cairo	LOCATION
,	O
thinner	O
perhaps	O
as	O
we	O
are	O
nearly	O
two	O
weeks	O
earlier	O
than	O
usual	O
.	O

The	O
Nile	O
is	O
very	O
high	O
this	O
year	O
--	O
and	O
we	O
have	O
just	O
Page	O
2	O
escaped	O
a	O
week	O
of	O
rain	O
which	O
they	O
have	O
had	O
here	O
,	O
and	O
which	O
has	O
filled	O
Cairo	LOCATION
with	O
mosquitos	O
.	O

And	O
right	O
glad	O
I	O
was	O
to	O
escape	O
Shepheards	O
,	O
and	O
constant	O
combats	O
with	O
mosquitos	O
,	O
and	O
come	O
to	O
our	O
own	O
home	O
on	O
this	O
beautiful	O
Bedouin	O
.	O

She	O
has	O
never	O
been	O
in	O
such	O
perfect	O
order	O
--	O
or	O
so	O
pretty	O
and	O
comfortable	O
--	O
and	O
peace	O
and	O
repose	O
are	O
again	O
descending	O
upon	O
me	O
.	O

Bedrescheyn	O
.	O

Dec.	O
13	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
.	O

Everyone	O
went	O
out	O
to	O
Saqqara	LOCATION
this	O
morning	O
except	O
Lellie	PERSON
Parsons	PERSON
and	O
myself	O
.	O

About	O
4	O
o'clock	O
it	O
began	O
to	O
look	O
rather	O
threatening	O
--	O
and	O
in	O
a	O
few	O
moments	O
the	O
rain	O
came	O
in	O
torrents	O
.	O

I	O
never	O
saw	O
it	O
rain	O
more	O
furiously	O
for	O
a	O
little	O
while	O
.	O

Great	O
excitement	O
on	O
the	O
boat	O
--	O
all	O
hands	O
gathering	O
the	O
bread	O
that	O
was	O
drying	O
on	O
deck	O
into	O
safe	O
quarters	O
.	O

I	O
had	O
to	O
take	O
refuge	O
below	O
,	O
while	O
the	O
deck	O
was	O
quickly	O
dismantled	O
and	O
everything	O
put	O
under	O
canvass	O
.	O

I	O
was	O
uncomfortable	O
about	O
our	O
people	O
--	O
as	O
I	O
saw	O
the	O
Cook	PERSON
party	O
from	O
the	O
Ramesis	O
arriving	O
in	O
bedraggled	O
condition	O
.	O

But	O
they	O
came	O
home	O
dry	O
,	O
having	O
taken	O
refuge	O
under	O
cover	O
.	O

It	O
has	O
rained	O
at	O
intervals	O
since	O
--	O
is	O
warm	O
-	O
the	O
cloud	O
scenery	O
after	O
the	O
heavy	O
storm	O
was	O
wonderful	O
.	O

Our	O
boat	O
did	O
not	O
leak	O
in	O
the	O
slightest	O
degree	O
.	O

Wednesday	O
,	O
Dec.	O
.	O

14	O
.	O

Beautiful	O
weather	O
,	O
but	O
no	O
wind	O
until	O
about	O
4	O
o'clock	O
,	O
when	O
we	O
started	O
and	O
made	O
a	O
mile	O
or	O
two	O
.	O

Thursday	O
,	O
Dec.	O
.	O

15	O
.	O

Did	O
not	O
move	O
--	O
lovely	O
,	O
serene	O
weather	O
--	O
no	O
wind	O
.	O

Thermometer	O
Page	O
3	O
at	O
2	O
o'clock	O
in	O
the	O
shade	O
stood	O
at	O
65	O
˚	O
.	O

Friday	O
,	O
Dec.	O
.	O

16	O
.	O

Our	O
men	O
tracked	O
about	O
half	O
a	O
mile	O
,	O
but	O
Theodore	PERSON
thinks	O
this	O
such	O
a	O
waste	O
of	O
time	O
and	O
strength	O
,	O
that	O
he	O
does	O
not	O
often	O
permit	O
it	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
still	O
in	O
sight	O
of	O
Helouan	O
--	O
and	O
the	O
Saqqara	LOCATION
pyramids	O
.	O

Saturday	O
,	O
Dec.	O
.	O

17	O
.	O

We	O
all	O
took	O
a	O
walk	O
into	O
the	O
town	O
on	O
the	O
railroad	O
this	O
morning	O
to	O
post	O
some	O
letters	O
.	O

Our	O
way	O
was	O
by	O
the	O
pleasant	O
palm	O
forest	O
--	O
along	O
the	O
canal	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
picturesque	O
,	O
but	O
vilely	O
smelling	O
mud	O
town	O
.	O

A	O
charming	O
country	O
about	O
--	O
still	O
no	O
wind	O
--	O
but	O
rather	O
promising	O
signs	O
in	O
the	O
sky	O
this	O
evening	O
.	O

Wasta	O
.	O

Dec.	O
.	O

18	O
.	O

Fourth	O
Sunday	O
in	O
Advent	O
.	O

36	O
miles	O
.	O

We	O
at	O
last	O
got	O
off	O
this	O
morning	O
at	O
7	O
o'clock	O
,	O
in	O
a	O
good	O
wind	O
that	O
held	O
finely	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
had	O
a	O
glorious	O
run	O
,	O
bringing	O
up	O
here	O
at	O
4	O
o'clock	O
.	O

The	O
Lul	PERSON
el	O
Nil	O
,	O
came	O
along	O
an	O
hour	O
after	O
--	O
and	O
tomorrow	O
we	O
will	O
all	O
go	O
by	O
rail	O
to	O
the	O
Fayum	LOCATION
--	O
returning	O
the	O
same	O
day	O
.	O

This	O
will	O
not	O
of	O
course	O
give	O
us	O
time	O
to	O
see	O
much	O
.	O

But	O
the	O
Greek	ORGANIZATION
Inn	ORGANIZATION
at	O
the	O
Medina	LOCATION
is	O
impossible	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
could	O
not	O
see	O
our	O
way	O
to	O
doing	O
the	O
whole	O
thing	O
,	O
much	O
as	O
we	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
see	O
it	O
,	O
as	O
we	O
should	O
be	O
obliged	O
to	O
carry	O
a	O
camp	O
outfit	O
and	O
spend	O
three	O
or	O
four	O
days	O
there	O
.	O

High	O
wind	O
tonight	O
and	O
we	O
are	O
rolling	O
a	O
good	O
deal	O
.	O

Page	O
4	O
Monday	O
,	O
Dec.	O
.	O

19	O
.	O

Started	O
for	O
El	PERSON
Medina	PERSON
,	O
Fayum	LOCATION
by	O
rail	O
at	O
10:30	O
,	O
Parson	PERSON
included	O
--	O
and	O
folted	O
in	O
fairly	O
comfortable	O
fashion	O
across	O
the	O
desert	O
to	O
Medina	LOCATION
which	O
we	O
reached	O
at	O
12	O
o'clock	O
--	O
and	O
had	O
an	O
excellent	O
luncheon	O
at	O
the	O
Hotel	LOCATION
du	LOCATION
Fayoum	LOCATION
--	O
where	O
one	O
could	O
be	O
very	O
comfortable	O
for	O
a	O
few	O
days	O
and	O
see	O
the	O
district	O
thoroughly	O
.	O

Then	O
we	O
had	O
3	O
carriages	O
!	O

and	O
drove	O
about	O
through	O
the	O
town	O
and	O
environs	O
.	O

The	O
town	O
is	O
quite	O
European	O
,	O
is	O
of	O
much	O
importance	O
,	O
40,000	O
inhabitants	O
--	O
and	O
the	O
great	O
canal	O
,	O
the	O
Bahr	LOCATION
Jusuf	LOCATION
which	O
leaves	O
the	O
Nile	LOCATION
near	O
Assiut	LOCATION
and	O
flows	O
to	O
the	O
Fayoum	LOCATION
gives	O
extraordinary	O
fertility	O
to	O
this	O
district	O
.	O

Its	O
many	O
branches	O
flowing	O
through	O
the	O
town	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
numerous	O
bridges	O
we	O
crossed	O
gave	O
many	O
novel	O
features	O
--	O
making	O
a	O
kind	O
of	O
Egyptian	O
Venice	LOCATION
or	O
Amsterdam	LOCATION
.	O

Very	O
good	O
streets	O
,	O
with	O
handsome	O
buildings	O
,	O
and	O
gardens	O
--	O
most	O
interesting	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
made	O
the	O
acquaintance	O
of	O
an	O
unknown	O
Englishman	O
who	O
has	O
lived	O
there	O
for	O
10	O
years	O
--	O
and	O
he	O
says	O
one	O
can	O
drive	O
quite	O
comfortably	O
to	O
the	O
pyramids	O
of	O
Hawara	LOCATION
and	O
Illahun	LOCATION
.	O

Home	O
by	O
5	O
o'clock	O
tired	O
and	O
glad	O
.	O

Fine	O
evening	O
effects	O
returning	O
across	O
the	O
desert	O
.	O

The	O
Meydum	O
pyramid	O
touched	O
to	O
radiance	O
by	O
the	O
setting	O
sun	O
,	O
while	O
all	O
about	O
was	O
grey	O
and	O
dark	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
,	O
Dec.	O
.	O

20	O
.	O

Very	O
heavy	O
fog	O
this	O
morning	O
--	O
and	O
no	O
wind	O
until	O
11	O
o'clock	O
--	O
very	O
shifting	O
all	O
day	O
--	O
with	O
heavy	O
clouds	O
about	O
late	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
,	O
and	O
some	O
lightning	O
and	O
a	O
little	O
rain	O
.	O

Made	O
about	O
6	O
miles	O
.	O

I	O
had	O
one	O
charming	O
hour	O
on	O
deck	O
just	O
after	O
lunch	O
,	O
while	O
we	O
were	O
anchored	O
in	O
a	O
Page	O
5	O
dead	O
calm	O
.	O

Water	O
like	O
glass	O
--	O
the	O
delicate	O
colouring	O
of	O
that	O
hour	O
of	O
the	O
day	O
--	O
the	O
utter	O
stillness	O
only	O
emphasised	O
by	O
a	O
boat	O
descending	O
the	O
other	O
side	O
of	O
the	O
wide	O
river	O
,	O
with	O
its	O
boatmen	O
crooning	O
and	O
singing	O
.	O

What	O
heavenly	O
repose	O
!	O

Wednesday	O
,	O
Dec.	O
.	O

21	O
.	O

A	O
cool	O
morning	O
and	O
but	O
little	O
wind	O
until	O
about	O
3	O
P.M.	O
when	O
with	O
a	O
west	O
wind	O
we	O
sailed	O
until	O
4:30	O
and	O
made	O
near	O
6	O
miles	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
obliged	O
to	O
tie	O
up	O
to	O
the	O
bank	O
.	O

Thursday	O
,	O
Dec.	O
.	O

22	O
.	O

3	O
miles	O
.	O

A	O
splendid	O
cloudless	O
day	O
with	O
light	O
south	O
west	O
wind	O
--	O
we	O
pulled	O
to	O
the	O
anchor	O
to	O
opposite	O
side	O
of	O
river	O
,	O
tracked	O
a	O
little	O
way	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
pulled	O
back	O
and	O
tracked	O
--	O
making	O
3	O
miles	O
,	O
we	O
suppose	O
we	O
are	O
about	O
15	O
miles	O
south	O
of	O
Wasta	LOCATION
.	O

A	O
radiant	O
night	O
!	O

Friday	O
,	O
Dec.	O
.	O

23	O
.	O

One	O
mile	O
.	O

S.E.	O
wind	O
still	O
holds	O
--	O
tracked	O
a	O
little	O
--	O
and	O
beginning	O
to	O
feel	O
a	O
little	O
discouraged	O
.	O

The	O
``	O
Thames	O
''	O
with	O
the	O
Kidders	O
from	O
Boston	LOCATION
,	O
is	O
lying	O
ahead	O
of	O
us	O
,	O
too	O
far	O
for	O
visiting	O
.	O

The	O
``	O
Eurydice	O
''	O
somewhere	O
near	O
her	O
,	O
on	O
which	O
are	O
a	O
Canadian	O
family	O
-LRB-	O
Smith	PERSON
-RRB-	O
who	O
crossed	O
with	O
us	O
on	O
the	O
Kaiser	PERSON
Wilhem	PERSON
.	O

Page	O
6	O
Saturday	O
,	O
Dec.	O
.	O

24	O
.	O

Still	O
lying	O
where	O
we	O
were	O
last	O
night	O
with	O
high	O
south	O
wind	O
blowing	O
.	O

If	O
it	O
had	O
not	O
been	O
so	O
cold	O
last	O
night	O
,	O
I	O
should	O
have	O
thought	O
a	O
khamseen	O
coming	O
for	O
it	O
has	O
been	O
thick	O
and	O
hazy	O
all	O
day	O
--	O
the	O
sun	O
a	O
pale	O
round	O
orb	O
disappearing	O
early	O
in	O
an	O
atmosphere	O
laden	O
with	O
dust	O
and	O
sand	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
been	O
trying	O
to	O
put	O
the	O
boat	O
into	O
festive	O
Xmas	O
attire	O
with	O
the	O
very	O
poor	O
things	O
we	O
could	O
find	O
at	O
a	O
garden	O
near	O
here	O
.	O

The	O
little	O
salon	O
now	O
looks	O
gay	O
with	O
bunches	O
of	O
rosemary	O
in	O
masses	O
over	O
sideboard	O
and	O
pictures	O
,	O
making	O
a	O
pleasant	O
atmosphere	O
--	O
and	O
looking	O
like	O
hemlocks	O
.	O

Christmas	O
.	O

Dec.	O
.	O

25	O
.	O

Sunday	O
.	O

A	O
brilliant	O
,	O
beautiful	O
morning	O
--	O
and	O
our	O
breakfast	O
table	O
had	O
a	O
very	O
festive	O
air	O
with	O
its	O
flowers	O
,	O
and	O
its	O
many	O
presents	O
.	O

Mrs.	O
Parsons	PERSON
and	O
the	O
girls	O
came	O
to	O
dine	O
--	O
and	O
we	O
had	O
a	O
nice	O
evening	O
.	O

The	O
same	O
S.W.	O
gale	O
has	O
continued	O
to	O
blow	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
have	O
not	O
moved	O
.	O

Monday	O
,	O
Dec.	O
.	O

26	O
.	O

8	O
miles	O
.	O

West	O
wind	O
--	O
between	O
tracking	O
and	O
sailing	O
made	O
8	O
miles	O
,	O
and	O
are	O
now	O
near	O
Benisoef	LOCATION
,	O
tied	O
up	O
to	O
an	O
island	O
.	O

It	O
has	O
rained	O
slightly	O
two	O
or	O
three	O
times	O
this	O
afternoon	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
.	O

Dec.	O
.	O

27	O
.	O

13	O
miles	O
.	O

A	O
strong	O
wind	O
,	O
dying	O
down	O
by	O
11	O
o'clock	O
,	O
enabled	O
Page	O
7	O
us	O
to	O
make	O
a	O
start	O
,	O
and	O
tracking	O
,	O
pulling	O
to	O
the	O
anchor	O
,	O
and	O
sailing	O
brought	O
us	O
near	O
Bibeh	LOCATION
,	O
where	O
we	O
are	O
tied	O
up	O
--	O
having	O
made	O
about	O
13	O
miles	O
.	O

Cold	O
.	O

Wednesday	O
,	O
Dec.	O
.	O

28th	O
.	O

34-35	O
miles	O
.	O

Started	O
in	O
light	O
wind	O
soon	O
after	O
9	O
--	O
then	O
we	O
tracked	O
and	O
at	O
11	O
a	O
light	O
wind	O
brought	O
us	O
along	O
until	O
7	O
o'clock	O
,	O
when	O
we	O
brought	O
up	O
a	O
mile	O
this	O
side	O
of	O
Abu	PERSON
Girgeh	PERSON
--	O
having	O
made	O
about	O
35	O
miles	O
--	O
still	O
cold	O
--	O
the	O
thermometer	O
went	O
last	O
night	O
down	O
to	O
39	O
˚	O
.	O

Thursday	O
,	O
Dec.	O
.	O

29	O
.	O

31	O
miles	O
.	O

A	O
dense	O
fog	O
this	O
morning	O
and	O
calm	O
--	O
wind	O
rose	O
at	O
11	O
and	O
remained	O
light	O
and	O
fitful	O
all	O
day	O
.	O

We	O
brought	O
up	O
at	O
7:30	O
,	O
5	O
miles	O
north	O
of	O
Minieh	LOCATION
,	O
having	O
made	O
31	O
miles	O
.	O

Friday	O
,	O
Dec.	O
.	O

30	O
.	O

5	O
miles	O
.	O

No	O
wind	O
until	O
after	O
3	O
P.M.	O
when	O
a	O
light	O
one	O
carried	O
us	O
down	O
to	O
Minieh	O
--	O
the	O
Luli	O
el-Nil	O
,	O
coming	O
in	O
half	O
an	O
hour	O
after	O
.	O

Just	O
too	O
late	O
to	O
get	O
the	O
mail	O
--	O
for	O
then	O
we	O
had	O
to	O
wait	O
until	O
8	O
o'clock	O
--	O
many	O
letters	O
but	O
happily	O
no	O
bad	O
news	O
.	O

Heaps	O
of	O
papers	O
bringing	O
us	O
news	O
of	O
the	O
great	O
gale	O
at	O
Newport	LOCATION
and	O
along	O
the	O
coast	O
on	O
the	O
27	O
Nov.	O
also	O
of	O
the	O
sudden	O
death	O
by	O
pneumonia	O
of	O
Mr.	O
Calvin	PERSON
Brice	PERSON
.	O

Page	O
8	O
Saturday	O
,	O
Dec.	O
.	O

31	O
.	O

Still	O
at	O
Minieh	LOCATION
.	O

Have	O
been	O
dining	O
with	O
Lellie	PERSON
Parsons	PERSON
on	O
the	O
Luli	O
el-Nil	O
.	O

Young	O
Gouverneur	PERSON
Morris	PERSON
from	O
New	LOCATION
York	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
a	O
friend	O
of	O
his	O
having	O
come	O
up	O
to	O
spend	O
the	O
night	O
and	O
dine	O
with	O
them	O
.	O

Just	O
before	O
coming	O
away	O
as	O
we	O
were	O
such	O
a	O
party	O
of	O
Americans	O
,	O
we	O
all	O
stood	O
up	O
and	O
sang	O
,	O
``	O
My	O
Country	O
`	O
tis	O
of	O
Thee	O
''	O
.	O

Monday	O
,	O
Jan.	O
.	O

2	O
,	O
1899	O
.	O

5	O
miles	O
.	O

Yesterday	O
a	O
dead	O
calm	O
--	O
or	O
wind	O
in	O
the	O
South	LOCATION
--	O
today	O
the	O
same	O
,	O
but	O
between	O
tracking	O
and	O
polling	O
have	O
made	O
5	O
miles	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
,	O
Jan.	O
.	O

3	O
.	O

8-1/2	O
miles	O
.	O

Calm	O
until	O
early	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
--	O
when	O
we	O
began	O
tracking	O
and	O
sailed	O
a	O
little	O
bringing	O
up	O
at	O
Beni	PERSON
Hassan	PERSON
,	O
or	O
a	O
mile	O
north	O
of	O
it	O
about	O
5	O
o'clock	O
,	O
making	O
8-1/2	O
miles	O
.	O

Saturday	O
,	O
Jan.	O
.	O

7	O
.	O

7	O
miles	O
.	O

A	O
strong	O
,	O
cold	O
,	O
south	O
wind	O
has	O
been	O
blowing	O
since	O
Tuesday	O
--	O
sometimes	O
amounting	O
to	O
a	O
gale	O
--	O
so	O
that	O
sitting	O
on	O
deck	O
,	O
and	O
even	O
walking	O
has	O
been	O
disagreeable	O
--	O
sand	O
flying	O
etc.	O
.	O

We	O
laid	O
all	O
the	O
time	O
just	O
opposite	O
the	O
Beni	PERSON
Hassan	PERSON
hills	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
tombs	O
plainly	O
in	O
sight	O
--	O
and	O
the	O
afternoon	O
sun	O
falling	O
softly	O
upon	O
them	O
made	O
them	O
seem	O
a	O
splendid	O
resting	O
place	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
and	O
Bessie	PERSON
,	O
with	O
the	O
people	O
from	O
the	O
other	O
boat	O
went	O
over	O
yesterday	O
morning	O
--	O
Mary	PERSON
and	O
I	O
would	O
not	O
face	O
the	O
wind	O
and	O
sand	O
.	O

This	O
morning	O
we	O
began	O
tracking	O
about	O
8	O
Page	O
9	O
o'clock	O
and	O
soon	O
the	O
wind	O
shifting	O
to	O
the	O
west	O
,	O
made	O
it	O
possible	O
to	O
sail	O
,	O
as	O
there	O
was	O
a	O
favorable	O
bend	O
in	O
the	O
river	O
--	O
and	O
we	O
made	O
7	O
miles	O
,	O
and	O
are	O
near	O
Rhoda	LOCATION
.	O

Thermometer	O
last	O
night	O
42	O
˚	O
.	O

Sunday	O
,	O
Jan.	O
.	O

8	O
.	O

1st	O
Sunday	O
after	O
Epiphany	O
.	O

We	O
began	O
tracking	O
this	O
morning	O
at	O
7	O
o'clock	O
--	O
thus	O
making	O
a	O
difficult	O
turn	O
,	O
when	O
we	O
were	O
able	O
to	O
sail	O
,	O
and	O
kept	O
on	O
nearly	O
until	O
10	O
o'clock	O
,	O
when	O
the	O
wind	O
became	O
so	O
strong	O
,	O
we	O
had	O
to	O
bring	O
up	O
near	O
the	O
town	O
which	O
lies	O
almost	O
on	O
the	O
site	O
of	O
the	O
old	O
town	O
built	O
by	O
Hadrian	PERSON
in	O
memory	O
of	O
Antinous	O
.	O

A	O
lovely	O
place	O
it	O
was	O
,	O
amidst	O
its	O
lovely	O
palms	O
.	O

I	O
did	O
not	O
walk	O
with	O
the	O
rest	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
few	O
scant	O
ruins	O
of	O
the	O
ancient	O
town	O
--	O
for	O
the	O
wind	O
was	O
so	O
strong	O
and	O
cold	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
dust	O
and	O
sand	O
flying	O
in	O
such	O
blinding	O
fashion	O
.	O

Everything	O
inside	O
and	O
out	O
was	O
covered	O
with	O
it	O
.	O

We	O
got	O
away	O
this	O
afternoon	O
in	O
a	O
fine	O
wind	O
,	O
which	O
brought	O
us	O
to	O
Hadji	PERSON
Kandil	PERSON
about	O
7	O
o'clock	O
,	O
making	O
17	O
miles	O
.	O

Mercury	O
again	O
at	O
42	O
˚	O
last	O
night	O
.	O

Monday	O
,	O
Jan	O
9	O
.	O

28	O
miles	O
.	O

Tracking	O
begun	O
at	O
7	O
o'clock	O
this	O
morning	O
--	O
it	O
being	O
calm	O
and	O
misty	O
.	O

By	O
10	O
o'clock	O
the	O
wind	O
had	O
risen	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
were	O
bowling	O
along	O
in	O
splendid	O
fashion	O
,	O
until	O
we	O
approached	O
the	O
difficult	O
Abu	PERSON
Fêda	PERSON
cliffs	O
--	O
where	O
the	O
great	O
bends	O
in	O
the	O
river	O
make	O
such	O
difficult	O
sailing	O
when	O
the	O
wind	O
became	O
fitful	O
--	O
coming	O
in	O
dangerous	O
gusts	O
--	O
followed	O
by	O
Page	O
10	O
almost	O
dead	O
calms	O
--	O
even	O
drawing	O
ahead	O
.	O

The	O
situation	O
further	O
complicated	O
by	O
many	O
gyasses	O
,	O
made	O
it	O
so	O
exciting	O
,	O
that	O
we	O
feel	O
quite	O
worn	O
out	O
this	O
evening	O
.	O

The	O
Beduin	O
behaved	O
splendidly	O
,	O
and	O
our	O
men	O
were	O
enthusiastic	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
now	O
lying	O
opposite	O
Manfalût	O
,	O
where	O
we	O
hope	O
to	O
get	O
some	O
coal	O
or	O
charcoal	O
,	O
as	O
our	O
fuel	O
is	O
exhausted	O
--	O
and	O
although	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
lot	O
waiting	O
for	O
us	O
at	O
Assiut	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
we	O
are	O
only	O
26	O
miles	O
from	O
there	O
,	O
yet	O
in	O
this	O
uncertain	O
sailing	O
we	O
may	O
not	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
get	O
there	O
tomorrow	O
.	O

The	O
Lulu	O
el-Nil	O
lies	O
just	O
behind	O
us	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
,	O
Jan.	O
.	O

10	O
.	O

26	O
miles	O
.	O

Started	O
at	O
7	O
A.M.	O
and	O
with	O
wind	O
more	O
or	O
less	O
light	O
sailed	O
until	O
after	O
dark	O
--	O
about	O
6	O
we	O
struck	O
the	O
sand	O
,	O
and	O
our	O
men	O
worked	O
hard	O
for	O
an	O
hour	O
before	O
we	O
were	O
off	O
--	O
fairly	O
lifting	O
the	O
boat	O
along	O
.	O

Then	O
we	O
were	O
off	O
,	O
and	O
reached	O
Assiut	LOCATION
at	O
7	O
o'clock	O
P.M.	O
.	O

One	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
beautiful	O
sunsets	O
it	O
was	O
ever	O
vouchsafed	O
to	O
man	O
to	O
see	O
--	O
beginning	O
with	O
a	O
glory	O
that	O
the	O
river	O
everywhere	O
reflected	O
,	O
with	O
masses	O
and	O
great	O
sweeps	O
of	O
light	O
clouds	O
--	O
dying	O
down	O
through	O
every	O
range	O
of	O
colour	O
--	O
and	O
leaving	O
earth	O
and	O
sky	O
in	O
a	O
deep	O
blue	O
and	O
pink	O
darkness	O
!	O

Very	O
cold	O
this	O
morning	O
--	O
thermometer	O
at	O
38	O
˚	O
last	O
night	O
.	O

Wednesday	O
,	O
Jan.	O
.	O

11	O
.	O

Assiut	LOCATION
.	O

22	O
miles	O
.	O

Still	O
very	O
cold	O
this	O
morning	O
though	O
mercury	O
only	O
at	O
42	O
˚	O
-	O
Mary	PERSON
,	O
Bessie	PERSON
and	O
I	O
,	O
taking	O
Abdul	PERSON
,	O
drove	O
into	O
the	O
town	O
as	O
far	O
as	O
the	O
Post	ORGANIZATION
Office	ORGANIZATION
,	O
intending	O
to	O
keep	O
on	O
to	O
the	O
Page	O
11	O
bazaar	O
.	O

But	O
meeting	O
Jones	PERSON
and	O
the	O
Cook	PERSON
entering	O
with	O
all	O
their	O
purchases	O
made	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
wind	O
being	O
favourable	O
,	O
and	O
Theodore	PERSON
who	O
went	O
off	O
early	O
to	O
inspect	O
the	O
new	O
barrage	O
works	O
,	O
having	O
instructed	O
us	O
not	O
to	O
stay	O
long	O
,	O
we	O
obediently	O
turned	O
back	O
at	O
the	O
P.O.	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
a	O
travesty	O
of	O
a	O
carriage	O
,	O
a	O
most	O
curiously	O
compounded	O
harness	O
--	O
and	O
two	O
poor	O
,	O
little	O
,	O
starved	O
horses	O
that	O
made	O
one	O
's	O
heart	O
ache	O
.	O

Came	O
very	O
near	O
an	O
upset	O
--	O
off	O
at	O
11:30	O
,	O
and	O
sailing	O
and	O
tracking	O
we	O
kept	O
on	O
until	O
9	O
this	O
morning	O
,	O
bringing	O
up	O
7	O
miles	O
south	O
of	O
Aboutig	LOCATION
.	O

Sohag	LOCATION
.	O

Thursday	O
,	O
Jan.	O
.	O

12	O
.	O

45	O
miles	O
.	O

A	O
very	O
heavy	O
fog	O
this	O
morning	O
--	O
tracked	O
,	O
and	O
began	O
sailing	O
at	O
1	O
o'clock	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
wind	O
holding	O
we	O
kept	O
on	O
until	O
8	O
o'clock	O
--	O
when	O
we	O
brought	O
up	O
at	O
Sohag	LOCATION
,	O
under	O
its	O
high	O
bank	O
with	O
its	O
fine	O
street	O
and	O
electric	O
lamps	O
.	O

Soon	O
after	O
we	O
pulled	O
up	O
heavy	O
firing	O
began	O
just	O
above	O
us	O
,	O
making	O
us	O
jump	O
in	O
our	O
seats	O
at	O
each	O
discharge	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
the	O
announcement	O
that	O
Ramadan	O
begins	O
tomorrow	O
,	O
the	O
new	O
moon	O
having	O
shown	O
herself	O
last	O
night	O
,	O
I	O
hope	O
she	O
will	O
bring	O
us	O
warmer	O
weather	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
a	O
pleasure	O
to	O
look	O
forward	O
to	O
the	O
lovely	O
nights	O
she	O
brings	O
.	O

The	O
wind	O
has	O
been	O
cold	O
all	O
day	O
--	O
and	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
penetrating	O
cold	O
tonight	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
the	O
little	O
stove	O
lighted	O
and	O
placed	O
in	O
the	O
hall	O
.	O

37	O
˚	O
last	O
night	O
.	O

Early	O
this	O
morning	O
we	O
passed	O
dahabeah	O
``	O
Cairo	LOCATION
''	O
with	O
the	O
English	O
flag	O
,	O
later	O
the	O
Enterpe	O
,	O
also	O
with	O
English	O
flag	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
left	O
the	O
Luli	PERSON
el	PERSON
Nil	PERSON
with	O
our	O
friends	O
behind	O
--	O
they	O
did	O
not	O
get	O
off	O
from	O
Assiut	LOCATION
as	O
early	O
as	O
we	O
did	O
.	O

Page	O
13	O
Friday	O
,	O
Jan.	O
.	O

13	O
.	O

Girgeh	O
.	O

24-1/2	O
miles	O
.	O

A	O
fair	O
sailing	O
day	O
--	O
though	O
obliged	O
to	O
track	O
past	O
Akmim	O
--	O
an	O
awkward	O
thing	O
as	O
its	O
banks	O
are	O
strewn	O
with	O
large	O
stones	O
,	O
and	O
many	O
boats	O
are	O
always	O
lying	O
there	O
.	O

Brought	O
up	O
at	O
Girgeh	LOCATION
at	O
6:30	O
.	O

Cold	O
.	O

Salah	PERSON
not	O
yet	O
in	O
sight	O
.	O

Girgeh	PERSON
has	O
been	O
for	O
years	O
shut	O
off	O
from	O
boats	O
by	O
a	O
huge	O
sand	O
island	O
which	O
the	O
high	O
Nile	O
of	O
this	O
year	O
has	O
completely	O
carried	O
away	O
--	O
so	O
that	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
we	O
could	O
approach	O
the	O
town	O
.	O

Saturday	O
Jan.	O
.	O

14	O
.	O

8	O
miles	O
.	O

Did	O
not	O
reach	O
Balliana	PERSON
until	O
near	O
one	O
o'clock	O
--	O
as	O
the	O
wind	O
was	O
so	O
light	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
,	O
Mary	PERSON
and	O
Bessie	PERSON
with	O
Jones	PERSON
,	O
3	O
of	O
our	O
men	O
and	O
the	O
lunch	O
started	O
at	O
once	O
for	O
Abydos	LOCATION
.	O

Mary	PERSON
in	O
my	O
chair	O
,	O
with	O
2	O
donkeys	O
--	O
she	O
pronounces	O
the	O
new	O
harness	O
a	O
success	O
.	O

They	O
had	O
a	O
beautiful	O
excursion	O
--	O
I	O
with	O
the	O
memory	O
of	O
my	O
last	O
two	O
rides	O
on	O
the	O
bad	O
donkeys	O
for	O
which	O
Abydos	LOCATION
has	O
long	O
been	O
famous	O
,	O
declined	O
to	O
go	O
and	O
had	O
a	O
pleasant	O
busy	O
day	O
at	O
home	O
.	O

An	O
ideal	O
day	O
for	O
such	O
a	O
long	O
ride	O
,	O
cool	O
,	O
cloudy	O
and	O
no	O
wind	O
.	O

We	O
passed	O
a	O
large	O
gyassa	O
lying	O
at	O
Balliana	LOCATION
,	O
which	O
looked	O
as	O
if	O
it	O
must	O
have	O
come	O
straight	O
from	O
The	O
Sudan	LOCATION
,	O
or	O
from	O
the	O
Arabian	O
Nights	O
--	O
loaded	O
with	O
strange	O
interesting	O
looking	O
bales	O
,	O
in	O
mattings	O
,	O
with	O
pretty	O
rugs	O
--	O
and	O
patches	O
of	O
colour	O
--	O
queer	O
looking	O
skins	O
filled	O
with	O
valuables	O
hung	O
about	O
the	O
masts	O
--	O
one	O
red	O
,	O
and	O
one	O
green	O
flag	O
with	O
characters	O
from	O
the	O
Koran	O
--	O
and	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
swarthy	O
fellows	O
in	O
enormous	O
white	O
turbans	O
,	O
and	O
spotless	O
white	O
gowns	O
,	O
sitting	O
and	O
lying	O
about	O
.	O

Page	O
13	O
Salah	PERSON
not	O
yet	O
in	O
sight	O
--	O
we	O
hear	O
they	O
are	O
at	O
Sohag	LOCATION
today	O
.	O

I	O
am	O
so	O
sorry	O
to	O
lose	O
them	O
--	O
but	O
hope	O
we	O
may	O
soon	O
get	O
together	O
again	O
.	O

Sunday	O
--	O
2d	O
after	O
Epiphany	O
.	O

Jan.	O
.	O

15	O
.	O

10	O
miles	O
.	O

Light	O
wind	O
and	O
tracking	O
made	O
10	O
miles	O
above	O
Balliana	LOCATION
weather	O
warmer	O
.	O

Monday	O
,	O
Jan.	O
.	O

16	O
.	O

28	O
miles	O
.	O

Could	O
not	O
start	O
until	O
near	O
noon	O
.	O

When	O
the	O
wind	O
came	O
up	O
we	O
reached	O
Nag	O
Hamade	O
at	O
one	O
o'clock	O
--	O
and	O
waited	O
for	O
the	O
bridge	O
to	O
open	O
.	O

The	O
wind	O
very	O
strong	O
and	O
cool	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
were	O
suffocated	O
with	O
the	O
dust	O
that	O
blew	O
over	O
the	O
high	O
bank	O
above	O
us	O
.	O

At	O
3:30	O
when	O
the	O
bridge	O
opened	O
the	O
wind	O
so	O
strong	O
that	O
I	O
was	O
surprised	O
that	O
Theodore	PERSON
would	O
venture	O
through	O
.	O

Our	O
sailors	O
took	O
the	O
rope	O
on	O
shore	O
and	O
we	O
worked	O
through	O
under	O
a	O
good	O
deal	O
of	O
excitement	O
as	O
the	O
wind	O
carried	O
us	O
against	O
the	O
iron	O
barge	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
was	O
with	O
some	O
scratches	O
and	O
much	O
effort	O
that	O
we	O
got	O
through	O
.	O

A	O
tearing	O
wind	O
for	O
an	O
hour	O
growing	O
somewhat	O
quieter	O
brought	O
us	O
at	O
10:30	O
to	O
Dishneh	LOCATION
.	O

Sunday	O
,	O
Jan.	O
.	O

17	O
.	O

20-1/2	O
miles	O
.	O

Off	O
at	O
7	O
o'clock	O
,	O
reaching	O
Denderah	PERSON
at	O
9:30	O
.	O

Wind	O
high	O
and	O
much	O
dust	O
.	O

The	O
rest	O
went	O
to	O
the	O
temple	O
.	O

I	O
wisely	O
stayed	O
at	O
home	O
--	O
and	O
took	O
my	O
exercise	O
on	O
the	O
clean	O
deck	O
.	O

They	O
were	O
back	O
for	O
one	O
o'clock	O
lunch	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
were	O
off	O
immediately	O
,	O
flying	O
along	O
in	O
the	O
highwind	O
,	O
when	O
we	O
found	O
the	O
chicken	O
boat	O
was	O
full	O
of	O
water	O
,	O
Page	O
14	O
and	O
we	O
made	O
for	O
land	O
,	O
coming	O
in	O
unpleasant	O
contact	O
with	O
the	O
Nitocris	O
.	O

We	O
found	O
3	O
chickens	O
dead	O
,	O
and	O
several	O
of	O
the	O
pigeons	O
.	O

The	O
coops	O
were	O
lifted	O
to	O
shore	O
and	O
opened	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
half	O
drowned	O
survivors	O
came	O
out	O
to	O
dry	O
themselves	O
--	O
but	O
our	O
one	O
precious	O
goose	O
with	O
a	O
cry	O
of	O
joy	O
made	O
for	O
the	O
water	O
,	O
and	O
took	O
a	O
long	O
and	O
enthusiastic	O
bath	O
.	O

After	O
the	O
boat	O
had	O
been	O
cleaned	O
,	O
and	O
fowls	O
put	O
back	O
,	O
we	O
started	O
again	O
--	O
but	O
the	O
river	O
was	O
so	O
dangerous	O
with	O
its	O
sudden	O
turns	O
and	O
gusts	O
of	O
wind	O
we	O
stopped	O
at	O
5	O
o'clock	O
at	O
Kuft	LOCATION
.	O

Wednesday	O
,	O
Jan.	O
.	O

18	O
.	O

28	O
miles	O
.	O

Started	O
at	O
7:30	O
--	O
light	O
wind	O
--	O
tracking	O
,	O
polling	O
,	O
we	O
came	O
to	O
within	O
4	O
or	O
5	O
miles	O
of	O
Luxor	LOCATION
--	O
but	O
can	O
not	O
make	O
the	O
last	O
turn	O
in	O
the	O
river	O
,	O
without	O
wind	O
--	O
so	O
have	O
stopped	O
for	O
the	O
night	O
.	O

Thursday	O
,	O
Jan.	O
.	O

19	O
.	O

Luxor	LOCATION
.	O

4	O
miles	O
.	O

We	O
were	O
until	O
2	O
P.M.	O
making	O
the	O
four	O
miles	O
here	O
,	O
found	O
only	O
one	O
dahabeah	O
here	O
--	O
having	O
passed	O
the	O
Gazelle	LOCATION
early	O
this	O
morning	O
.	O

We	O
came	O
to	O
our	O
usual	O
mooring	O
,	O
our	O
favorite	O
place	O
under	O
the	O
Castle	O
--	O
and	O
soon	O
our	O
friends	O
had	O
found	O
us	O
out	O
.	O

Achmed	PERSON
with	O
his	O
donkey	O
boys	O
--	O
our	O
chicken	O
boy	O
--	O
Sablool	O
--	O
and	O
all	O
--	O
I	O
did	O
not	O
leave	O
the	O
boat	O
,	O
always	O
enjoying	O
the	O
settling	O
for	O
a	O
prolonged	O
stay	O
.	O

The	O
rest	O
went	O
to	O
Karnak	LOCATION
--	O
still	O
cool	O
,	O
even	O
cold	O
.	O

Page	O
15	O
Thursday	O
,	O
Jan.	O
.	O

26	O
.	O

Still	O
at	O
Luxor	LOCATION
.	O

It	O
grows	O
a	O
little	O
warmer	O
.	O

The	O
Lulèe	O
el	O
Nil	O
came	O
in	O
on	O
the	O
21st	O
,	O
and	O
is	O
just	O
behind	O
us	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
done	O
the	O
usual	O
things	O
.	O

Races	O
,	O
visits	O
to	O
ruins	O
etc	O
--	O
I	O
went	O
for	O
the	O
day	O
with	O
all	O
,	O
to	O
the	O
Tombs	O
of	O
the	O
Kings	ORGANIZATION
--	O
a	O
lovely	O
day	O
,	O
and	O
coming	O
home	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
I	O
used	O
the	O
carrying	O
chair	O
which	O
Theodore	PERSON
has	O
had	O
rigged	O
for	O
donkeys	O
--	O
and	O
found	O
it	O
most	O
successful	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Huhatt	PERSON
has	O
been	O
as	O
usual	O
to	O
lunch	O
and	O
to	O
play	O
chess	O
.	O

The	O
Insingers	O
have	O
been	O
to	O
call	O
etc.	O
etc.	O
.	O

Reginald	PERSON
Norman	PERSON
and	O
his	O
brother	O
Max	PERSON
,	O
the	O
Rough	O
Rider	O
whom	O
we	O
left	O
recovering	O
from	O
fever	O
in	O
Newport	LOCATION
,	O
came	O
up	O
in	O
the	O
Rameses	O
the	O
Great	O
to	O
our	O
surprise	O
,	O
and	O
came	O
to	O
dine	O
.	O

Very	O
calm	O
weather	O
.	O

The	O
Lulèe	O
el	O
Nil	O
went	O
off	O
today	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
shall	O
go	O
tomorrow	O
if	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
breath	O
of	O
north	O
wind	O
.	O

The	O
moon	O
is	O
full	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
beauty	O
of	O
the	O
nights	O
is	O
beyond	O
belief	O
and	O
what	O
a	O
view	O
we	O
have	O
of	O
the	O
mountains	O
opposite	O
,	O
their	O
soft	O
yellow	O
tones	O
changing	O
with	O
every	O
hour	O
of	O
the	O
day	O
.	O

I	O
can	O
never	O
weary	O
of	O
this	O
--	O
night	O
or	O
day	O
--	O
each	O
hour	O
has	O
its	O
own	O
charm	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
do	O
not	O
want	O
to	O
leave	O
the	O
boat	O
and	O
lose	O
it	O
.	O

Friday	O
,	O
Jan.	O
.	O

27	O
.	O

34-1/2	O
miles	O
.	O

We	O
got	O
off	O
this	O
morning	O
at	O
12	O
o'clock	O
with	O
a	O
very	O
light	O
wind	O
,	O
which	O
growing	O
stronger	O
brought	O
us	O
at	O
11	O
o'clock	O
to	O
Esneh	LOCATION
.	O

Saturday	O
.	O

Jan.	O
.	O

28	O
.	O

41	O
miles	O
.	O

A	O
fine	O
wind	O
began	O
at	O
7	O
o'clock	O
which	O
has	O
lasted	O
Page	O
16	O
all	O
day	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
have	O
made	O
our	O
best	O
record	O
.	O

A	O
splendid	O
day	O
--	O
every	O
hour	O
delightful	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
about	O
10	O
miles	O
south	O
of	O
Edfu	LOCATION
--	O
passed	O
El	PERSON
Kab	PERSON
this	O
morning	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Somers-Clarke	PERSON
not	O
there	O
--	O
house	O
shut	O
--	O
no	O
dahabeah	O
.	O

Brought	O
up	O
at	O
2:30	O
at	O
Edfu	LOCATION
where	O
we	O
found	O
the	O
Lulèe	PERSON
el	O
Nil	O
.	O

The	O
rest	O
went	O
off	O
to	O
the	O
Temple	O
.	O

The	O
natives	O
here	O
very	O
noisy	O
and	O
unmanageable	O
.	O

We	O
got	O
away	O
sometime	O
after	O
the	O
Lulie	PERSON
el	O
Nil	O
,	O
but	O
passed	O
her	O
in	O
the	O
evening	O
and	O
are	O
now	O
tied	O
up	O
near	O
each	O
other	O
.	O

A	O
splendid	O
night	O
--	O
the	O
sight	O
of	O
the	O
full	O
moon	O
sailing	O
up	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
horizon	O
was	O
wonderful	O
.	O

Septuagesima	O
Sunday	O
.	O

Jan.	O
.	O

29	O
.	O

31	O
miles	O
.	O

Kom	PERSON
Ombo	PERSON
.	O

Started	O
at	O
7	O
--	O
in	O
good	O
wind	O
,	O
reached	O
Silsilis	LOCATION
at	O
noon	O
--	O
and	O
visited	O
the	O
quarries	O
.	O

The	O
other	O
boat	O
came	O
up	O
and	O
joined	O
us	O
--	O
and	O
we	O
both	O
succeeded	O
in	O
reaching	O
Kom	ORGANIZATION
Ombo	ORGANIZATION
about	O
6	O
P.M.	ORGANIZATION
Mary	ORGANIZATION
has	O
gone	O
up	O
with	O
the	O
girls	O
from	O
the	O
other	O
boat	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
Temple	O
by	O
this	O
pleasant	O
soft	O
moonlight	O
.	O

Aswân	O
.	O

Jan.	O
.	O

30	O
.	O

Monday	O
.	O

26	O
miles	O
.	O

Went	O
up	O
to	O
the	O
Temple	O
after	O
breakfast	O
and	O
were	O
off	O
at	O
10:30	O
,	O
sailing	O
splendidly	O
into	O
Asswan	PERSON
at	O
5	O
o'clock	O
.	O

The	O
Lulie	O
el	O
Nil	O
not	O
far	O
behind	O
us	O
.	O

Found	O
the	O
Istar	ORGANIZATION
,	O
Hathor	PERSON
,	O
Cairo	LOCATION
,	O
Ammon	PERSON
Ra	PERSON
,	O
Nephthis	LOCATION
,	O
Oonas	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
Isis	ORGANIZATION
here	O
--	O
with	O
Cheops	LOCATION
and	O
Horus	O
.	O

Difficult	O
to	O
find	O
a	O
place	O
.	O

Page	O
17	O
Aswân	O
--	O
Feb.	O
.	O

5th	O
.	O

Sunday	O
.	O

We	O
start	O
tomorrow	O
for	O
Wady	PERSON
Halfa	PERSON
,	O
with	O
Mrs.	O
Parsons	PERSON
and	O
the	O
girls	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
really	O
sorry	O
to	O
leave	O
Prof.	O
Sayce	PERSON
,	O
behind	O
whose	O
boat	O
we	O
are	O
lying	O
.	O

He	O
is	O
suffering	O
from	O
a	O
bad	O
case	O
of	O
blood	O
poisoning	O
--	O
with	O
a	O
bad	O
carbuncle	O
on	O
his	O
neck	O
just	O
mending	O
,	O
and	O
a	O
very	O
bad	O
finger	O
with	O
an	O
inflamed	O
arm	O
--	O
and	O
being	O
quite	O
alone	O
on	O
his	O
boat	O
,	O
his	O
situation	O
has	O
seemed	O
so	O
triste	O
,	O
that	O
we	O
have	O
been	O
having	O
him	O
with	O
us	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
time	O
.	O

He	O
has	O
dined	O
with	O
us	O
almost	O
every	O
night	O
,	O
in	O
spite	O
of	O
his	O
protests	O
about	O
his	O
bandaged	O
appearance	O
.	O

He	O
gives	O
us	O
all	O
the	O
news	O
we	O
have	O
had	O
as	O
to	O
work	O
along	O
the	O
river	O
.	O

The	O
Marquis	PERSON
of	O
Northampton	LOCATION
on	O
his	O
dahabeah	O
Mâat	O
has	O
gone	O
down	O
earlier	O
than	O
usual	O
,	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
put	O
Lady	O
Northampton	LOCATION
under	O
the	O
care	O
of	O
a	O
Paris	LOCATION
doctor	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
feared	O
that	O
the	O
nervous	O
disorder	O
of	O
which	O
she	O
has	O
been	O
the	O
unhappy	O
victim	O
,	O
is	O
the	O
forerunner	O
of	O
creeping	O
paralysis	O
.	O

The	O
Marquess	O
is	O
bearing	O
all	O
the	O
expense	O
of	O
the	O
excavations	O
Newberry	PERSON
is	O
making	O
at	O
Thebes	LOCATION
--	O
and	O
they	O
have	O
found	O
a	O
rich	O
and	O
interesting	O
tomb	O
of	O
one	O
Tahuti	PERSON
,	O
``	O
the	O
beloved	O
friend	O
of	O
Queen	O
Hatshepsowet	O
''	O
,	O
and	O
are	O
on	O
the	O
track	O
of	O
another	O
tomb	O
--	O
all	O
the	O
finds	O
go	O
to	O
the	O
Ghizeh	ORGANIZATION
Museum	ORGANIZATION
--	O
which	O
is	O
very	O
generous	O
on	O
the	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
M.	O
of	O
N.	PERSON
Flinders-Petrie	PERSON
is	O
excavating	O
near	O
Hou	O
--	O
and	O
Quibell	LOCATION
and	O
Somers-Clarke	O
are	O
still	O
at	O
work	O
at	O
Kom	LOCATION
el	LOCATION
Akmar	LOCATION
opposite	O
El	LOCATION
Kab	LOCATION
.	O

The	O
latter	O
has	O
taken	O
his	O
boat	O
up	O
above	O
the	O
Cataract	O
,	O
but	O
is	O
expected	O
down	O
this	O
month	O
.	O

The	O
weather	O
has	O
been	O
comfortably	O
warm	O
here	O
--	O
we	O
have	O
spent	O
one	O
day	O
at	O
Philae	O
--	O
found	O
the	O
Newmans	O
there	O
,	O
and	O
went	O
down	O
to	O
their	O
boat	O
after	O
lunch	O
.	O

Yemma	PERSON
was	O
there	O
clean	O
and	O
well	O
grown	O
--	O
but	O
very	O
thin	O
,	O
having	O
just	O
recovered	O
from	O
pneumonia	O
.	O

Came	O
home	O
in	O
one	O
of	O
Page	O
18	O
the	O
cataract	O
boats	O
--	O
quite	O
exciting	O
,	O
as	O
the	O
river	O
is	O
so	O
full	O
.	O

Thousands	O
of	O
workmen	O
are	O
now	O
employed	O
on	O
the	O
weir	O
at	O
Assouan	LOCATION
.	O

I	O
went	O
across	O
the	O
desert	O
to	O
Philae	O
in	O
the	O
donkey	O
chair	O
--	O
and	O
great	O
numbers	O
of	O
masses	O
of	O
quarried	O
stone	O
are	O
lying	O
in	O
orderly	O
array	O
along	O
the	O
route	O
--	O
and	O
blasting	O
going	O
on	O
in	O
various	O
places	O
,	O
and	O
red	O
flags	O
fluttering	O
here	O
and	O
there	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
beautiful	O
red	O
brown	O
tint	O
of	O
the	O
rocks	O
bringing	O
the	O
bare	O
white	O
surfaces	O
of	O
the	O
lately	O
quarried	O
rocks	O
into	O
glaring	O
and	O
painful	O
contrast	O
,	O
and	O
more	O
painful	O
still	O
were	O
the	O
transformed	O
shores	O
of	O
the	O
river	O
along	O
the	O
cataract	O
.	O

Their	O
beautiful	O
isolation	O
,	O
and	O
quiet	O
loveliness	O
,	O
now	O
broken	O
with	O
the	O
sounds	O
of	O
blasting	O
--	O
the	O
raw	O
surfaces	O
of	O
the	O
newly	O
cut	O
rocks	O
--	O
the	O
almost	O
continuous	O
buildings	O
of	O
the	O
agents	O
and	O
employees	O
,	O
hospitals	O
,	O
storehouses	O
etc.	O
,	O
steam	O
launches	O
rushing	O
about	O
--	O
and	O
the	O
barbaric	O
quiet	O
of	O
the	O
river	O
gone	O
for	O
ever	O
!	O

It	O
is	O
a	O
pity	O
!	O

Mr.	O
Sayce	PERSON
came	O
to	O
tea	O
and	O
sat	O
until	O
after	O
dark	O
--	O
looking	O
very	O
miserable	O
indeed	O
.	O

Monday	O
,	O
Feb.	O
.	O

6th	O
.	O

S.S.	PERSON
Tewfik	PERSON
.	O

We	O
had	O
an	O
early	O
breakfast	O
and	O
were	O
across	O
the	O
river	O
and	O
off	O
in	O
time	O
for	O
the	O
train	O
at	O
9	O
o'clock	O
.	O

Our	O
cook	O
came	O
with	O
us	O
,	O
as	O
he	O
wanted	O
to	O
see	O
his	O
old	O
friends	O
,	O
having	O
been	O
employed	O
on	O
this	O
boat	O
for	O
two	O
years	O
.	O

He	O
took	O
great	O
pains	O
to	O
confide	O
as	O
to	O
the	O
attention	O
of	O
all	O
the	O
servants	O
.	O

We	O
find	O
our	O
former	O
cook	O
boy	O
Tommy	PERSON
among	O
the	O
crew	O
.	O

We	O
were	O
off	O
at	O
11	O
o'clock	O
--	O
and	O
are	O
delighted	O
with	O
this	O
very	O
comfortable	O
,	O
clean	O
boat	O
.	O

There	O
are	O
not	O
many	O
passengers	O
,	O
our	O
rooms	O
,	O
the	O
table	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
service	O
,	O
Page	O
19	O
are	O
excellent	O
.	O

We	O
passed	O
Dabâd	LOCATION
where	O
is	O
a	O
temple	O
of	O
an	O
Ethiopian	O
monarch	O
,	O
a	O
contemporary	O
of	O
Ptolemy	O
IV	O
but	O
did	O
not	O
stop	O
--	O
then	O
Cartassi	PERSON
where	O
are	O
a	O
ruined	O
temple	O
and	O
quarries	O
--	O
then	O
Wady	PERSON
Tafa	PERSON
also	O
with	O
temple	O
ruins	O
,	O
then	O
Kalâbsha	LOCATION
with	O
its	O
temple	O
built	O
in	O
the	O
reign	O
of	O
Augustus	O
on	O
an	O
older	O
foundation	O
as	O
stones	O
with	O
the	O
names	O
of	O
Amenhotep	O
II	O
and	O
Thothmes	O
III	O
have	O
been	O
found	O
there	O
.	O

We	O
saw	O
this	O
on	O
our	O
former	O
journey	O
up	O
here	O
,	O
and	O
were	O
little	O
interested	O
in	O
it	O
.	O

Passed	O
also	O
Kêt	O
el-Wali	O
,	O
with	O
temple	O
ruins	O
of	O
Ramses	O
II	O
--	O
arriving	O
at	O
Dendur	O
about	O
7	O
o'clock	O
P.M.	O
which	O
was	O
our	O
first	O
stop	O
,	O
and	O
where	O
we	O
spent	O
the	O
night	O
--	O
I	O
did	O
not	O
go	O
up	O
with	O
the	O
rest	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
temple	O
.	O

Made	O
52-1/2	O
miles	O
.	O

Feb.	O
.	O

7	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
.	O

Started	O
at	O
5	O
o'clock	O
--	O
and	O
made	O
Dakka	PERSON
,	O
where	O
we	O
stopped	O
to	O
see	O
a	O
temple	O
of	O
Aeg-Amen	O
,	O
an	O
Ethiopian	O
king	O
,	O
built	O
on	O
foundation	O
of	O
Amenemhat	O
I.	O
I	O
did	O
not	O
go	O
to	O
see	O
it	O
.	O

Then	O
we	O
stopped	O
at	O
Wady	O
es-Sabû	O
à	O
,	O
where	O
is	O
a	O
temple	O
of	O
Ramses	O
II	O
,	O
lying	O
almost	O
buried	O
in	O
yellow	O
sand	O
--	O
which	O
was	O
not	O
inviting	O
in	O
the	O
hot	O
noon	O
time	O
.	O

Reached	O
Korosko	O
,	O
the	O
large	O
and	O
important	O
town	O
at	O
7:30	O
where	O
we	O
spent	O
the	O
night	O
,	O
making	O
69	O
miles	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
impressed	O
with	O
this	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
Nile	O
--	O
so	O
different	O
in	O
its	O
features	O
from	O
the	O
lower	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
river	O
.	O

The	O
villages	O
,	O
desolate	O
but	O
clean	O
looking	O
--	O
the	O
houses	O
so	O
well	O
and	O
squarely	O
built	O
--	O
large	O
with	O
their	O
domed	O
roofs	O
and	O
many	O
window	O
openings	O
,	O
looking	O
almost	O
attractive	O
.	O

The	O
people	O
look	O
cleaner	O
--	O
but	O
there	O
are	O
so	O
few	O
of	O
them	O
--	O
and	O
what	O
can	O
they	O
in	O
this	O
desert	O
country	O
live	O
on	O
!	O

Page	O
20	O
Wednesday	O
,	O
Feb.	O
.	O

8	O
.	O

This	O
morning	O
half	O
of	O
the	O
passengers	O
were	O
called	O
at	O
5	O
o'clock	O
,	O
to	O
make	O
the	O
ascent	O
of	O
the	O
mountain	O
at	O
Korosko	LOCATION
--	O
and	O
see	O
the	O
sun	O
rise	O
--	O
naturally	O
the	O
other	O
half	O
found	O
their	O
slumbers	O
much	O
interrupted	O
by	O
the	O
departure	O
and	O
arrival	O
of	O
the	O
others	O
.	O

Before	O
the	O
Sudan	LOCATION
trade	O
was	O
interfered	O
with	O
by	O
the	O
war	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
this	O
was	O
the	O
point	O
of	O
departure	O
for	O
Abu	PERSON
Hamed	PERSON
--	O
and	O
when	O
we	O
were	O
here	O
7	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
there	O
was	O
a	O
large	O
and	O
important	O
garrison	O
here	O
,	O
which	O
does	O
not	O
exist	O
now	O
.	O

Stopped	O
at	O
Amada	ORGANIZATION
about	O
noon	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
got	O
out	O
with	O
the	O
rest	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
temple	O
founded	O
by	O
Usertesen	PERSON
III	PERSON
and	O
added	O
to	O
and	O
restored	O
from	O
time	O
to	O
time	O
by	O
Thotmes	O
III	O
Amenhetep	O
II	O
,	O
Thotmes	O
IV	O
and	O
Seti	O
I	O
--	O
whose	O
cartouches	O
we	O
found	O
.	O

It	O
needs	O
excavating	O
,	O
as	O
the	O
sand	O
has	O
almost	O
covered	O
and	O
filled	O
it	O
.	O

Fine	O
dôm	O
palms	O
are	O
showing	O
themselves	O
in	O
profusion	O
--	O
and	O
the	O
splendid	O
drifts	O
of	O
yellow	O
,	O
yellow	O
sand	O
--	O
what	O
Miss	O
Edwards	PERSON
happily	O
describes	O
as	O
``	O
snow	O
drifts	O
turned	O
to	O
gold	O
''	O
.	O

Between	O
Amada	PERSON
and	O
Derr	PERSON
,	O
the	O
country	O
is	O
rich	O
with	O
splendid	O
palms	O
--	O
the	O
best	O
dates	O
come	O
from	O
here	O
.	O

Kasr	PERSON
Ibrîm	PERSON
we	O
passed	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
with	O
its	O
Roman	O
ruins	O
on	O
the	O
cliffs	O
,	O
and	O
rock	O
tombs	O
beneath	O
--	O
and	O
we	O
brought	O
up	O
at	O
8	O
o'clock	O
at	O
Abu	LOCATION
Simbel	LOCATION
where	O
we	O
are	O
now	O
lying	O
--	O
the	O
rest	O
went	O
with	O
their	O
lanterns	O
up	O
to	O
see	O
it	O
--	O
but	O
as	O
we	O
stop	O
on	O
our	O
way	O
down	O
,	O
Lellie	PERSON
Parsons	PERSON
and	O
I	O
stayed	O
home	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
a	O
little	O
sensation	O
yesterday	O
late	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
when	O
we	O
came	O
to	O
where	O
the	O
little	O
steamer	O
``	O
Edfu	O
''	O
,	O
of	O
the	O
Khedivial	LOCATION
line	O
had	O
been	O
sticking	O
in	O
the	O
sand	O
for	O
21	O
days	O
.	O

A	O
large	O
force	O
of	O
men	O
were	O
at	O
work	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
stopped	O
to	O
give	O
them	O
a	O
pull	O
--	O
but	O
in	O
vain	O
--	O
and	O
after	O
breaking	O
our	O
cable	O
twice	O
,	O
we	O
left	O
her	O
.	O

68-1/2	O
miles	O
.	O

Page	O
21	O
Thursday	O
,	O
Feb.	O
.	O

9	O
.	O

Wady	PERSON
Halfa	PERSON
.	O

Left	O
Abu	PERSON
Simbel	PERSON
early	O
this	O
morning	O
--	O
I	O
was	O
awakened	O
at	O
3	O
A.M.	O
by	O
the	O
different	O
people	O
being	O
aroused	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
Southern	ORGANIZATION
Cross	ORGANIZATION
--	O
and	O
again	O
by	O
our	O
early	O
start	O
.	O

We	O
reached	O
Halfa	PERSON
at	O
11	O
o'clock	O
,	O
passing	O
dahabeah	O
``	O
Thames	O
''	O
on	O
her	O
way	O
down	O
.	O

The	O
country	O
in	O
spite	O
of	O
its	O
desert	O
air	O
,	O
is	O
interesting	O
--	O
and	O
even	O
beautiful	O
,	O
with	O
its	O
strange	O
mountain	O
peaks	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
evidences	O
everywhere	O
of	O
proplonged	O
water	O
action	O
--	O
and	O
everything	O
partly	O
submerged	O
in	O
yellow	O
,	O
pink	O
sand	O
drifts	O
--	O
no	O
birds	O
to	O
be	O
seen	O
--	O
many	O
fine	O
dome	O
like	O
sycamores	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
finest	O
tamarasks	O
I	O
have	O
ever	O
seen	O
--	O
the	O
foliage	O
so	O
thick	O
and	O
brightly	O
green	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
made	O
40	O
miles	O
.	O

We	O
drew	O
up	O
to	O
what	O
is	O
an	O
entirely	O
new	O
quarter	O
of	O
Halfa	O
,	O
called	O
Tewfikyia	O
--	O
good	O
European	O
houses	O
,	O
new	O
and	O
clean	O
--	O
a	O
fine	O
modern	O
mosque	O
,	O
bazaar	O
,	O
Greek	O
shops	O
,	O
etc.	O
.	O

All	O
our	O
people	O
chose	O
to	O
go	O
to	O
the	O
2d	O
cataract	O
this	O
afternoon	O
,	O
instead	O
of	O
waiting	O
for	O
the	O
regular	O
excursion	O
in	O
the	O
morning	O
.	O

The	O
wind	O
was	O
strong	O
and	O
cold	O
,	O
and	O
sand	O
flying	O
in	O
clouds	O
.	O

They	O
took	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
large	O
sail	O
boats	O
,	O
and	O
with	O
the	O
Reis	PERSON
of	O
the	O
steamer	O
and	O
several	O
of	O
the	O
sailors	O
started	O
,	O
not	O
returning	O
until	O
we	O
had	O
nearly	O
finished	O
dinner	O
.	O

They	O
reported	O
that	O
they	O
were	O
not	O
only	O
able	O
to	O
sail	O
up	O
to	O
the	O
rock	O
of	O
Abusir	LOCATION
,	O
but	O
3	O
miles	O
beyond	O
.	O

I	O
spent	O
a	O
quiet	O
,	O
nice	O
afternoon	O
with	O
Mrs.	O
Parsons	PERSON
--	O
the	O
whole	O
boat	O
enveloped	O
in	O
canvass	O
,	O
to	O
protect	O
us	O
from	O
the	O
wind	O
and	O
sand	O
.	O

However	O
the	O
little	O
open	O
space	O
in	O
the	O
center	O
of	O
the	O
steamer	O
,	O
which	O
really	O
serves	O
us	O
as	O
drawing	O
room	O
,	O
was	O
very	O
comfortable	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
where	O
afternoon	O
tea	O
is	O
served	O
,	O
and	O
coffee	O
.	O

This	O
evening	O
we	O
took	O
refuge	O
in	O
the	O
dining	O
saloon	O
Page	O
22	O
as	O
it	O
was	O
so	O
cold	O
.	O

The	O
doctor	O
of	O
the	O
Fort	LOCATION
was	O
on	O
board	O
,	O
and	O
was	O
presented	O
to	O
us	O
--	O
and	O
has	O
invited	O
us	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
fort	O
tomorrow	O
.	O

Friday	O
,	O
Feb.	O
.	O

10	O
.	O

Abu	PERSON
Simbel	PERSON
.	O

Immediately	O
after	O
breakfast	O
we	O
mounted	O
donkeys	O
and	O
started	O
for	O
Salah	PERSON
's	O
house	O
,	O
stopping	O
en	O
route	O
at	O
the	O
Fort	LOCATION
,	O
two	O
miles	O
from	O
Tewfikyia	LOCATION
.	O

It	O
is	O
very	O
large	O
--	O
indeed	O
is	O
Halfa	O
--	O
with	O
its	O
railway	O
--	O
machine	O
shops	O
--	O
hospitals	O
--	O
prisons	O
,	O
officers	O
'	O
quarters	O
and	O
barracks	O
--	O
we	O
saw	O
the	O
hospital	O
,	O
and	O
a	O
company	O
of	O
conscripts	O
just	O
arrived	O
--	O
and	O
dervishes	O
working	O
in	O
chains	O
.	O

They	O
were	O
not	O
permitted	O
to	O
show	O
``	O
Mamoud	O
''	O
whom	O
we	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
have	O
seen	O
--	O
saw	O
an	O
interesting	O
collection	O
of	O
dervish	O
arms	O
etc.	O
.	O

--	O
at	O
the	O
doctor	O
's	O
quarters	O
--	O
and	O
a	O
lovely	O
little	O
gazelle	O
wandering	O
about	O
among	O
the	O
palms	O
of	O
the	O
little	O
enclosure	O
.	O

A	O
very	O
dusty	O
ride	O
of	O
2	O
miles	O
or	O
more	O
to	O
Salah	PERSON
's	O
house	O
--	O
which	O
we	O
found	O
greatly	O
improved	O
since	O
our	O
last	O
visit	O
.	O

We	O
were	O
shown	O
into	O
a	O
large	O
room	O
well	O
lighted	O
with	O
good	O
windows	O
--	O
nice	O
rugs	O
on	O
the	O
floor	O
,	O
and	O
divan	O
--	O
and	O
tea	O
waiting	O
for	O
us	O
--	O
with	O
good	O
china	O
etc.	O
.	O

The	O
old	O
mother	O
,	O
supposed	O
to	O
be	O
over	O
90	O
,	O
and	O
quite	O
blind	O
,	O
was	O
led	O
in	O
by	O
Salah	PERSON
--	O
and	O
then	O
he	O
brought	O
his	O
pretty	O
wife	O
Tamai	PERSON
,	O
with	O
a	O
clean	O
and	O
very	O
pretty	O
baby	O
in	O
her	O
arms	O
,	O
who	O
was	O
frightened	O
into	O
tears	O
at	O
the	O
sight	O
of	O
such	O
fearsome	O
white	O
beings	O
as	O
we	O
were	O
.	O

Tamai	PERSON
has	O
grown	O
a	O
trifle	O
stouter	O
since	O
I	O
saw	O
her	O
7	O
years	O
ago	O
--	O
was	O
well	O
,	O
even	O
richly	O
dressed	O
.	O

She	O
evidently	O
hated	O
to	O
have	O
us	O
look	O
at	O
her	O
baby	O
.	O

Home	O
by	O
one	O
o'clock	O
,	O
and	O
off	O
immediately	O
for	O
Abu	PERSON
Simbel	PERSON
,	O
reaching	O
here	O
at	O
4:30	O
.	O

We	O
went	O
to	O
the	O
temples	O
at	O
once	O
.	O

``	O
Thames	O
''	O
lying	O
Page	O
23	O
here	O
--	O
and	O
post	O
boat	O
stopped	O
to	O
allow	O
her	O
few	O
passengers	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
temples	O
.	O

An	O
elderly	O
man	O
was	O
pointed	O
out	O
to	O
me	O
as	O
the	O
Earl	O
of	O
Carlisle	PERSON
who	O
had	O
been	O
to	O
Khartoum	LOCATION
to	O
see	O
the	O
grave	O
of	O
his	O
son	O
,	O
Mr.	O
Howard	PERSON
who	O
met	O
his	O
death	O
,	O
after	O
the	O
battle	O
in	O
the	O
streets	O
of	O
Omdurmân	LOCATION
.	O

Saturday	O
,	O
Feb.	O
.	O

11	O
.	O

Got	O
up	O
at	O
6	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
dawn	O
on	O
the	O
faces	O
of	O
the	O
splendid	O
colossi	O
--	O
went	O
again	O
to	O
the	O
great	O
temple	O
after	O
breakfast	O
--	O
started	O
at	O
10	O
o'clock	O
--	O
wind	O
high	O
and	O
cold	O
--	O
stopped	O
at	O
Derr	PERSON
,	O
about	O
2	O
o'clock	O
--	O
did	O
not	O
get	O
off	O
--	O
a	O
crowd	O
of	O
the	O
noisiest	O
natives	O
I	O
ever	O
saw	O
,	O
besieged	O
the	O
boat	O
and	O
made	O
a	O
hideous	O
din	O
--	O
passed	O
Korosko	PERSON
at	O
5:30	O
--	O
and	O
are	O
still	O
steaming	O
down	O
the	O
river	O
,	O
and	O
will	O
not	O
stop	O
until	O
we	O
reach	O
Marakya	PERSON
.	O

In	O
getting	O
away	O
from	O
Derr	PERSON
we	O
broke	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
paddle	O
blades	O
,	O
and	O
had	O
to	O
stop	O
to	O
repair	O
it	O
.	O

Sunday	O
evening	O
--	O
Feb.	O
.	O

12	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
a	O
pleasant	O
thought	O
on	O
waking	O
this	O
morning	O
to	O
know	O
that	O
we	O
would	O
reach	O
home	O
this	O
afternoon	O
.	O

We	O
stopped	O
for	O
an	O
hour	O
at	O
Kalabshi	LOCATION
I	O
did	O
not	O
go	O
to	O
the	O
temple	O
,	O
which	O
I	O
had	O
seen	O
before	O
,	O
and	O
which	O
is	O
only	O
interesting	O
from	O
its	O
inscriptions	O
which	O
of	O
course	O
we	O
could	O
not	O
read	O
.	O

The	O
most	O
typical	O
and	O
barbaric	O
crowd	O
about	O
the	O
boat	O
,	O
offering	O
Dervish	O
arms	O
,	O
dresses	O
etc.	O
for	O
sale	O
.	O

Many	O
of	O
these	O
people	O
had	O
served	O
as	O
officers	O
servants	O
during	O
the	O
late	O
campaign	O
,	O
and	O
of	O
course	O
had	O
possessed	O
themselves	O
of	O
many	O
trophies	O
--	O
which	O
they	O
held	O
at	O
enormous	O
prices	O
.	O

I	O
saw	O
one	O
naked	O
black	O
boy	O
,	O
clothed	O
in	O
a	O
Seaforth	LOCATION
Highlander	O
waistcoat	O
!	O

and	O
another	O
Page	O
24	O
black	O
fellow	O
with	O
enormous	O
white	O
turban	O
,	O
and	O
bristling	O
with	O
arms	O
,	O
smoking	O
a	O
pipe	O
!	O

After	O
we	O
got	O
away	O
from	O
Kalabshi	LOCATION
,	O
had	O
a	O
nice	O
little	O
service	O
,	O
our	O
pleasant	O
little	O
vicar	O
-LRB-	O
Brockenbury	LOCATION
-RRB-	O
officiating	O
--	O
passed	O
Somers-Clarke	O
boat	O
at	O
Dabbôd	O
--	O
reached	O
Shellal	O
at	O
2	O
o'clock	O
,	O
and	O
found	O
it	O
entirely	O
en	O
fête	O
,	O
the	O
Duke	ORGANIZATION
and	O
Duchess	O
of	O
Connaught	O
having	O
arrived	O
en	O
route	O
for	O
Khartoum	LOCATION
.	O

Flags	O
,	O
pennants	O
,	O
everywhere	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
royal	O
standard	O
floating	O
over	O
the	O
little	O
steamer	O
on	O
which	O
they	O
were	O
.	O

We	O
were	O
soon	O
in	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
Cataract	O
boats	O
,	O
making	O
the	O
descent	O
,	O
and	O
at	O
5	O
o'clock	O
were	O
once	O
more	O
on	O
this	O
blessed	O
Beduin	O
--	O
a	O
band	O
of	O
happy	O
pilgrims	O
,	O
home	O
from	O
their	O
wanderings	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
and	O
Bess	PERSON
crossed	O
the	O
river	O
to	O
Asswan	LOCATION
,	O
stopping	O
at	O
the	O
Istar	ORGANIZATION
on	O
their	O
way	O
home	O
,	O
reporting	O
Mr.	O
Sayce	PERSON
better	O
.	O

Monday	O
,	O
Feb.	O
.	O

13	O
.	O

Such	O
a	O
pleasant	O
quiet	O
day	O
at	O
home	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Sayce	PERSON
came	O
to	O
tea	O
and	O
afterwards	O
to	O
dinner	O
--	O
looking	O
rather	O
better	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Somers-Clarke	PERSON
came	O
for	O
a	O
call	O
this	O
morning	O
,	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Parson	PERSON
and	O
the	O
girls	O
,	O
the	O
vicar	O
and	O
his	O
friend	O
came	O
down	O
in	O
a	O
cataract	O
boat	O
,	O
and	O
made	O
us	O
a	O
farewell	O
visit	O
--	O
as	O
they	O
went	O
off	O
on	O
the	O
Post	ORGANIZATION
boat	O
at	O
noon	O
--	O
expecting	O
to	O
pick	O
up	O
their	O
dahabeah	O
between	O
this	O
and	O
Esneh	O
.	O

The	O
Craiks	O
,	O
the	O
vicar	O
and	O
Mr.	O
Brotherton	PERSON
came	O
to	O
tea	O
also	O
,	O
and	O
everybody	O
stayed	O
later	O
than	O
everybody	O
else	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Somers-Clarke	PERSON
left	O
his	O
boat	O
at	O
Philae	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
rode	O
over	O
--	O
not	O
expecting	O
to	O
come	O
down	O
for	O
a	O
few	O
days	O
.	O

He	O
says	O
he	O
found	O
the	O
upper	O
Nile	O
enchanting	O
in	O
a	O
dahabeah	O
.	O

He	O
stopped	O
at	O
60	O
places	O
--	O
and	O
has	O
made	O
plans	O
and	O
drawings	O
of	O
20	O
.	O

Happy	O
occupation	O
!	O

We	O
are	O
trying	O
to	O
persuade	O
Theodore	PERSON
to	O
wait	O
until	O
Saturday	O
,	O
and	O
start	O
down	O
in	O
the	O
company	O
of	O
the	O
Page	O
25	O
Istar	ORGANIZATION
and	O
Althar	O
--	O
but	O
in	O
vain	O
.	O

I	O
am	O
always	O
struggling	O
to	O
get	O
amongst	O
these	O
Egyptologists	O
for	O
the	O
interesting	O
things	O
they	O
can	O
give	O
--	O
but	O
it	O
is	O
generally	O
in	O
vain	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
,	O
Feb.	O
.	O

14	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
ready	O
to	O
start	O
tomorrow	O
,	O
having	O
found	O
Theodore	PERSON
obstinate	O
--	O
Mary	PERSON
and	O
I	O
went	O
to	O
tea	O
this	O
afternoon	O
on	O
the	O
Istar	ORGANIZATION
,	O
and	O
then	O
took	O
a	O
last	O
,	O
little	O
row	O
in	O
the	O
charming	O
river	O
among	O
the	O
rocks	O
.	O

Met	O
on	O
the	O
Istar	ORGANIZATION
,	O
Mr.	O
Buxton	PERSON
of	O
dahabeah	O
Nephthys	O
--	O
and	O
Lord	O
and	O
Lady	PERSON
Bellhaven	PERSON
staying	O
at	O
the	O
hotel	O
--	O
Mr.	O
Sayce	PERSON
came	O
to	O
dinner	O
.	O

Wednesday	O
,	O
Feb.	O
.	O

15	O
.	O

Started	O
this	O
morning	O
at	O
9	O
and	O
have	O
made	O
15	O
miles	O
.	O

Thursday	O
,	O
Feb.	O
.	O

16	O
.	O

Got	O
off	O
at	O
6	O
o'clock	O
and	O
have	O
made	O
about	O
13	O
miles	O
--	O
strong	O
north	O
wind	O
--	O
passed	O
the	O
Chonsu	LOCATION
,	O
which	O
lay	O
just	O
behind	O
us	O
at	O
Elephantine	O
at	O
Kom	LOCATION
Ombo	LOCATION
.	O

Though	O
small	O
,	O
she	O
is	O
a	O
heavy	O
,	O
wooden	O
boat	O
,	O
and	O
outfloats	O
us	O
entirely	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
pulled	O
up	O
to	O
a	O
low	O
sand	O
bank	O
in	O
the	O
river	O
,	O
and	O
lying	O
quite	O
out	O
in	O
the	O
water	O
--	O
without	O
a	O
visible	O
human	O
being	O
near	O
us	O
.	O

I	O
would	O
always	O
like	O
to	O
lie	O
in	O
such	O
a	O
spot	O
--	O
it	O
is	O
an	O
ideal	O
place	O
to	O
stop	O
at	O
--	O
the	O
river	O
itself	O
so	O
wide	O
here	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
desert	O
on	O
each	O
side	O
wider	O
still	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
about	O
two	O
miles	O
from	O
Silsilis	O
--	O
I	O
stayed	O
on	O
deck	O
until	O
10	O
minutes	O
of	O
dinner	O
time	O
,	O
and	O
went	O
up	O
again	O
after	O
dinner	O
.	O

The	O
moon	O
is	O
still	O
in	O
her	O
first	O
quarter	O
--	O
and	O
the	O
stars	O
so	O
radiant	O
--	O
such	O
beautiful	O
Page	O
26	O
loneliness	O
--	O
one	O
could	O
almost	O
touch	O
it	O
,	O
and	O
feel	O
the	O
Divine	O
Creative	O
force	O
and	O
meaning	O
.	O

Friday	O
,	O
Feb.	O
.	O

17	O
.	O

6	O
miles	O
.	O

Off	O
at	O
7	O
o'clock	O
--	O
north	O
wind	O
increasing	O
--	O
we	O
however	O
passed	O
Silsilis	PERSON
soon	O
after	O
breakfast	O
,	O
and	O
are	O
lying	O
tonight	O
only	O
about	O
4	O
miles	O
below	O
--	O
having	O
fought	O
our	O
way	O
along	O
for	O
even	O
this	O
distance	O
.	O

Very	O
warm	O
and	O
heavy	O
clouds	O
collected	O
,	O
and	O
about	O
2	O
o'clock	O
,	O
a	O
sand	O
storm	O
broke	O
upon	O
us	O
,	O
and	O
for	O
an	O
hour	O
or	O
more	O
the	O
heat	O
was	O
great	O
,	O
78	O
on	O
my	O
balcony	O
.	O

A	O
beautiful	O
rainbow	O
afterwards	O
--	O
and	O
tonight	O
is	O
serenely	O
lovely	O
and	O
cooler	O
.	O

Saturday	O
,	O
Feb.	O
.	O

18	O
.	O

28	O
miles	O
.	O

Got	O
off	O
at	O
7	O
P.M.	O
--	O
calm	O
--	O
reached	O
Edfou	PERSON
at	O
one	O
o'clock	O
,	O
and	O
stopped	O
for	O
certain	O
things	O
such	O
as	O
yeast	O
,	O
butter	O
and	O
such	O
--	O
then	O
the	O
wind	O
began	O
to	O
blow	O
,	O
and	O
drifting	O
and	O
rowing	O
we	O
tied	O
up	O
6	O
miles	O
below	O
Edfou	LOCATION
.	O

Passed	O
this	O
morning	O
dahabeah	O
Cleopatra	O
with	O
tug	O
going	O
up	O
--	O
and	O
this	O
P.M.	O
also	O
going	O
up	O
,	O
the	O
Juliette	PERSON
,	O
Manhattan	LOCATION
,	O
Gamilla	PERSON
and	O
one	O
other	O
.	O

Warm	O
-	O
76	O
˚	O
.	O

1st	O
Sunday	O
in	O
Lent	O
.	O

Feb.	O
.	O

19	O
.	O

23	O
miles	O
.	O

Starting	O
at	O
our	O
usual	O
time	O
this	O
morning	O
,	O
7	O
o'clock	O
--	O
we	O
reached	O
El	PERSON
Kab	PERSON
at	O
9	O
o'clock	O
--	O
and	O
went	O
out	O
to	O
the	O
tombs	O
--	O
I	O
riding	O
a	O
wretched	O
little	O
donkey	O
,	O
the	O
others	O
walking	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
just	O
6	O
years	O
ago	O
that	O
we	O
did	O
the	O
same	O
thing	O
--	O
and	O
made	O
Page	O
27	O
a	O
visit	O
to	O
Mr.	O
Tyler	PERSON
,	O
and	O
Mr.	O
Somers-Clarke	PERSON
who	O
were	O
then	O
excavating	O
there	O
.	O

We	O
were	O
warmly	O
welcomed	O
by	O
my	O
old	O
woman	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
three	O
dogs	O
who	O
live	O
at	O
Mr.	O
Somers-Clarke	PERSON
's	O
house	O
--	O
and	O
I	O
fancy	O
all	O
four	O
will	O
sleep	O
more	O
comfortably	O
tonight	O
,	O
from	O
the	O
good	O
feeding	O
they	O
got	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
now	O
at	O
Esneh	ORGANIZATION
--	O
a	O
beautiful	O
day	O
--	O
and	O
inspiring	O
air	O
--	O
and	O
a	O
radiant	O
night	O
--	O
wind	O
a	O
little	O
cool	O
.	O

Passed	O
a	O
large	O
dahabeah	O
going	O
up	O
--	O
and	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
Khedivial	O
steamers	O
going	O
up	O
for	O
the	O
Duke	ORGANIZATION
and	O
Duchess	O
of	O
Connaught	O
.	O

Monday	O
,	O
Feb.	O
.	O

20	O
.	O

Luxor	LOCATION
.	O

34-1/2	O
miles	O
.	O

We	O
reached	O
here	O
at	O
3	O
o'clock	O
this	O
afternoon	O
--	O
very	O
warm	O
indeed	O
.	O

Came	O
again	O
to	O
our	O
old	O
place	O
under	O
the	O
Castle	O
.	O

Found	O
only	O
two	O
dahabeahs	O
here	O
--	O
and	O
I	O
never	O
saw	O
Luxor	LOCATION
so	O
quiet	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
,	O
Feb.	O
.	O

21	O
.	O

Very	O
high	O
wind	O
all	O
day	O
--	O
Theodore	PERSON
and	O
Bessie	PERSON
went	O
to	O
Der	PERSON
el	PERSON
Medineh	PERSON
.	O

Wednesday	O
,	O
Feb.	O
.	O

22	O
.	O

Cool	O
weather	O
with	O
strong	O
wind	O
from	O
the	O
north	O
.	O

Rode	O
into	O
Luxor	LOCATION
and	O
Mr.	O
Huhatt	PERSON
came	O
to	O
play	O
chess	O
with	O
Theodore	PERSON
,	O
and	O
stayed	O
to	O
lunch	O
.	O

Mary	PERSON
and	O
Bessie	PERSON
spent	O
the	O
day	O
at	O
Deir	PERSON
el	PERSON
Bahri	PERSON
.	O

Page	O
28	O
Luxor	LOCATION
,	O
Thursday	O
.	O

March	O
2	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
start	O
down	O
the	O
river	O
tomorrow	O
--	O
though	O
we	O
hate	O
the	O
necessity	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
so	O
pleasant	O
here	O
--	O
so	O
many	O
interesting	O
things	O
to	O
do	O
,	O
and	O
people	O
to	O
see	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
had	O
9	O
days	O
here	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
has	O
had	O
Mr.	O
Huhatt	PERSON
almost	O
every	O
day	O
to	O
lunch	O
--	O
and	O
to	O
play	O
chess	O
--	O
I	O
have	O
crossed	O
the	O
river	O
3	O
times	O
and	O
had	O
that	O
charming	O
ride	O
,	O
on	O
my	O
best	O
of	O
little	O
donkeys	O
,	O
Yankee	ORGANIZATION
Doodle	ORGANIZATION
Plymouth	ORGANIZATION
Rock	ORGANIZATION
!	O

First	O
,	O
Theodore	PERSON
,	O
Bessie	PERSON
and	O
I	O
went	O
to	O
Gurnah	LOCATION
,	O
to	O
call	O
on	O
Mr.	O
Newberry	PERSON
whom	O
we	O
found	O
at	O
home	O
.	O

Earl	PERSON
Spencer	PERSON
and	O
his	O
wife	O
were	O
making	O
him	O
a	O
visit	O
and	O
after	O
they	O
went	O
away	O
we	O
looked	O
at	O
many	O
of	O
the	O
beautiful	O
things	O
belonging	O
to	O
Mr.	O
Newberry	PERSON
.	O

All	O
the	O
things	O
found	O
in	O
their	O
excavations	O
were	O
packed	O
and	O
most	O
of	O
them	O
on	O
their	O
way	O
to	O
the	O
Museum	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
tea	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
he	O
and	O
Prof.	O
Spiegelberg	PERSON
who	O
has	O
been	O
working	O
with	O
him	O
all	O
the	O
winter	O
showed	O
us	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
tombs	O
they	O
had	O
opened	O
,	O
called	O
the	O
Gardeners	O
Tomb	O
,	O
with	O
very	O
beautiful	O
decorations	O
in	O
painting	O
--	O
the	O
colours	O
bright	O
as	O
new	O
.	O

The	O
tomb	O
was	O
just	O
below	O
the	O
house	O
of	O
the	O
Sheik	O
which	O
they	O
have	O
been	O
living	O
in	O
all	O
winter	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Newberry	PERSON
asked	O
us	O
to	O
go	O
with	O
him	O
to	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
private	O
tombs	O
,	O
I	O
had	O
never	O
seen	O
--	O
and	O
the	O
following	O
Sunday	O
morning	O
Theodore	O
,	O
Bessie	PERSON
and	O
I	O
went	O
over	O
after	O
breakfast	O
--	O
charming	O
morning	O
.	O

The	O
ride	O
along	O
the	O
high	O
canal	O
embankment	O
is	O
now	O
rather	O
disagreeable	O
,	O
as	O
hundreds	O
of	O
workmen	O
are	O
busy	O
digging	O
out	O
the	O
silt	O
,	O
left	O
from	O
last	O
years	O
inundation	O
.	O

In	O
this	O
way	O
this	O
great	O
embankment	O
grows	O
higher	O
and	O
wider	O
every	O
year	O
.	O

The	O
sun	O
proved	O
very	O
hot	O
while	O
we	O
were	O
clambering	O
over	O
and	O
down	O
the	O
rough	O
desert	O
of	O
that	O
ancient	O
necropolis	O
,	O
with	O
its	O
yawning	O
pits	O
.	O

We	O
went	O
first	O
to	O
one	O
that	O
had	O
been	O
delicately	O
beautiful	O
in	O
its	O
low	O
relief	O
.	O

Page	O
29	O
It	O
is	O
now	O
inhabited	O
by	O
fellaheen	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
sculptures	O
are	O
almost	O
entirely	O
buried	O
in	O
debris	O
.	O

Then	O
to	O
the	O
tomb	O
of	O
Nekht	O
--	O
then	O
to	O
one	O
of	O
Rekh-ma-ra	O
,	O
who	O
was	O
Governor	O
of	O
Thebes	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
died	O
in	O
the	O
reign	O
of	O
Amenhotep	O
II	O
.	O

This	O
tomb	O
with	O
its	O
elaborate	O
sculptures	O
and	O
paintings	O
,	O
Mr.	O
Newberry	PERSON
is	O
doing	O
for	O
publication	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
must	O
have	O
it	O
when	O
it	O
comes	O
out	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
delightful	O
to	O
have	O
Mr.	O
Newberry	PERSON
show	O
it	O
to	O
us	O
,	O
which	O
he	O
did	O
con	O
amore	O
--	O
with	O
every	O
explanation	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
after	O
12	O
when	O
we	O
said	O
goodbye	O
to	O
him	O
,	O
he	O
having	O
promised	O
to	O
come	O
to	O
dinner	O
with	O
us	O
the	O
next	O
night	O
.	O

We	O
found	O
him	O
more	O
interesting	O
than	O
we	O
thought	O
--	O
knows	O
everybody	O
and	O
everything	O
--	O
began	O
life	O
as	O
a	O
scientific	O
botanist	O
under	O
Sir	O
Joseph	PERSON
Hooker	PERSON
--	O
and	O
we	O
fraternised	O
at	O
once	O
over	O
our	O
mutual	O
tastes	O
in	O
gardening	O
and	O
architecture	O
.	O

Then	O
we	O
met	O
Mr.	O
Howard	PERSON
Carter	PERSON
--	O
who	O
has	O
been	O
doing	O
such	O
beautiful	O
work	O
at	O
Der	LOCATION
el	LOCATION
Bahri	LOCATION
,	O
for	O
so	O
long	O
.	O

He	O
also	O
came	O
to	O
dine	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
went	O
over	O
and	O
had	O
tea	O
with	O
him	O
the	O
afternoon	O
before	O
we	O
came	O
away	O
--	O
and	O
I	O
chose	O
the	O
subjects	O
of	O
two	O
sketches	O
he	O
is	O
to	O
make	O
for	O
me	O
--	O
Queen	O
Aahmes	O
--	O
and	O
Queen	PERSON
Sensenet	PERSON
,	O
Mother	O
of	O
Thothmes	O
I	O
.	O

The	O
Buxtons	PERSON
,	O
who	O
are	O
on	O
the	O
Nepthys	O
,	O
and	O
whom	O
we	O
met	O
at	O
Aswân	LOCATION
,	O
taking	O
tea	O
with	O
us	O
one	O
afternoon	O
,	O
told	O
us	O
that	O
Mrs.	O
Buxton	PERSON
's	O
-LRB-	O
Gurney	PERSON
-RRB-	O
grandfather	O
's	O
gamekeeper	O
,	O
was	O
this	O
young	O
Carter	PERSON
's	O
father	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
he	O
had	O
great	O
talent	O
-LRB-	O
the	O
father	O
-RRB-	O
in	O
drawing	O
animals	O
.	O

An	O
interesting	O
history	O
--	O
we	O
came	O
very	O
near	O
stumbling	O
upon	O
the	O
Duke	O
and	O
Duchess	O
of	O
Connaught	O
one	O
afternoon	O
as	O
we	O
went	O
to	O
pay	O
a	O
visit	O
to	O
the	O
Buxtons	O
.	O

They	O
asked	O
us	O
to	O
come	O
again	O
a	O
little	O
later	O
,	O
as	O
the	O
Duke	ORGANIZATION
had	O
sent	O
word	O
that	O
they	O
were	O
coming	O
to	O
have	O
tea	O
with	O
them	O
--	O
so	O
we	O
refrained	O
from	O
entering	O
the	O
boat	O
.	O

The	O
Nephtys	O
,	O
Thames	O
and	O
Istar	ORGANIZATION
all	O
came	O
down	O
the	O
same	O
day	O
.	O

Poor	O
Mr.	O
Sayce	PERSON
is	O
again	O
in	O
great	O
suffering	O
Page	O
30	O
and	O
under	O
the	O
surgical	O
care	O
of	O
the	O
doctor	O
here	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
and	O
I	O
went	O
to	O
see	O
him	O
yesterday	O
--	O
he	O
was	O
in	O
bed	O
--	O
but	O
called	O
to	O
me	O
to	O
come	O
and	O
speak	O
to	O
him	O
.	O

It	O
really	O
seems	O
very	O
serious	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
made	O
the	O
acquaintance	O
of	O
Mr.	O
Chauncey	PERSON
Murch	PERSON
,	O
the	O
head	O
of	O
the	O
American	ORGANIZATION
Mission	ORGANIZATION
here	O
at	O
Luxor	LOCATION
.	O

He	O
has	O
been	O
15	O
years	O
in	O
Egypt	LOCATION
--	O
and	O
is	O
a	O
native	O
of	O
Ohio	LOCATION
--	O
of	O
Reynoldsburg	LOCATION
,	O
nor	O
far	O
from	O
Columbus	LOCATION
,	O
where	O
I	O
used	O
sometimes	O
to	O
drive	O
as	O
a	O
child	O
with	O
my	O
father	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Murch	PERSON
is	O
really	O
huge	O
--	O
a	O
nice	O
little	O
wife	O
.	O

He	O
has	O
the	O
most	O
rare	O
and	O
beautiful	O
collection	O
of	O
scarabs	O
I	O
have	O
ever	O
seen	O
--	O
and	O
of	O
small	O
objects	O
.	O

Our	O
old	O
friend	O
Mohammed	PERSON
Mohassib	PERSON
has	O
had	O
some	O
very	O
interesting	O
things	O
.	O

Among	O
others	O
some	O
pre-historic	O
mummies	O
--	O
brought	O
from	O
Nagada	LOCATION
.	O

One	O
of	O
which	O
Theodore	PERSON
bought	O
,	O
and	O
is	O
going	O
to	O
present	O
it	O
to	O
the	O
Metropolitan	LOCATION
Museum	LOCATION
of	LOCATION
New	LOCATION
York	LOCATION
.	O

Friday	O
,	O
March	O
3d	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
and	O
I	O
went	O
to	O
see	O
Mr.	O
Sayce	PERSON
this	O
morning	O
--	O
but	O
I	O
did	O
not	O
see	O
him	O
.	O

He	O
reported	O
himself	O
going	O
on	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
could	O
be	O
hoped	O
--	O
we	O
got	O
away	O
about	O
noon	O
,	O
in	O
a	O
light	O
north	O
wind	O
,	O
passed	O
the	O
Nepthys	O
lying	O
at	O
Karnac	LOCATION
.	O

Have	O
made	O
about	O
17-1/2	O
miles	O
and	O
are	O
now	O
some	O
5	O
miles	O
south	O
of	O
Nagada	LOCATION
.	O

Saturday	O
,	O
March	O
4th	O
.	O

Have	O
made	O
only	O
7-1/2	O
miles	O
,	O
and	O
are	O
2	O
miles	O
below	O
Nagada	LOCATION
.	O

Day	O
cool	O
--	O
but	O
wind	O
very	O
fitful	O
.	O

Page	O
31	O
Third	O
Sunday	O
in	O
Lent	O
.	O

March	O
5th	O
.	O

An	O
early	O
start	O
,	O
but	O
have	O
accomplished	O
little	O
.	O

Are	O
now	O
within	O
2	O
or	O
3	O
miles	O
of	O
Keneh	LOCATION
.	O

The	O
wind	O
has	O
raged	O
at	O
times	O
.	O

The	O
Nephthys	O
appeared	O
early	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
Buxtons	O
and	O
Miss	O
Gurney	PERSON
came	O
to	O
tea	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
now	O
lying	O
at	O
anchor	O
,	O
both	O
boats	O
,	O
almost	O
side	O
by	O
side	O
.	O

Monday	O
,	O
March	O
6	O
.	O

14	O
miles	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
struggled	O
with	O
the	O
wind	O
all	O
day	O
,	O
and	O
are	O
now	O
lying	O
near	O
the	O
bank	O
about	O
12	O
miles	O
below	O
Keneh	LOCATION
.	O

The	O
Buxtons	PERSON
stopped	O
there	O
.	O

I	O
love	O
to	O
lie	O
near	O
some	O
desert	O
shore	O
,	O
or	O
best	O
some	O
lonely	O
stretch	O
of	O
sand	O
,	O
and	O
anchored	O
near	O
the	O
land	O
.	O

The	O
feeling	O
of	O
being	O
so	O
apart	O
,	O
the	O
lapping	O
of	O
the	O
water	O
and	O
the	O
silence	O
,	O
all	O
,	O
all	O
,	O
delightful	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
,	O
March	O
7	O
.	O

17	O
miles	O
.	O

The	O
same	O
history	O
for	O
the	O
day	O
--	O
an	O
early	O
start	O
,	O
baffling	O
winds	O
,	O
then	O
calms	O
,	O
until	O
as	O
usual	O
about	O
4	O
o'clock	O
a	O
regular	O
gale	O
began	O
--	O
and	O
we	O
lay	O
sometime	O
at	O
anchor	O
,	O
until	O
we	O
finally	O
pulled	O
to	O
shore	O
,	O
starting	O
again	O
about	O
9	O
o'clock	O
,	O
and	O
going	O
a	O
short	O
distance	O
,	O
about	O
10	O
miles	O
above	O
Nagh	LOCATION
Hamadi	LOCATION
.	O

Wednesday	O
,	O
March	O
8	O
.	O

14	O
miles	O
.	O

Started	O
early	O
,	O
and	O
reached	O
Nagh	PERSON
Hamadi	PERSON
about	O
10	O
o'clock	O
,	O
finding	O
the	O
bridge	O
closed	O
,	O
so	O
we	O
tied	O
up	O
to	O
the	O
float	O
next	O
the	O
bridge	O
,	O
and	O
waited	O
for	O
the	O
three	O
o'clock	O
Page	O
32	O
opening	O
.	O

The	O
day	O
very	O
hot	O
.	O

Soon	O
after	O
the	O
``	O
Manhattan	LOCATION
''	O
came	O
down	O
,	O
and	O
took	O
a	O
position	O
behind	O
us	O
--	O
and	O
in	O
the	O
distance	O
the	O
Nepthys	O
appeared	O
,	O
but	O
she	O
was	O
too	O
far	O
behind	O
to	O
take	O
advantage	O
of	O
that	O
opening	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
suppose	O
will	O
have	O
to	O
wait	O
for	O
tomorrow	O
6	O
o'clock	O
A.M.	O
.	O

We	O
got	O
through	O
with	O
some	O
little	O
excitement	O
,	O
and	O
have	O
made	O
4	O
miles	O
since	O
,	O
and	O
are	O
lying	O
at	O
an	O
island	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
Manhattan	LOCATION
near	O
.	O

Thursday	O
,	O
March	O
9	O
.	O

38-1/2	O
miles	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
done	O
very	O
well	O
today	O
,	O
and	O
are	O
now	O
4	O
miles	O
below	O
Menshieh	LOCATION
,	O
or	O
3-1/2	O
miles	O
south	O
of	O
Akmim	LOCATION
.	O

Very	O
hot	O
-	O
85	O
˚	O
on	O
my	O
cabana	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
mercury	O
standing	O
at	O
50	O
this	O
morning	O
.	O

Friday	O
,	O
March	O
10	O
.	O

26	O
miles	O
.	O

We	O
started	O
early	O
-	O
I	O
heard	O
the	O
sailors	O
at	O
their	O
oars	O
by	O
5:30	O
-	O
and	O
at	O
8:30	O
,	O
we	O
were	O
tying	O
up	O
at	O
the	O
handsome	O
town	O
of	O
Sohag	LOCATION
-	O
to	O
get	O
our	O
mail	O
and	O
provisions	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
have	O
been	O
there	O
two	O
hours	O
-	O
and	O
pulled	O
up	O
at	O
7:30	O
this	O
evening	O
within	O
7	O
miles	O
of	O
Tahtah	LOCATION
.	O

Calms	O
and	O
contrary	O
winds	O
all	O
day	O
.	O

Much	O
cooler	O
than	O
yesterday	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
been	O
struggling	O
with	O
a	O
great	O
batch	O
of	O
newspapers	O
today	O
-	O
all	O
of	O
them	O
full	O
of	O
extraordinary	O
storms	O
in	O
America	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
the	O
unprecedented	O
cold	O
-	O
which	O
is	O
hard	O
for	O
us	O
to	O
realize	O
.	O

They	O
bring	O
too	O
,	O
the	O
welcome	O
news	O
of	O
Kipling	O
's	O
improvement	O
,	O
who	O
has	O
been	O
so	O
ill	O
with	O
pneumonia	O
.	O

He	O
is	O
now	O
said	O
to	O
be	O
out	O
of	O
danger	O
.	O

The	O
world	O
can	O
ill	O
spare	O
such	O
a	O
mind	O
and	O
spirit	O
.	O

Page	O
33	O
Saturday	O
,	O
Mar.	O
.	O

11	O
.	O

22	O
miles	O
.	O

Started	O
at	O
5:30	O
--	O
with	O
the	O
exception	O
of	O
about	O
3	O
hours	O
of	O
calm	O
,	O
we	O
have	O
had	O
baffling	O
north	O
winds	O
all	O
day	O
--	O
very	O
warm	O
--	O
deck	O
disagreeable	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
now	O
about	O
2	O
or	O
3	O
miles	O
north	O
of	O
Gaen	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
are	O
lying	O
pleasantly	O
anchored	O
near	O
the	O
shore	O
.	O

Fourth	O
Sunday	O
in	O
Lent	O
.	O

Mar.	O
.	O

12	O
.	O

15	O
miles	O
.	O

Reached	O
Aboutig	O
at	O
one	O
o'clock	O
,	O
where	O
we	O
stayed	O
two	O
hours	O
--	O
Theodore	PERSON
writing	O
and	O
telegraphing	O
Cook	PERSON
at	O
Cairo	LOCATION
about	O
our	O
passage	O
across	O
to	O
Italy	LOCATION
.	O

High	O
north	O
wind	O
much	O
of	O
the	O
time	O
all	O
day	O
,	O
in	O
spite	O
of	O
the	O
heat	O
.	O

Mary	PERSON
and	O
Bessie	PERSON
walked	O
into	O
the	O
town	O
to	O
the	O
P.O.	O
with	O
the	O
sailors	O
.	O

While	O
they	O
were	O
away	O
,	O
I	O
sat	O
out	O
in	O
the	O
shade	O
of	O
my	O
cabana	O
,	O
and	O
looked	O
at	O
the	O
white	O
heat	O
that	O
pervaded	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

Across	O
the	O
water	O
at	O
the	O
edge	O
of	O
a	O
broad	O
stretch	O
of	O
sand	O
,	O
were	O
two	O
large	O
groups	O
of	O
native	O
men	O
,	O
engaged	O
in	O
some	O
disputation	O
.	O

I	O
took	O
my	O
glass	O
and	O
watched	O
them	O
--	O
and	O
could	O
not	O
but	O
admire	O
their	O
gestures	O
and	O
bearing	O
--	O
in	O
spite	O
of	O
their	O
heavy	O
,	O
trailing	O
garments	O
of	O
black	O
and	O
dark	O
brown	O
,	O
which	O
looked	O
so	O
inappropriate	O
--	O
and	O
,	O
as	O
they	O
in	O
the	O
heat	O
of	O
argument	O
threw	O
their	O
white	O
scarfs	O
off	O
,	O
and	O
again	O
on	O
,	O
they	O
might	O
have	O
served	O
as	O
studies	O
to	O
a	O
school	O
of	O
acting	O
.	O

At	O
last	O
they	O
separated	O
,	O
going	O
their	O
ways	O
across	O
the	O
burning	O
sand	O
,	O
striding	O
along	O
,	O
one	O
after	O
the	O
other	O
.	O

The	O
country	O
is	O
full	O
of	O
poppy	O
fields	O
in	O
bloom	O
--	O
such	O
pretty	O
pictures	O
they	O
make	O
along	O
the	O
bank	O
.	O

Page	O
34	O
Monday	O
,	O
March	O
13	O
.	O

20	O
miles	O
.	O

Reached	O
Asyut	O
at	O
11	O
o'clock	O
,	O
and	O
stopped	O
long	O
enough	O
to	O
get	O
our	O
mail	O
.	O

I	O
had	O
some	O
nice	O
letters	O
--	O
one	O
from	O
Mrs.	O
Norman	PERSON
,	O
full	O
of	O
wailing	O
about	O
the	O
dreadful	O
winter	O
at	O
home	O
.	O

One	O
from	O
Mr.	O
Sayce	PERSON
,	O
saying	O
he	O
was	O
able	O
to	O
walk	O
a	O
little	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
Doctor	O
thought	O
him	O
progressing	O
favorably	O
.	O

After	O
quitting	O
Asyut	LOCATION
,	O
we	O
passed	O
the	O
place	O
of	O
the	O
future	O
barrage	O
--	O
where	O
3	O
or	O
4	O
thousand	O
men	O
are	O
at	O
work	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
a	O
scene	O
from	O
the	O
Inferno	O
--	O
dust	O
--	O
turmoil	O
--	O
smoke	O
of	O
machines	O
--	O
shrieks	O
of	O
steam	O
--	O
inconceivable	O
--	O
and	O
in	O
such	O
a	O
heat	O
!	O

I	O
was	O
thankful	O
when	O
a	O
turn	O
in	O
the	O
river	O
hid	O
the	O
hideous	O
sight	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
the	O
fowls	O
out	O
for	O
a	O
little	O
while	O
,	O
and	O
Dick	PERSON
came	O
up	O
to	O
the	O
deck	O
to	O
see	O
me	O
,	O
and	O
get	O
his	O
biscuit	O
.	O

A	O
little	O
new	O
moon	O
has	O
appeared	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
,	O
Mar.	O
.	O

14	O
.	O

36-1/2	O
miles	O
.	O

A	O
very	O
hot	O
gray	O
day	O
--	O
like	O
a	O
Kamseen	O
,	O
without	O
the	O
wind	O
.	O

Occasionally	O
a	O
gentle	O
south	O
wind	O
which	O
carried	O
us	O
along	O
successfully	O
the	O
whole	O
Abu	LOCATION
Feda	LOCATION
chain	O
,	O
with	O
its	O
dangerous	O
bends	O
.	O

A	O
very	O
hot	O
night	O
-	O
86	O
˚	O
on	O
the	O
cabana	O
,	O
and	O
82	O
in	O
my	O
room	O
!	O

Wednesday	O
,	O
Mar.	O
.	O

15	O
.	O

Minia	PERSON
.	O

48-1/2	O
miles	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
had	O
a	O
beautiful	O
run	O
,	O
and	O
are	O
now	O
ahead	O
of	O
our	O
time	O
.	O

The	O
heat	O
has	O
been	O
great	O
--	O
of	O
a	O
more	O
trying	O
quality	O
than	O
that	O
of	O
yesterday	O
--	O
still	O
very	O
gray	O
and	O
overcast	O
,	O
and	O
apparently	O
threatening	O
rain	O
every	O
moment	O
.	O

Lying	O
at	O
the	O
disagreeable	O
bank	O
of	O
Minia	LOCATION
.	O

Page	O
35	O
Thursday	O
.	O

Mar.	O
.	O

16	O
.	O

28-1/2	O
miles	O
.	O

A	O
perfectly	O
calm	O
,	O
translucent	O
grey	O
day	O
,	O
sometimes	O
a	O
light	O
wind	O
from	O
the	O
north	O
.	O

The	O
men	O
have	O
worked	O
hard	O
with	O
their	O
oars	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
are	O
now	O
near	O
Sheik	LOCATION
Fadl	LOCATION
--	O
and	O
can	O
see	O
the	O
lights	O
of	O
the	O
great	O
sugar	O
factories	O
--	O
I	O
think	O
we	O
must	O
be	O
within	O
two	O
miles	O
of	O
it	O
.	O

Have	O
spent	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
day	O
down	O
stairs	O
writing	O
.	O

Have	O
finished	O
my	O
questions	O
on	O
the	O
Constitution	O
of	O
the	O
United	LOCATION
States	LOCATION
.	O

Every	O
moment	O
today	O
has	O
threatened	O
rain	O
--	O
mercury	O
at	O
85	O
˚	O
!	O

We	O
are	O
lying	O
out	O
in	O
the	O
stream	O
--	O
both	O
of	O
my	O
big	O
windows	O
are	O
uncurtained	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
look	O
out	O
unimpeded	O
on	O
the	O
night	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
water	O
softly	O
gurgling	O
about	O
the	O
boat	O
.	O

How	O
I	O
love	O
it	O
!	O

Friday	O
,	O
Mar.	O
.	O

17	O
.	O

32-1/2	O
miles	O
.	O

Another	O
gray	O
and	O
very	O
hot	O
day	O
,	O
until	O
late	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
when	O
the	O
wind	O
grew	O
strong	O
,	O
coming	O
in	O
gusts	O
,	O
and	O
tonight	O
it	O
is	O
from	O
the	O
north	O
and	O
cold	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
within	O
4	O
miles	O
of	O
Fashen	LOCATION
--	O
we	O
saw	O
our	O
young	O
moon	O
last	O
night	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
.	O

Thermometer	O
90	O
on	O
deck	O
today	O
.	O

We	O
smashed	O
our	O
bowsprit	O
this	O
afternoon	O
,	O
the	O
wind	O
driving	O
us	O
on	O
the	O
bank	O
.	O

Saturday	O
,	O
Mar.	O
.	O

18	O
.	O

28	O
miles	O
.	O

A	O
gray	O
day	O
again	O
,	O
but	O
cooler	O
--	O
and	O
several	O
times	O
rain	O
has	O
fallen	O
.	O

We	O
were	O
driven	O
below	O
by	O
quite	O
a	O
smart	O
little	O
shower	O
this	O
morning	O
--	O
saw	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
beautiful	O
pelicans	O
--	O
with	O
bill	O
quite	O
red	O
in	O
under	O
portion	O
,	O
and	O
green	O
above	O
.	O

Rowed	O
Page	O
36	O
until	O
after	O
8	O
o'clock	O
--	O
and	O
are	O
now	O
5	O
miles	O
below	O
Benisoef	LOCATION
.	O

5th	O
Sunday	O
in	O
Lent	O
.	O

Mar.	O
.	O

19	O
.	O

28	O
miles	O
.	O

Stopped	O
at	O
Wasta	LOCATION
for	O
mail	O
this	O
morning	O
at	O
11	O
o'clock	O
--	O
and	O
tied	O
up	O
at	O
6	O
o'clock	O
tonight	O
26	O
miles	O
from	O
Bedrasheyn	LOCATION
.	O

Day	O
hot	O
--	O
and	O
wind	O
cold	O
.	O

How	O
we	O
do	O
hate	O
to	O
be	O
winding	O
up	O
the	O
pleasant	O
Nile	O
days	O
--	O
and	O
how	O
I	O
shall	O
miss	O
my	O
charming	O
room	O
.	O

The	O
brilliant	O
nights	O
,	O
when	O
with	O
uncurtained	O
windows	O
I	O
could	O
look	O
out	O
upon	O
the	O
night	O
--	O
the	O
swiftly	O
flowing	O
river	O
--	O
the	O
desert	O
,	O
or	O
the	O
palm	O
fringed	O
shore	O
.	O

The	O
early	O
morning	O
readings	O
in	O
bed	O
,	O
or	O
the	O
watching	O
of	O
the	O
dawn	O
.	O

How	O
tame	O
the	O
land	O
will	O
seem	O
,	O
and	O
how	O
shut	O
in	O
and	O
stifling	O
a	O
curtained	O
room	O
will	O
seem	O
!	O

Then	O
how	O
comfortable	O
to	O
move	O
from	O
place	O
to	O
place	O
with	O
no	O
packing	O
to	O
do	O
--	O
simply	O
to	O
keep	O
on	O
one	O
's	O
way	O
in	O
one	O
's	O
own	O
house	O
!	O

Monday	O
,	O
March	O
20	O
.	O

26	O
miles	O
.	O

Are	O
once	O
more	O
lying	O
at	O
Bedrasheyn	LOCATION
,	O
which	O
we	O
reached	O
at	O
7	O
o'clock	O
.	O

Strong	O
wind	O
from	O
the	O
north	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
,	O
March	O
21	O
.	O

15	O
miles	O
.	O

Started	O
very	O
early	O
this	O
morning	O
--	O
and	O
reached	O
the	O
Museum	O
landing	O
at	O
Ghizeh	LOCATION
at	O
9:30	O
.	O

Our	O
old	O
man	O
,	O
the	O
guardian	O
of	O
the	O
Museum	O
barge	O
,	O
was	O
very	O
glad	O
to	O
see	O
us	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
found	O
the	O
Loulie-el-Nil	LOCATION
,	O
lying	O
just	O
in	O
front	O
of	O
us	O
--	O
and	O
her	O
Captain	O
and	O
sailors	O
welcomed	O
us	O
warmly	O
,	O
and	O
with	O
ready	O
help	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
very	O
glad	O
to	O
have	O
got	O
Page	O
37	O
a	O
berth	O
here	O
as	O
it	O
is	O
so	O
convenient	O
to	O
visit	O
the	O
Museum	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
went	O
to	O
town	O
,	O
and	O
came	O
back	O
with	O
our	O
mail	O
,	O
and	O
Salah	PERSON
,	O
bringing	O
his	O
arms	O
full	O
of	O
flowers	O
for	O
me	O
.	O

Mary	PERSON
and	O
I	O
drove	O
into	O
town	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
,	O
and	O
met	O
Mr.	O
Newberry	PERSON
,	O
and	O
asked	O
him	O
to	O
dine	O
tomorrow	O
.	O

He	O
came	O
on	O
the	O
train	O
this	O
morning	O
,	O
and	O
said	O
he	O
passed	O
us	O
below	O
Bedrescheyn	LOCATION
this	O
morning	O
at	O
6	O
o'clock	O
.	O

We	O
drove	O
about	O
the	O
orange	O
gardens	O
on	O
our	O
way	O
home	O
.	O

Alas	O
!	O

owing	O
to	O
some	O
disease	O
last	O
year	O
,	O
they	O
have	O
all	O
been	O
shorn	O
of	O
their	O
branches	O
,	O
and	O
cut	O
almost	O
to	O
the	O
ground	O
,	O
and	O
all	O
the	O
diseased	O
branches	O
and	O
leaves	O
have	O
been	O
left	O
everywhere	O
as	O
they	O
fell	O
from	O
the	O
trees	O
,	O
and	O
are	O
now	O
quite	O
withered	O
and	O
dry	O
--	O
and	O
have	O
fully	O
no	O
doubt	O
,	O
impregnated	O
the	O
ground	O
with	O
their	O
disease	O
germs	O
--	O
when	O
this	O
has	O
been	O
thoroughly	O
accomplished	O
,	O
they	O
will	O
cart	O
them	O
away	O
--	O
and	O
this	O
is	O
the	O
native	O
method	O
with	O
everything	O
in	O
life	O
--	O
and	O
this	O
is	O
why	O
Egyptians	O
and	O
Egypt	LOCATION
will	O
always	O
need	O
an	O
intelligent	O
domineering	O
.	O

Wednesday	O
,	O
March	O
22	O
.	O

We	O
all	O
went	O
over	O
early	O
to	O
the	O
Museum	O
this	O
morning	O
--	O
and	O
how	O
pleasant	O
it	O
was	O
to	O
see	O
it	O
all	O
again	O
.	O

The	O
new	O
finds	O
are	O
enormously	O
interesting	O
.	O

One	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
remarkable	O
is	O
a	O
statue	O
of	O
bronze	O
,	O
heroic	O
size	O
,	O
found	O
at	O
Kom	LOCATION
el-Ahmar	LOCATION
,	O
opposite	O
El	LOCATION
Kab	LOCATION
,	O
by	O
Mr.	O
Quibell	PERSON
--	O
with	O
a	O
smaller	O
statue	O
near	O
it	O
of	O
the	O
same	O
material	O
;	O
and	O
the	O
gold	O
hawks	O
head	O
that	O
we	O
saw	O
last	O
year	O
on	O
Mr.	O
Somers-Clarke	PERSON
's	O
dahabeah	O
,	O
found	O
at	O
the	O
same	O
place	O
,	O
and	O
above	O
all	O
a	O
large	O
slate	O
,	O
from	O
the	O
same	O
place	O
,	O
and	O
with	O
the	O
name	O
of	O
a	O
king	O
preceeding	O
Mena	ORGANIZATION
--	O
a	O
most	O
remarkable	O
piece	O
.	O

We	O
spent	O
a	O
long	O
time	O
among	O
all	O
the	O
beautiful	O
little	O
objects	O
up	O
stairs	O
--	O
and	O
I	O
Page	O
38	O
looked	O
at	O
the	O
mummy	O
of	O
the	O
beautiful	O
Nefertari	PERSON
and	O
fancied	O
I	O
could	O
trace	O
lines	O
of	O
beauty	O
in	O
the	O
shrunken	O
black	O
face	O
--	O
and	O
wondered	O
why	O
she	O
was	O
not	O
laid	O
beside	O
her	O
victorious	O
and	O
famous	O
husband	O
Aahmes	PERSON
,	O
the	O
first	O
king	O
of	O
the	O
18th	O
dynasty	O
.	O

We	O
met	O
Mr.	O
Newberry	PERSON
there	O
,	O
and	O
he	O
showed	O
us	O
such	O
interesting	O
things	O
--	O
and	O
he	O
introduced	O
Mr.	O
Quibell	PERSON
,	O
and	O
also	O
Baron	PERSON
von	PERSON
Bissing	PERSON
,	O
a	O
very	O
clever	O
young	O
scholar	O
who	O
is	O
working	O
at	O
the	O
Museum	O
.	O

Mary	PERSON
and	O
I	O
drove	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
and	O
we	O
had	O
a	O
charming	O
evening	O
with	O
Mr.	O
Newberry	PERSON
--	O
and	O
we	O
talked	O
Egypt	LOCATION
and	O
things	O
Egyptian	O
galore	O
.	O

The	O
moon	O
is	O
almost	O
full	O
now	O
--	O
and	O
I	O
enjoy	O
the	O
nights	O
,	O
with	O
my	O
curtains	O
not	O
drawn	O
and	O
all	O
the	O
night	O
looking	O
in	O
upon	O
me	O
.	O

Thursday	O
,	O
March	O
23	O
.	O

Again	O
at	O
the	O
Museum	O
this	O
morning	O
--	O
though	O
first	O
Mr.	O
Newberry	PERSON
came	O
by	O
appointment	O
to	O
go	O
to	O
Ali	PERSON
the	O
Antiquity	O
man	O
in	O
Ghirgeh	LOCATION
with	O
us	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
bought	O
some	O
good	O
things	O
--	O
we	O
stumbled	O
by	O
chance	O
in	O
the	O
Museum	O
after	O
Mr.	O
Newberry	PERSON
left	O
us	O
,	O
upon	O
a	O
room	O
entirely	O
filled	O
with	O
things	O
from	O
the	O
tomb	O
of	O
Amenophis	O
III	O
which	O
was	O
found	O
last	O
year	O
by	O
M.	PERSON
Loret	PERSON
of	O
the	O
Museum	O
.	O

Such	O
wonderful	O
blue	O
glazes	O
--	O
and	O
such	O
exquisite	O
work	O
!	O

In	O
the	O
afternoon	O
Mary	PERSON
and	O
I	O
drove	O
out	O
almost	O
to	O
the	O
Pyramids	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
tremendously	O
hot	O
--	O
and	O
a	O
high	O
wind	O
blowing	O
as	O
it	O
has	O
blown	O
for	O
days	O
.	O

One	O
of	O
our	O
horses	O
soon	O
after	O
we	O
turned	O
to	O
come	O
home	O
,	O
had	O
the	O
blind	O
staggers	O
--	O
Mary	PERSON
and	O
I	O
easily	O
stepped	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
Victoria	LOCATION
,	O
the	O
coachman	O
and	O
Salah	PERSON
sprang	O
from	O
the	O
box	O
--	O
but	O
these	O
people	O
are	O
so	O
unready	O
and	O
helpless	O
in	O
an	O
emergency	O
--	O
they	O
could	O
not	O
relieve	O
the	O
poor	O
animal	O
of	O
the	O
harness	O
--	O
a	O
mounted	O
gens	O
d'armes	O
fortunately	O
arrived	O
,	O
and	O
gave	O
Page	O
39	O
what	O
help	O
he	O
could	O
--	O
the	O
horse	O
at	O
last	O
struggled	O
on	O
his	O
feet	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
began	O
the	O
wildest	O
scene	O
,	O
the	O
poor	O
beast	O
crazed	O
,	O
kicked	O
everything	O
to	O
pieces	O
,	O
overturned	O
the	O
nice	O
carriage	O
,	O
which	O
by	O
great	O
exertion	O
on	O
the	O
part	O
of	O
Salah	PERSON
and	O
the	O
coachman	O
was	O
just	O
saved	O
as	O
it	O
was	O
going	O
over	O
the	O
embankment	O
--	O
the	O
dash	O
board	O
,	O
dashes	O
,	O
lamps	O
were	O
smashed	O
--	O
the	O
pole	O
broken	O
in	O
3	O
pieces	O
--	O
the	O
harness	O
a	O
wreck	O
.	O

The	O
other	O
horse	O
behaved	O
most	O
beautifully	O
and	O
intelligently	O
--	O
as	O
quiet	O
as	O
possible	O
,	O
and	O
showed	O
such	O
concern	O
for	O
the	O
sick	O
one	O
,	O
that	O
it	O
was	O
quite	O
touching	O
.	O

Everyone	O
who	O
passed	O
offered	O
assistance	O
,	O
but	O
we	O
sent	O
to	O
the	O
Mena	ORGANIZATION
House	ORGANIZATION
for	O
another	O
carriage	O
,	O
and	O
arrived	O
at	O
home	O
a	O
few	O
minutes	O
before	O
dinner	O
.	O

Friday	O
,	O
March	O
24	O
.	O

Museum	O
--	O
driving	O
--	O
Mr.	O
Newberry	PERSON
to	O
lunch	O
--	O
very	O
hot	O
--	O
wind	O
still	O
very	O
strong	O
.	O

Saturday	O
,	O
March	O
25	O
.	O

Another	O
morning	O
at	O
the	O
Museum	O
,	O
and	O
Mr.	O
Quibell	PERSON
to	O
lunch	O
--	O
a	O
kamseen	O
day	O
--	O
dry	O
--	O
hot	O
--	O
windy	O
--	O
I	O
declined	O
going	O
out	O
.	O

Sunday	O
,	O
March	O
26	O
.	O

Sunday	O
before	O
Easter	O
.	O

A	O
very	O
hot	O
morning	O
-	O
Mary	PERSON
and	O
Bessie	PERSON
drove	O
into	O
town	O
-	O
Theodore	O
to	O
the	O
Museum	O
,	O
a	O
long	O
visit	O
from	O
Mr.	O
Paterson	PERSON
which	O
prevented	O
me	O
from	O
doing	O
what	O
I	O
had	O
devoted	O
the	O
morning	O
to	O
do	O
.	O

At	O
home	O
all	O
day	O
-	O
``	O
Thames	O
''	O
came	O
down	O
today	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
Ammon-Ra	O
last	O
evening	O
with	O
a	O
tug	O
.	O

Saw	O
the	O
Buxtons	O
today	O
.	O

Very	O
gray	O
and	O
stormy	O
-	O
some	O
rain	O
fell	O
two	O
or	O
three	O
times	O
.	O

Too	O
unpleasant	O
to	O
be	O
on	O
deck	O
.	O

Page	O
40	O
Monday	O
,	O
March	O
27	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
and	O
I	O
went	O
into	O
town	O
today	O
to	O
antiquity	O
shops	O
-	O
met	O
Mr.	O
Newberry	PERSON
and	O
persuaded	O
him	O
to	O
come	O
to	O
lunch	O
-	O
and	O
we	O
talked	O
Museum	O
matters	O
all	O
the	O
time	O
.	O

Mary	PERSON
drove	O
him	O
home	O
,	O
Theodore	PERSON
and	O
Bessie	PERSON
went	O
to	O
ride	O
as	O
they	O
do	O
every	O
day	O
-	O
and	O
I	O
began	O
my	O
little	O
arrangements	O
for	O
packing	O
.	O

Much	O
fever	O
in	O
Cairo	LOCATION
-	O
it	O
is	O
said	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Newberry	PERSON
starts	O
today	O
for	O
England	LOCATION
.	O

Baron	PERSON
von	PERSON
Bissing	PERSON
came	O
to	O
dine	O
-	O
very	O
clever	O
-	O
nervous	O
,	O
interesting	O
-	O
talks	O
a	O
great	O
deal	O
-	O
has	O
the	O
clearest	O
and	O
keenest	O
eyes	O
I	O
have	O
ever	O
seen	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
,	O
March	O
28	O
.	O

A	O
great	O
change	O
in	O
the	O
temperature	O
since	O
yesterday	O
-	O
it	O
is	O
gray	O
-	O
cold	O
-	O
and	O
a	O
howling	O
wind	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
all	O
the	O
canvass	O
down	O
on	O
the	O
deck	O
-	O
but	O
there	O
was	O
such	O
a	O
flapping	O
and	O
such	O
a	O
blow	O
,	O
we	O
could	O
hardly	O
pack	O
up	O
there	O
.	O

These	O
last	O
days	O
of	O
packing	O
are	O
so	O
triste	O
and	O
trying	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
Beduin	O
grows	O
in	O
spite	O
of	O
it	O
the	O
more	O
attractive	O
,	O
as	O
these	O
last	O
days	O
draw	O
on	O
-	O
I	O
hate	O
to	O
leave	O
this	O
river	O
life	O
.	O

Good	O
Friday	O
-	O
March	O
31st	O
.	O

We	O
came	O
to	O
the	O
Ghezireh	O
Palace	O
Hotel	O
on	O
Wednesday	O
afternoon	O
-	O
quitting	O
the	O
Beduin	O
with	O
sad	O
hearts	O
-	O
we	O
have	O
the	O
same	O
big	O
rooms	O
overlooking	O
the	O
garden	O
we	O
had	O
two	O
years	O
ago	O
.	O

The	O
weather	O
has	O
been	O
very	O
bad	O
,	O
cold	O
-	O
with	O
such	O
tremendous	O
winds	O
.	O

The	O
storm	O
along	O
the	O
coast	O
has	O
been	O
so	O
great	O
that	O
steamers	O
have	O
not	O
been	O
able	O
to	O
leave	O
Alexandria	LOCATION
for	O
days	O
.	O

Snow	O
on	O
the	O
Continent	O
and	O
skating	O
in	O
England	LOCATION
!	O

Not	O
a	O
good	O
prospect	O
for	O
Page	O
41	O
sailing	O
as	O
we	O
expect	O
to	O
do	O
on	O
the	O
3d	O
April	O
,	O
from	O
Port	LOCATION
Said	LOCATION
for	O
Brindisi	LOCATION
.	O

We	O
have	O
been	O
to	O
the	O
boat	O
every	O
day	O
-	O
and	O
have	O
this	O
afternoon	O
said	O
good-bye	O
to	O
the	O
sailors	O
who	O
go	O
to	O
their	O
homes	O
up	O
the	O
river	O
at	O
once	O
.	O

Cairo	LOCATION
begins	O
to	O
look	O
deserted	O
-	O
and	O
this	O
hotel	O
a	O
vast	O
wilderness	O
.	O

Saturday	O
,	O
April	O
1st	O
.	O

Visits	O
to	O
the	O
antiquity	O
shops	O
this	O
morning	O
-	O
and	O
immediately	O
after	O
luncheon	O
a	O
last	O
drive	O
and	O
visit	O
to	O
the	O
Beduin	O
.	O

All	O
the	O
sailors	O
had	O
left	O
-	O
and	O
there	O
only	O
remained	O
Rais	PERSON
Fuli	PERSON
and	O
Abdul	PERSON
,	O
and	O
a	O
friend	O
of	O
Fuli	PERSON
's	O
who	O
is	O
to	O
stay	O
with	O
them	O
.	O

She	O
will	O
drop	O
down	O
a	O
little	O
way	O
tomorrow	O
,	O
to	O
a	O
better	O
resting	O
place	O
for	O
the	O
summer	O
.	O

She	O
is	O
in	O
her	O
dress	O
of	O
coarse	O
canvass	O
,	O
shrouded	O
entirely	O
.	O

On	O
the	O
lower	O
deck	O
,	O
this	O
canvass	O
was	O
lifted	O
on	O
the	O
river	O
side	O
and	O
everything	O
was	O
so	O
clean	O
and	O
orderly	O
I	O
felt	O
like	O
stopping	O
forever	O
.	O

Dick	PERSON
,	O
with	O
his	O
little	O
white	O
hen	O
,	O
strutted	O
across	O
the	O
gangway	O
to	O
have	O
a	O
last	O
biscuit	O
from	O
me	O
,	O
and	O
even	O
the	O
geese	O
swam	O
around	O
to	O
have	O
a	O
last	O
look	O
at	O
us	O
.	O

Then	O
back	O
to	O
the	O
Gezireh	O
-	O
Baron	PERSON
von	PERSON
Bissing	PERSON
came	O
to	O
tea	O
,	O
and	O
for	O
a	O
final	O
talk	O
about	O
Egyptian	O
matters	O
-	O
Theodore	PERSON
was	O
so	O
tired	O
,	O
I	O
thought	O
he	O
would	O
have	O
fallen	O
asleep	O
.	O

Brindisi	LOCATION
-	O
April	O
6	O
.	O

We	O
arrived	O
in	O
port	O
about	O
midnight	O
and	O
had	O
decided	O
to	O
stay	O
on	O
the	O
steamer	O
and	O
take	O
breakfast	O
,	O
but	O
what	O
with	O
many	O
passengers	O
going	O
off	O
at	O
once	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
others	O
to	O
catch	O
the	O
7	O
o'clock	O
A.M.	O
train	O
,	O
there	O
was	O
but	O
little	O
sleep	O
to	O
be	O
had	O
.	O

We	O
left	O
Cairo	LOCATION
on	O
Easter	O
morning	O
at	O
10	O
o'clock	O
-	O
Fuli	PERSON
,	O
Abdul	PERSON
,	O
the	O
Cook	PERSON
,	O
Salah	PERSON
and	O
Mr.	O
Landus	PERSON
to	O
see	O
us	O
off	O
.	O

A	O
Page	O
42	O
very	O
tiring	O
,	O
dusty	O
ride	O
to	O
Ismailia	LOCATION
which	O
we	O
reached	O
at	O
3	O
o'clock	O
and	O
where	O
we	O
changed	O
cars	O
,	O
for	O
Port	LOCATION
Said	LOCATION
,	O
where	O
we	O
arrived	O
about	O
7	O
o'clock	O
,	O
an	O
uncomfortable	O
dinner	O
in	O
the	O
overcrowded	O
hotel	O
,	O
where	O
we	O
met	O
the	O
Buxtons	PERSON
who	O
were	O
going	O
off	O
in	O
the	O
Arabia	LOCATION
for	O
Marseilles	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
then	O
we	O
went	O
out	O
to	O
our	O
own	O
boat	O
the	O
Osiris	O
,	O
P.	O
&	O
O.	O
and	O
went	O
comfortably	O
and	O
early	O
to	O
bed	O
in	O
our	O
clean	O
looking	O
cabins	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
to	O
wait	O
until	O
the	O
morning	O
for	O
the	O
Arabia	LOCATION
,	O
for	O
the	O
mails	O
-	O
and	O
were	O
off	O
at	O
9	O
o'clock	O
on	O
the	O
3d	O
and	O
went	O
immediately	O
into	O
the	O
most	O
tempestuous	O
sea	O
I	O
ever	O
knew	O
,	O
which	O
grew	O
worse	O
as	O
each	O
hour	O
went	O
by	O
-	O
until	O
finally	O
smashing	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
bridge	O
and	O
the	O
forward	O
galley	O
,	O
the	O
boat	O
was	O
put	O
at	O
a	O
low	O
rate	O
of	O
speed	O
.	O

I	O
was	O
comfortably	O
taking	O
my	O
breakfast	O
in	O
bed	O
when	O
we	O
started	O
-	O
I	O
never	O
finished	O
it	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
did	O
not	O
leave	O
my	O
berth	O
until	O
last	O
evening	O
,	O
for	O
dinner	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
,	O
the	O
Captain	O
,	O
one	O
other	O
officer	O
and	O
Jones	PERSON
,	O
were	O
the	O
only	O
persons	O
at	O
table	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
ships	O
doctor	O
was	O
in	O
bed	O
all	O
the	O
way	O
over	O
.	O

We	O
decided	O
we	O
would	O
never	O
again	O
try	O
this	O
route	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
rather	O
comfortable	O
here	O
.	O

Took	O
a	O
bright	O
drive	O
about	O
this	O
bare	O
and	O
dreary	O
town	O
and	O
country	O
this	O
afternoon	O
-	O
and	O
will	O
take	O
the	O
early	O
train	O
to	O
Rome	LOCATION
tomorrow	O
morning	O
.	O

Hotel	O
Bristol	LOCATION
.	O

First	O
Sunday	O
after	O
Easter	O
.	O

April	O
9	O
.	O

Arrived	O
evening	O
before	O
last	O
at	O
7:30	O
-	O
after	O
a	O
long	O
journey	O
of	O
13	O
hours	O
-	O
which	O
was	O
not	O
as	O
tiring	O
as	O
I	O
had	O
feared	O
it	O
would	O
be	O
.	O

But	O
after	O
our	O
rude	O
experience	O
at	O
sea	O
,	O
I	O
find	O
my	O
head	O
still	O
going	O
round	O
and	O
Page	O
43	O
round	O
,	O
and	O
my	O
legs	O
failing	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
in	O
our	O
pleasant	O
old	O
rooms	O
overlooking	O
the	O
Piazza	PERSON
Barberini	PERSON
.	O

I	O
went	O
out	O
this	O
afternoon	O
,	O
but	O
only	O
to	O
St.	LOCATION
Peters	LOCATION
-	O
where	O
we	O
stayed	O
some	O
time	O
-	O
and	O
I	O
walked	O
up	O
and	O
down	O
that	O
splendid	O
building	O
,	O
until	O
I	O
was	O
tired	O
.	O

Day	O
damp	O
and	O
rainy	O
and	O
cold	O
.	O

We	O
find	O
Andersen	PERSON
looking	O
much	O
better	O
;	O
he	O
takes	O
most	O
of	O
his	O
meals	O
with	O
us	O
.	O

After	O
St.	PERSON
Peters	PERSON
we	O
went	O
to	O
the	O
Elliotts	ORGANIZATION
and	O
found	O
them	O
at	O
home	O
.	O

Dr.	O
Bull	PERSON
dined	O
with	O
us	O
.	O

Monday	O
,	O
April	O
10	O
.	O

Raining	O
and	O
cold	O
.	O

The	O
Elliots	ORGANIZATION
and	O
Andersen	PERSON
dined	O
with	O
us	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
,	O
April	O
11	O
.	O

Went	O
to	O
the	O
Palazzo	O
Patriècè	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
pictures	O
with	O
M.	PERSON
Jeubert	PERSON
.	O

A	O
desperately	O
dismal	O
palace	O
,	O
and	O
not	O
a	O
picture	O
that	O
I	O
would	O
have	O
had	O
.	O

Did	O
some	O
rummaging	O
about	O
in	O
an	O
old	O
shop	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
drove	O
in	O
the	O
fine	O
,	O
bracing	O
cold	O
air	O
on	O
the	O
Pincian	LOCATION
.	O

At	O
home	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
.	O

Mary	PERSON
and	O
Bessie	PERSON
hard	O
at	O
work	O
every	O
day	O
sight	O
seeing	O
.	O

Countess	PERSON
Freufelli-Cibo	PERSON
called	O
.	O

Wednesday	O
,	O
April	O
12	O
.	O

Steady	O
,	O
hard	O
rain	O
all	O
the	O
morning	O
-	O
for	O
a	O
short	O
drive	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
.	O

Dr.	O
Richter	PERSON
here	O
for	O
a	O
long	O
time	O
.	O

In	O
spite	O
of	O
rain	O
went	O
with	O
Mr.	O
Elliot	PERSON
to	O
the	O
house	O
of	O
the	O
artist	O
Villegas	PERSON
and	O
saw	O
and	O
bought	O
some	O
nice	O
stuffs	O
.	O

Page	O
44	O
Thursday	O
,	O
April	O
13	O
.	O

Drove	O
in	O
the	O
rain	O
to	O
the	O
Colonna	LOCATION
Gallery	LOCATION
.	O

Met	O
Miss	O
Alexander	PERSON
there	O
,	O
Daisy	PERSON
Busk	PERSON
's	O
friend	O
-	O
asked	O
her	O
to	O
tea	O
on	O
Saturday	O
.	O

Home	O
in	O
the	O
rain	O
,	O
growling	O
at	O
the	O
weather	O
.	O

Dr.	O
Richter	PERSON
to	O
lunch	O
-	O
and	O
did	O
not	O
leave	O
the	O
house	O
again	O
.	O

Basil	O
Fielding	O
called	O
.	O

He	O
is	O
now	O
Father	O
Fielding	O
,	O
mature	O
,	O
and	O
somewhat	O
less	O
exuberant	O
-	O
and	O
very	O
devote	O
.	O

Frida	PERSON
,	O
April	O
14th	O
.	O

Met	O
Mr.	O
Hobson	PERSON
and	O
Andersen	PERSON
at	O
the	O
Vatican	LOCATION
this	O
morning	O
by	O
appointment	O
,	O
and	O
went	O
through	O
the	O
Borgia	PERSON
appartments	O
.	O

Saw	O
the	O
Bradleys	O
there	O
.	O

Then	O
I	O
made	O
a	O
bold	O
effort	O
to	O
get	O
into	O
the	O
Museo	ORGANIZATION
Cristiano	ORGANIZATION
,	O
which	O
I	O
had	O
never	O
seen	O
,	O
and	O
after	O
traversing	O
the	O
great	O
galleries	O
back	O
to	O
the	O
entrance	O
,	O
we	O
gained	O
the	O
door	O
to	O
the	O
Bibliotèque	O
,	O
through	O
which	O
we	O
had	O
to	O
walk	O
,	O
before	O
reaching	O
the	O
Museo	O
.	O

Here	O
we	O
found	O
all	O
the	O
pictures	O
shut	O
away	O
behind	O
glass	O
cases	O
,	O
which	O
were	O
locked	O
,	O
and	O
no	O
catalogues	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
attendants	O
ignorant	O
and	O
surly	O
.	O

I	O
had	O
a	O
small	O
list	O
which	O
I	O
had	O
gathered	O
from	O
Berenson	PERSON
's	O
Italian	O
Central	O
Painters	O
.	O

There	O
are	O
beautiful	O
treasures	O
of	O
Sienese	O
and	O
Umbrian	O
art	O
.	O

Home	O
just	O
in	O
time	O
for	O
luncheon	O
-	O
and	O
Mary	PERSON
and	O
I	O
went	O
at	O
5	O
o'clock	O
to	O
a	O
reception	O
at	O
Countess	ORGANIZATION
Freufelli-Cibo	ORGANIZATION
's	O
which	O
was	O
nice	O
-	O
she	O
so	O
cordial	O
-	O
and	O
so	O
many	O
Italian	O
people	O
,	O
-	O
Duchesses	O
,	O
Princesses	O
galore	O
-	O
I	O
talked	O
with	O
many	O
pleasant	O
people	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
evening	O
Theodore	PERSON
and	O
I	O
went	O
to	O
dine	O
at	O
the	O
Palazzo	LOCATION
Borghese	LOCATION
with	O
Mrs.	O
Bronson	PERSON
-	O
a	O
beautiful	O
dinner	O
,	O
several	O
people	O
and	O
a	O
very	O
grand	O
appartment	O
.	O

Well	O
tired	O
tonight	O
.	O

Page	O
45	O
Saturday	O
,	O
April	O
15	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
ready	O
to	O
make	O
an	O
early	O
start	O
tomorrow	O
.	O

It	O
has	O
rained	O
all	O
day	O
-	O
I	O
did	O
a	O
little	O
shopping	O
this	O
morning	O
,	O
and	O
Mary	PERSON
,	O
Bessie	PERSON
and	O
I	O
drove	O
over	O
to	O
St.	PERSON
Peters	PERSON
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
to	O
find	O
it	O
closed	O
in	O
preparation	O
for	O
the	O
great	O
anniversary	O
of	O
the	O
Pope	O
's	O
coronation	O
tomorrow	O
.	O

The	O
venerable	O
Pope	PERSON
has	O
now	O
well	O
recovered	O
from	O
the	O
serious	O
operation	O
he	O
has	O
lately	O
gone	O
through	O
,	O
and	O
is	O
pronounced	O
able	O
to	O
bear	O
the	O
excitement	O
.	O

It	O
rained	O
so	O
hard	O
that	O
I	O
came	O
home	O
,	O
while	O
Mary	PERSON
and	O
Bessie	PERSON
went	O
to	O
some	O
churches	O
.	O

Miss	O
Alexander	PERSON
came	O
to	O
tea	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
and	O
Miss	O
Bronson	PERSON
came	O
to	O
say	O
goodbye	O
.	O

Basil	O
Fielding	O
dined	O
,	O
and	O
stayed	O
a	O
long	O
time	O
talking	O
.	O

Monday	O
,	O
April	O
17	O
.	O

Not	O
a	O
bad	O
journey	O
from	O
Rome	LOCATION
yesterday	O
.	O

I	O
slept	O
much	O
of	O
the	O
time	O
.	O

Lizzie	PERSON
Buttles	PERSON
,	O
and	O
Nettie	PERSON
with	O
Hassan	PERSON
met	O
us	O
-	O
and	O
we	O
came	O
to	O
our	O
old	O
quarters	O
at	O
the	O
Grande	LOCATION
Bretagne	LOCATION
.	O

The	O
weather	O
still	O
á	O
la	O
pluie	O
.	O

The	O
Arno	PERSON
full	O
.	O

Andersen	PERSON
came	O
with	O
us	O
from	O
Florence	LOCATION
.	O

Mr.	O
Berenson	PERSON
came	O
to	O
dine	O
.	O

This	O
morning	O
I	O
went	O
after	O
breakfast	O
to	O
the	O
Villino	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
much	O
talked	O
of	O
little	O
house	O
-	O
and	O
found	O
it	O
charming	O
-	O
full	O
of	O
pretty	O
and	O
valuable	O
things	O
-	O
clean	O
,	O
modern	O
,	O
and	O
convenient	O
and	O
a	O
sweet	O
little	O
garden	O
.	O

I	O
was	O
charmed	O
with	O
it	O
,	O
and	O
with	O
their	O
satisfaction	O
in	O
it	O
.	O

Then	O
Nettie	PERSON
and	O
I	O
went	O
to	O
the	O
Academia	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
had	O
a	O
beautiful	O
time	O
.	O

There	O
is	O
no	O
one	O
I	O
so	O
enjoy	O
going	O
to	O
a	O
gallery	O
with	O
.	O

Some	O
very	O
remarkable	O
and	O
beautiful	O
tapestires	O
have	O
been	O
hung	O
there	O
in	O
the	O
long	O
corridor	O
-	O
once	O
a	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
Medician	O
riches	O
-	O
delightful	O
things	O
.	O

This	O
afternoon	O
,	O
Theodore	PERSON
,	O
Bessie	PERSON
and	O
I	O
drove	O
up	O
to	O
Mrs.	O
Castello	PERSON
's	O
in	O
the	O
Page	O
46	O
rain	O
to	O
have	O
tea	O
,	O
and	O
see	O
her	O
and	O
Berenson	PERSON
's	O
pretty	O
things	O
.	O

We	O
met	O
there	O
her	O
brother	O
Mr.	O
Logan-Smith	PERSON
,	O
and	O
a	O
young	O
Percy	PERSON
Fielding	PERSON
a	O
cousin	O
of	O
our	O
friends	O
-	O
and	O
we	O
had	O
good	O
tea	O
and	O
buttered	O
toast	O
in	O
a	O
charming	O
hall	O
overlooking	O
the	O
valley	O
,	O
surrounded	O
with	O
quaint	O
things	O
,	O
looking	O
at	O
Sienese	O
paintings	O
and	O
discussing	O
its	O
beauties	O
,	O
and	O
many	O
things	O
besides	O
,	O
and	O
had	O
a	O
charming	O
time	O
,	O
and	O
stayed	O
an	O
unconscionable	O
time	O
,	O
and	O
drove	O
home	O
in	O
the	O
rain	O
,	O
dressed	O
,	O
and	O
drove	O
to	O
Lizzie	PERSON
's	O
and	O
dined	O
-	O
and	O
enjoyed	O
ourselves	O
hugely	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
,	O
April	O
18	O
.	O

Nettie	PERSON
and	O
I	O
went	O
to	O
the	O
Ufizzi	O
this	O
morning	O
,	O
and	O
stayed	O
until	O
we	O
were	O
blind	O
with	O
fatigue	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
afternoon	O
we	O
all	O
went	O
to	O
a	O
reception	O
at	O
Lizzie	PERSON
's	O
which	O
she	O
was	O
very	O
anxious	O
to	O
give	O
me	O
-	O
and	O
I	O
met	O
many	O
of	O
her	O
friends	O
,	O
who	O
were	O
most	O
cordial	O
.	O

The	O
house	O
looked	O
charming	O
-	O
Mr.	O
Berenson	PERSON
came	O
to	O
dine	O
.	O

Wednesday	O
,	O
April	O
19	O
.	O

Went	O
with	O
Theodore	PERSON
this	O
morning	O
across	O
the	O
river	O
to	O
the	O
antiquity	O
shop	O
of	O
Constantine	O
to	O
see	O
a	O
lovely	O
medallion	O
of	O
Madonna	PERSON
and	O
Child	O
by	O
Mino	PERSON
da	PERSON
Fiesole	PERSON
,	O
that	O
Berenson	PERSON
had	O
told	O
him	O
about	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
decided	O
to	O
buy	O
it	O
-	O
but	O
felt	O
the	O
embarrassment	O
of	O
getting	O
it	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
country	O
-	O
it	O
is	O
necessary	O
to	O
be	O
very	O
quiet	O
about	O
it	O
,	O
as	O
its	O
history	O
is	O
so	O
peculiar	O
and	O
interesting	O
.	O

It	O
came	O
from	O
the	O
unimportant	O
church	O
of	O
St.	ORGANIZATION
Bridget	ORGANIZATION
in	O
Rome	LOCATION
only	O
a	O
short	O
time	O
since	O
.	O

Constantine	PERSON
,	O
prowling	O
Page	O
47	O
about	O
some	O
months	O
ago	O
for	O
treasures	O
came	O
upon	O
this	O
church	O
and	O
persuaded	O
the	O
sacristan	O
or	O
priest	O
to	O
allow	O
him	O
to	O
have	O
a	O
copy	O
made	O
to	O
replace	O
the	O
original	O
-	O
it	O
was	O
done	O
,	O
the	O
Mino	PERSON
gave	O
place	O
to	O
the	O
copy	O
,	O
the	O
church	O
received	O
the	O
money	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
precious	O
Mino	PERSON
goes	O
to	O
America	LOCATION
to	O
take	O
her	O
place	O
in	O
our	O
hall	O
,	O
and	O
to	O
administer	O
to	O
us	O
daily	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
sweet	O
peace	O
and	O
pure	O
beauty	O
of	O
that	O
XVth	O
century	O
art	O
.	O

A	O
young	O
man	O
,	O
the	O
son	O
of	O
Constantine	PERSON
,	O
who	O
lived	O
some	O
time	O
in	O
New	LOCATION
York	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
was	O
a	O
clerk	O
at	O
Tiffany	ORGANIZATION
's	O
and	O
who	O
speaks	O
excellent	O
English	O
told	O
Theodore	PERSON
that	O
he	O
was	O
going	O
over	O
to	O
America	LOCATION
next	O
month	O
and	O
would	O
take	O
in	O
the	O
medallion	O
and	O
charge	O
himself	O
with	O
all	O
responsibility	O
and	O
trouble	O
.	O

So	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
strength	O
of	O
this	O
,	O
we	O
bought	O
several	O
things	O
-	O
chairs	O
,	O
stuffs	O
etc.	O
-	O
so	O
that	O
they	O
might	O
all	O
go	O
over	O
together	O
.	O

Then	O
we	O
prowled	O
into	O
some	O
other	O
shops	O
,	O
and	O
bought	O
a	O
little	O
exquisitely	O
painted	O
portrait	O
,	O
probably	O
French	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
afternoon	O
I	O
and	O
Bessie	PERSON
went	O
for	O
Lizzie	PERSON
,	O
and	O
the	O
girls	O
and	O
we	O
went	O
to	O
Mrs.	O
Ryerson	PERSON
's	O
pretty	O
appartment	O
to	O
a	O
reception	O
given	O
me	O
,	O
and	O
met	O
some	O
pleasant	O
people	O
.	O

Saw	O
and	O
talked	O
a	O
long	O
time	O
with	O
Prof.	O
Fiske	PERSON
,	O
who	O
asked	O
us	O
to	O
tea	O
tomorrow	O
.	O

Berenson	PERSON
to	O
dinner	O
.	O

Thursday	O
,	O
April	O
20	O
.	O

Nettie	PERSON
and	O
I	O
went	O
to	O
the	O
Pitti	LOCATION
this	O
morning	O
and	O
met	O
Theodore	PERSON
,	O
Anderson	PERSON
and	O
Bessie	PERSON
there	O
-	O
went	O
to	O
the	O
flower	O
market	O
for	O
flowers	O
and	O
bought	O
some	O
trinkets	O
at	O
a	O
shop	O
-	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
we	O
drove	O
in	O
the	O
rain	O
out	O
to	O
Prof.	O
Fiskes	PERSON
,	O
had	O
tea	O
,	O
ices	O
and	O
strawberries	O
!!	O

-LRB-	O
at	O
5	O
o'clock	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
-RRB-	O
went	O
all	O
over	O
his	O
beautiful	O
old	O
Italian	O
villa	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
entirely	O
furnished	O
in	O
brutal	O
American	O
and	O
French	O
fashion	O
-	O
looked	O
Page	O
48	O
longingly	O
at	O
his	O
Italian	O
garden	O
from	O
each	O
window	O
,	O
and	O
marvelled	O
at	O
the	O
opportunities	O
going	O
to	O
waste	O
everywhere	O
,	O
-	O
then	O
drove	O
to	O
Berensons	ORGANIZATION
,	O
had	O
tea	O
again	O
and	O
watched	O
the	O
clouds	O
rolling	O
away	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
sun	O
deciding	O
to	O
show	O
himself	O
for	O
a	O
few	O
moments	O
,	O
and	O
listened	O
to	O
the	O
thrushes	O
and	O
blackbirds	O
,	O
saw	O
4	O
charming	O
panels	O
of	O
Saints	ORGANIZATION
by	O
Taddeo	PERSON
di	PERSON
Bartoli	PERSON
which	O
Berenson	PERSON
had	O
just	O
received	O
from	O
Siena	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
which	O
Theodore	PERSON
bought	O
at	O
once	O
,	O
and	O
drove	O
home	O
late	O
enough	O
for	O
dinner	O
with	O
Berenson	PERSON
and	O
Andersen	PERSON
to	O
dinner	O
.	O

Friday	O
,	O
April	O
21	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
ready	O
to	O
start	O
tomorrow	O
for	O
Venice	LOCATION
-	O
Nettie	PERSON
goes	O
with	O
us	O
fortunately	O
and	O
Andersen	PERSON
.	O

Shopping	O
,	O
sightseeing	O
,	O
dodging	O
the	O
rain	O
all	O
day	O
.	O

Lizzie	PERSON
and	O
the	O
girls	O
dined	O
and	O
have	O
just	O
gone	O
.	O
