PAGE	O
73	O
S.S.	PERSON
Gens	PERSON
.	O

Nov.	O
17	O
,	O
1896	O
We	O
sailed	O
at	O
10	O
o'clock	O
on	O
Saturday	O
the	O
14th	O
-	O
Mr.	O
Convers	O
,	O
Mr.	O
Luling	PERSON
and	O
Mr.	O
Jevons	PERSON
were	O
down	O
to	O
see	O
us	O
off	O
.	O

A	O
cold	O
bright	O
morning	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
cold	O
lasted	O
until	O
yesterday	O
-	O
everyone	O
congealed	O
-	O
but	O
we	O
are	O
now	O
in	O
warmer	O
waters	O
-	O
and	O
constant	O
sunshine	O
-	O
I	O
have	O
a	O
large	O
bright	O
room	O
-	O
at	O
a	O
table	O
in	O
which	O
I	O
am	O
writing	O
.	O

The	O
sun	O
looks	O
into	O
my	O
port	O
by	O
day	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
moon	O
by	O
night	O
-	O
for	O
we	O
have	O
fortunately	O
fallen	O
upon	O
the	O
second	O
quarter	O
of	O
the	O
moon	O
.	O

The	O
last	O
thing	O
I	O
do	O
,	O
after	O
having	O
turned	O
out	O
the	O
light	O
at	O
night	O
,	O
is	O
to	O
climb	O
up	O
on	O
the	O
sofa	O
,	O
and	O
take	O
a	O
look	O
at	O
the	O
night	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
wide	O
waste	O
:	O
of	O
blue	O
black	O
water	O
,	O
in	O
which	O
our	O
ship	O
makes	O
its	O
great	O
furrow	O
of	O
dashing	O
white	O
foam	O
-	O
what	O
a	O
beautiful	O
immensity	O
it	O
is	O
,	O
and	O
a	O
grand	O
picture	O
to	O
carry	O
into	O
the	O
oblivion	O
of	O
the	O
night	O
.	O

There	O
are	O
comparatively	O
few	O
passangers	O
-	O
and	O
I	O
have	O
never	O
known	O
such	O
pleasant	O
ones	O
.	O

The	O
Hamilton	PERSON
Fisks	PERSON
of	O
New	LOCATION
York	LOCATION
-	O
Dr.	O
Doty	PERSON
,	O
the	O
Health	O
Officer	O
of	O
the	O
N.	LOCATION
Y.	LOCATION
Port	LOCATION
,	O
Mrs.	O
Ward	PERSON
Howe	PERSON
Elliot	PERSON
,	O
the	O
daughter	O
of	O
Mrs.	O
Julia	PERSON
Ward	PERSON
Howe	PERSON
-	O
and	O
a	O
Mr.	O
Pratt	PERSON
-	O
now	O
American	O
Consul	O
General	O
at	O
Singapore	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
for	O
five	O
years	O
our	O
Minister	O
to	O
Persia	LOCATION
-	O
a	O
really	O
cultivated	O
man	O
.	O

We	O
all	O
have	O
tea	O
together	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
,	O
and	O
make	O
very	O
merry	O
-	O
and	O
we	O
have	O
Mrs.	O
Bend	O
of	O
New	LOCATION
York	LOCATION
and	O
her	O
two	O
daughters	O
at	O
our	O
table	O
.	O

I	O
asked	O
Mr.	O
Pratt	PERSON
how	O
long	O
Benjamin	PERSON
,	O
former	O
Minister	O
to	O
Persia	LOCATION
,	O
had	O
lived	O
in	O
that	O
country	O
,	O
and	O
he	O
said	O
3	O
years	O
.	O

I	O
said	O
that	O
was	O
rather	O
a	O
short	O
time	O
acquaintance	O
with	O
a	O
country	O
about	O
which	O
to	O
write	O
an	O
exhaustive	O
work	O
.	O

He	O
tole	O
me	O
Benjamin	PERSON
had	O
given	O
great	O
offence	O
to	O
the	O
Shela	PERSON
,	O
and	O
others	O
in	O
his	O
book	O
-	O
and	O
that	O
he	O
had	O
seen	O
absolutely	O
nothing	O
of	O
parts	O
of	O
Persia	LOCATION
about	O
which	O
he	O
writes	O
.	O

PAGE	O
74	O
Nov.	O
27	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
reach	O
Genoa	ORGANIZATION
in	O
a	O
few	O
hours	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
will	O
gladly	O
say	O
au	O
revoir	O
to	O
the	O
sea	O
for	O
3	O
or	O
4	O
days	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
very	O
cold	O
this	O
morning	O
,	O
but	O
clear	O
.	O

Until	O
we	O
reached	O
Gibraltar	LOCATION
our	O
beautiful	O
balmy	O
weather	O
lasted	O
.	O

We	O
passed	O
the	O
Azoros	O
on	O
the	O
20th	O
-	O
running	O
very	O
close	O
to	O
the	O
large	O
island	O
of	O
San	LOCATION
Miguel	LOCATION
-	O
very	O
picturesque	O
with	O
its	O
background	O
of	O
mountains	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
steep	O
slopes	O
,	O
some	O
of	O
them	O
quite	O
cultivated	O
to	O
the	O
top	O
-	O
its	O
pleasant	O
looking	O
houses	O
and	O
villages	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
miles	O
of	O
low	O
grass	O
houses	O
,	O
where	O
immense	O
quantities	O
of	O
pineapples	O
are	O
cultivated	O
.	O

On	O
Monday	O
morning	O
the	O
23d	O
we	O
reached	O
Gibraltar	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
went	O
ashore	O
,	O
despite	O
of	O
some	O
threatening	O
clouds	O
.	O

We	O
took	O
Beatrice	PERSON
Bend	PERSON
in	O
our	O
carriage	O
and	O
went	O
as	O
far	O
as	O
Europa	LOCATION
Point	LOCATION
,	O
but	O
before	O
we	O
again	O
reached	O
the	O
town	O
,	O
rain	O
began	O
to	O
fall	O
,	O
and	O
there	O
was	O
nothing	O
to	O
do	O
but	O
stop	O
at	O
the	O
wretched	O
Hotel	LOCATION
Royal	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
wait	O
until	O
it	O
was	O
time	O
to	O
go	O
back	O
to	O
the	O
steamer	O
-	O
and	O
there	O
we	O
waited	O
staring	O
out	O
on	O
the	O
same	O
little	O
square	O
where	O
I	O
spent	O
so	O
many	O
hours	O
doing	O
the	O
same	O
thing	O
two	O
years	O
ago	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
went	O
out	O
and	O
bought	O
3	O
umbrellas	O
-	O
a	O
pair	O
of	O
overshoes	O
for	O
me	O
,	O
and	O
3	O
yards	O
of	O
macintosh	O
cloth	O
for	O
us	O
to	O
sit	O
upon	O
on	O
the	O
wet	O
,	O
unprotected	O
decks	O
of	O
the	O
little	O
tender	O
.	O

From	O
that	O
time	O
until	O
last	O
night	O
the	O
gale	O
has	O
raged	O
-	O
and	O
3	O
miserable	O
nights	O
have	O
I	O
spent	O
and	O
2	O
days	O
in	O
my	O
forward	O
cabin	O
,	O
tossed	O
up	O
and	O
down	O
.	O

Yesterday	O
morning	O
early	O
the	O
26	O
,	O
we	O
dropped	O
our	O
anchor	O
in	O
the	O
bay	O
of	O
Naples	LOCATION
-	O
and	O
in	O
spite	O
of	O
some	O
rain	O
and	O
a	O
high	O
wind	O
,	O
I	O
went	O
ashore	O
with	O
the	O
rest	O
,	O
and	O
spent	O
a	O
pleasant	O
day	O
.	O

The	O
two	O
Bend	O
girls	O
we	O
took	O
immediately	O
to	O
the	O
Grand	LOCATION
Hotel	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
found	O
pleasant	O
rooms	O
for	O
them	O
,	O
and	O
by	O
the	O
time	O
Mrs.	O
Bend	PERSON
arrived	O
from	O
the	O
PAGE	O
75	O
Custom	ORGANIZATION
House	ORGANIZATION
,	O
we	O
had	O
ordered	O
luncheon	O
,	O
and	O
made	O
a	O
short	O
visit	O
to	O
the	O
Aquarium	O
.	O

How	O
good	O
that	O
lunch	O
was	O
,	O
and	O
how	O
good	O
the	O
stable	O
land	O
was	O
!	O

Then	O
we	O
said	O
goodbye	O
to	O
our	O
friends	O
,	O
and	O
started	O
back	O
to	O
the	O
steamer	O
-	O
stopping	O
a	O
few	O
moments	O
at	O
Squadriblis	LOCATION
to	O
buy	O
some	O
shell	O
things	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
had	O
a	O
quiet	O
night	O
,	O
and	O
are	O
running	O
smoothly	O
this	O
morning	O
.	O

S.S.	O
Freiderick	O
der	O
Grosser	O
.	O

near	O
Port	LOCATION
Said	LOCATION
.	O

Dec.	O
6	O
I	O
am	O
so	O
thankful	O
that	O
this	O
long	O
voyage	O
has	O
almost	O
come	O
to	O
an	O
end	O
-	O
and	O
that	O
we	O
will	O
arrive	O
at	O
Port	LOCATION
Said	LOCATION
early	O
tomorrow	O
morning	O
-	O
we	O
reached	O
Genoa	LOCATION
on	O
the	O
27	O
Nov.	O
just	O
too	O
late	O
to	O
catch	O
the	O
only	O
train	O
to	O
Florence	LOCATION
at	O
noon	O
-	O
and	O
after	O
a	O
slight	O
delay	O
at	O
the	O
Custom	ORGANIZATION
House	ORGANIZATION
,	O
made	O
a	O
long	O
journey	O
through	O
the	O
streets	O
of	O
the	O
town	O
to	O
the	O
``	O
Hotel	O
du	O
Pare	O
''	O
a	O
rather	O
attractive	O
looking	O
ancient	O
Villa	PERSON
standing	O
in	O
large	O
grounds	O
with	O
trees	O
,	O
which	O
might	O
be	O
cheerful	O
on	O
a	O
summers	O
day	O
,	O
but	O
on	O
that	O
chill	O
afternoon	O
,	O
dripping	O
with	O
rain	O
,	O
was	O
truly	O
disconsolate	O
.	O

The	O
palatial	O
rooms	O
and	O
halls	O
,	O
with	O
their	O
tiny	O
fires	O
and	O
enormous	O
windows	O
shaking	O
and	O
rattling	O
in	O
the	O
gale	O
,	O
made	O
us	O
thankful	O
we	O
were	O
only	O
going	O
to	O
stop	O
for	O
the	O
night	O
.	O

The	O
next	O
day	O
we	O
were	O
off	O
for	O
Florence	LOCATION
at	O
12	O
o'clock	O
-	O
which	O
we	O
reached	O
at	O
7	O
P.M.	O
-	O
a	O
weary	O
ride	O
-	O
slow	O
and	O
rough	O
,	O
through	O
never	O
ending	O
tunnels	O
.	O

The	O
girls	O
and	O
Hassan	PERSON
were	O
waiting	O
for	O
us	O
,	O
and	O
went	O
with	O
us	O
to	O
the	O
Grande	LOCATION
Bretagne	LOCATION
,	O
where	O
we	O
were	O
installed	O
in	O
our	O
old	O
appartment	O
.	O

Florence	LOCATION
the	O
next	O
day	O
was	O
cold	O
,	O
but	O
bright	O
.	O

I	O
spent	O
the	O
Sunday	O
morning	O
with	O
Mary	PERSON
shopping	O
-	O
I	O
found	O
her	O
chattering	O
Italian	O
like	O
a	O
native	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
and	O
Nettie	PERSON
went	O
to	O
the	O
Uffizzi	O
-	O
PAGE	O
76	O
Clarence	PERSON
and	O
Jones	PERSON
to	O
do	O
as	O
much	O
of	O
the	O
town	O
as	O
they	O
could	O
.	O

Lizzie	PERSON
and	O
both	O
girls	O
came	O
to	O
breakfast	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
girls	O
stopped	O
to	O
lunch	O
-	O
after	O
which	O
a	O
drive	O
to	O
Fiesole	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
the	O
rest	O
of	O
the	O
time	O
with	O
Lizzie	PERSON
in	O
their	O
pretty	O
little	O
appartment	O
,	O
2	O
Via	O
Venezia	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
all	O
came	O
home	O
with	O
us	O
to	O
dinner	O
.	O

Berenson	PERSON
also	O
came	O
to	O
dinner	O
,	O
looking	O
very	O
well	O
.	O

The	O
next	O
day	O
we	O
were	O
off	O
to	O
Genoa	LOCATION
again	O
,	O
with	O
Mary	PERSON
along	O
and	O
went	O
for	O
the	O
night	O
to	O
the	O
``	O
Hotel	O
Isotta	O
''	O
,	O
much	O
more	O
comfortable	O
than	O
the	O
other	O
.	O

At	O
2	O
o'clock	O
the	O
next	O
day	O
we	O
went	O
out	O
to	O
the	O
Frederick	O
the	O
Great	O
-	O
and	O
after	O
enormous	O
trouble	O
and	O
anxiety	O
,	O
through	O
the	O
insufficiency	O
and	O
want	O
of	O
order	O
of	O
the	O
North	O
German	O
Lloyd	ORGANIZATION
Co.	ORGANIZATION
.	O

we	O
succeeded	O
at	O
last	O
in	O
getting	O
all	O
our	O
30	O
pieces	O
of	O
luggage	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
Custom	ORGANIZATION
House	ORGANIZATION
and	O
aboard	O
the	O
steamer	O
-	O
and	O
sailed	O
about	O
5	O
o'clock	O
the	O
next	O
morning	O
for	O
Naples	LOCATION
.	O

We	O
found	O
the	O
steamer	O
very	O
pleasant	O
,	O
but	O
rather	O
durious	O
in	O
her	O
arrangement	O
.	O

Large	O
as	O
she	O
is	O
she	O
only	O
carries	O
120	O
first	O
class	O
passengers	O
-	O
but	O
she	O
carries	O
enormous	O
freight	O
to	O
Australia	LOCATION
-	O
her	O
decks	O
are	O
charming	O
-	O
the	O
service	O
and	O
the	O
food	O
very	O
poor	O
.	O

Reached	O
Naples	LOCATION
the	O
next	O
morning	O
-	O
rain	O
pouring	O
-	O
everyone	O
else	O
went	O
ashore	O
-	O
I	O
stayed	O
at	O
home	O
-	O
Dr.	O
Peabody	PERSON
and	O
family	O
,	O
Mr.	O
Pratt	PERSON
and	O
Dr.	O
Doty	PERSON
arrived	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
.	O

So	O
did	O
the	O
Kaiser	PERSON
Wilhelm	PERSON
,	O
just	O
from	O
New	LOCATION
York	LOCATION
,	O
a	O
week	O
later	O
than	O
ourselves	O
.	O

We	O
were	O
at	O
last	O
off	O
on	O
the	O
home	O
stretch	O
for	O
Egypt	LOCATION
at	O
6	O
P.M.	O
.	O

Since	O
then	O
the	O
weather	O
has	O
been	O
bad	O
,	O
and	O
heavy	O
seas	O
until	O
today	O
-	O
which	O
is	O
lovely	O
.	O

In	O
my	O
room	O
during	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
voyage	O
from	O
Genoa	LOCATION
.	O

PAGE	O
77	O
Shepheards	ORGANIZATION
Hotel	ORGANIZATION
.	O

Cairo	LOCATION
.	O

Dec.	O
9	O
-	O
96	O
We	O
arrived	O
day	O
before	O
yesterday	O
the	O
7th	O
at	O
6	O
P.M.	ORGANIZATION
and	O
took	O
possession	O
of	O
our	O
pleasant	O
old	O
appartment	O
facing	O
the	O
street	O
no.	O
120	O
et	O
suite	O
.	O

On	O
the	O
evening	O
of	O
the	O
6th	O
we	O
passed	O
the	O
Damietta	LOCATION
light	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
ship	O
steamed	O
slowly	O
and	O
almost	O
imperceptibly	O
along	O
until	O
she	O
dropped	O
anchor	O
at	O
Port	LOCATION
Said	LOCATION
about	O
2	O
o'clock	O
A.M.	O
.	O

There	O
was	O
but	O
little	O
sleep	O
to	O
be	O
had	O
-	O
what	O
with	O
the	O
coaling	O
,	O
the	O
babbling	O
and	O
shrieking	O
outside	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
stir	O
inside	O
-	O
and	O
as	O
the	O
night	O
was	O
warm	O
,	O
and	O
all	O
the	O
doors	O
and	O
ports	O
closed	O
because	O
of	O
the	O
coaling	O
,	O
sleep	O
was	O
far	O
from	O
every	O
one	O
.	O

At	O
6	O
o'clock	O
Amilie	O
came	O
to	O
call	O
me	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
was	O
glad	O
to	O
give	O
up	O
the	O
struggle	O
and	O
get	O
up	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
little	O
trouble	O
at	O
the	O
Custom	ORGANIZATION
House	ORGANIZATION
,	O
and	O
were	O
soon	O
in	O
a	O
clean	O
and	O
very	O
comfortable	O
railway	O
carriage	O
for	O
Ismailia	LOCATION
,	O
where	O
we	O
got	O
an	O
excellent	O
lunch	O
at	O
the	O
new	O
hotel	O
established	O
lately	O
by	O
Shepheards	O
,	O
and	O
waited	O
for	O
the	O
Cairo	LOCATION
train	O
.	O

We	O
find	O
Shepheards	O
practically	O
empty	O
-	O
and	O
this	O
season	O
is	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
bad	O
one	O
for	O
Egypt	LOCATION
I	O
fear	O
.	O

The	O
next	O
morning	O
we	O
had	O
a	O
grand	O
disappointment	O
in	O
finding	O
that	O
our	O
boat	O
was	O
a	O
month	O
behind	O
time	O
-	O
painters	O
and	O
carpenters	O
still	O
at	O
work	O
-	O
the	O
boom	O
not	O
raised	O
,	O
and	O
general	O
helplessness	O
.	O

The	O
English	O
foreman	O
of	O
Thubron	PERSON
is	O
quite	O
ineffectual	O
-	O
and	O
Thubron	PERSON
has	O
shown	O
gross	O
negligence	O
and	O
carelessness	O
.	O

Instead	O
of	O
the	O
boat	O
ready	O
,	O
and	O
in	O
sailing	O
order	O
for	O
the	O
1st	O
of	O
Dec.	O
as	O
the	O
contract	O
calls	O
for	O
-	O
Thubron	PERSON
has	O
evidently	O
given	O
his	O
whole	O
attention	O
to	O
building	O
gunboats	O
up	O
the	O
river	O
.	O

He	O
has	O
been	O
at	O
Dongola	LOCATION
for	O
3	O
months	O
-	O
and	O
has	O
allowed	O
the	O
Beduin	O
to	O
care	O
for	O
herself	O
.	O

Theodore	O
with	O
admirable	O
patience	O
made	O
PAGE	O
78	O
himself	O
master	O
of	O
facts	O
through	O
the	O
dire	O
confusion	O
of	O
falsehoods	O
and	O
incompetency	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
he	O
went	O
for	O
Thubron	PERSON
and	O
his	O
foreman	O
,	O
with	O
such	O
well	O
directed	O
effort	O
and	O
so	O
much	O
energetic	O
talking	O
,	O
that	O
the	O
foreman	O
is	O
scared	O
out	O
of	O
his	O
life	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
workmen	O
are	O
jumping	O
about	O
like	O
monkeys	O
.	O

I	O
am	O
busy	O
all	O
the	O
time	O
now	O
with	O
an	O
hundred	O
practical	O
details	O
.	O

Sunday	O
,	O
Dec.	O
13	O
.	O

Mary	PERSON
and	O
Clarence	PERSON
have	O
gone	O
off	O
in	O
the	O
carriage	O
with	O
Salah	PERSON
to	O
see	O
the	O
Tombs	O
of	O
the	O
Mameluks	O
and	O
the	O
Khalifs	LOCATION
-	LOCATION
Theodore	LOCATION
,	O
Dr.	O
Doty	PERSON
and	O
Dr.	O
Peabody	PERSON
,	O
have	O
gone	O
on	O
donkeys	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
dahabeah	O
.	O

We	O
go	O
every	O
day	O
to	O
the	O
boat	O
to	O
watch	O
and	O
direct	O
its	O
progress	O
-	O
and	O
we	O
hope	O
to	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
get	O
off	O
by	O
the	O
1st	O
of	O
January	O
.	O

The	O
great	O
trouble	O
now	O
is	O
that	O
the	O
furniture	O
was	O
not	O
shipped	O
from	O
England	LOCATION
until	O
the	O
6th	O
of	O
Dec.	O
!	O

We	O
have	O
engaged	O
our	O
old	O
cook	O
Hanna	PERSON
-	PERSON
poor	PERSON
Selim	PERSON
having	O
died	O
here	O
not	O
more	O
than	O
a	O
month	O
ago	O
-	O
Hanna	PERSON
speaks	O
no	O
French	O
or	O
English	O
,	O
but	O
as	O
we	O
have	O
engaged	O
a	O
very	O
promising	O
young	O
Nubian	O
as	O
waiter	O
whom	O
Salah	PERSON
knows	O
very	O
well	O
,	O
and	O
who	O
has	O
lived	O
for	O
years	O
in	O
England	LOCATION
,	O
we	O
can	O
get	O
on	O
very	O
well	O
.	O

Ibrahim	PERSON
too	O
is	O
engaged	O
as	O
2d	O
man	O
and	O
laundress	O
-	O
and	O
my	O
Mohammed	PERSON
Ibrahim	PERSON
is	O
going	O
in	O
no	O
capacity	O
that	O
I	O
can	O
think	O
of	O
,	O
except	O
to	O
learn	O
more	O
English	O
,	O
and	O
if	O
he	O
can	O
,	O
to	O
wait	O
and	O
do	O
domestic	O
work	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
impossible	O
now	O
to	O
tell	O
how	O
much	O
English	O
he	O
knows	O
,	O
as	O
he	O
is	O
so	O
shy	O
and	O
frightened	O
when	O
he	O
trys	O
to	O
speak	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
gave	O
a	O
dinner	O
last	O
night	O
,	O
and	O
had	O
Dr.	O
Sandwith	PERSON
and	O
Peabody	ORGANIZATION
and	O
Doty	PERSON
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
and	O
I	O
had	O
a	O
delicious	O
drive	O
yesterday	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
to	O
the	O
Ghezireh	LOCATION
Palace	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
walked	O
about	O
the	O
shady	O
avenues	O
PAGE	O
79	O
and	O
among	O
the	O
flowers	O
-	O
stopping	O
to	O
return	O
the	O
visit	O
of	O
Dr.	O
Sandwith	PERSON
and	O
Mrs.	O
Sandwith	PERSON
on	O
our	O
way	O
home	O
.	O

Ghesireh	O
Palace	O
Hotel	O
.	O

Dec.	O
27	O
.	O

We	O
left	O
Shepheards	O
this	O
morning	O
and	O
came	O
over	O
here	O
,	O
to	O
escape	O
the	O
smells	O
and	O
noise	O
of	O
Cairo	LOCATION
and	O
are	O
so	O
enchanted	O
with	O
the	O
delicious	O
air	O
and	O
space	O
-	O
our	O
rooms	O
are	O
really	O
palatial	O
-	O
and	O
look	O
out	O
on	O
the	O
beautiful	O
garden	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
sitting	O
room	O
opens	O
on	O
a	O
balcony	O
,	O
which	O
the	O
present	O
hot	O
weather	O
makes	O
quite	O
delightful	O
.	O

The	O
sun	O
was	O
so	O
hot	O
this	O
afternoon	O
that	O
the	O
awning	O
was	O
necessary	O
.	O

The	O
house	O
is	O
practically	O
empty	O
-	O
and	O
it	O
is	O
so	O
enormous	O
,	O
that	O
only	O
in	O
the	O
evening	O
after	O
dinner	O
,	O
when	O
everyone	O
congregated	O
in	O
the	O
big	O
hall	O
,	O
that	O
there	O
seems	O
to	O
be	O
anyone	O
here	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
so	O
busy	O
,	O
trying	O
to	O
help	O
along	O
the	O
boat	O
-	O
and	O
there	O
are	O
so	O
many	O
vexatious	O
delays	O
,	O
that	O
our	O
patience	O
is	O
fairly	O
exhausted	O
.	O

I	O
am	O
amazed	O
at	O
Theodore	PERSON
's	O
apparent	O
patience	O
with	O
Thubron	PERSON
and	O
his	O
unprincipled	O
inefficiency	O
.	O

I	O
have	O
never	O
been	O
so	O
long	O
in	O
Cairo	LOCATION
before	O
-	O
and	O
I	O
think	O
I	O
am	O
tired	O
of	O
it	O
-	O
if	O
not	O
of	O
Cairo	LOCATION
,	O
certainly	O
of	O
the	O
life	O
of	O
hotels	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
dreary	O
people	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
nice	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
interest	O
and	O
enjoyment	O
of	O
Clarence	PERSON
and	O
Mary	PERSON
in	O
everything	O
.	O

I	O
am	O
well	O
-	O
and	O
quite	O
free	O
from	O
cold	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
in	O
Cairo	LOCATION
.	O

Jan.	O
3	O
.	O

Second	O
Sunday	O
after	O
Christmas	O
.	O

Still	O
waiting	O
impatiently	O
to	O
get	O
off	O
-	O
some	O
progress	O
has	O
been	O
made	O
during	O
the	O
past	O
week	O
to	O
be	O
sure	O
.	O

The	O
obscure	O
and	O
troublesome	O
-	O
PAGE	O
80	O
Jan.	O
9th	O
-	O
what	O
I	O
intended	O
saying	O
when	O
I	O
began	O
that	O
last	O
sentence	O
,	O
quite	O
a	O
week	O
ago	O
,	O
I	O
have	O
now	O
not	O
the	O
faintest	O
idea	O
.	O

Each	O
day	O
since	O
has	O
been	O
so	O
busy	O
,	O
with	O
tiresome	O
occupations	O
,	O
driving	O
down	O
to	O
the	O
dahabeah	O
through	O
that	O
squalid	O
Boulak-Ramleh	O
quarter	O
-	O
until	O
I	O
am	O
fairly	O
sick	O
with	O
the	O
sight	O
of	O
so	O
much	O
misery	O
that	O
no	O
one	O
can	O
relieve	O
.	O

The	O
long	O
delayed	O
furniture	O
came	O
yesterday	O
-	O
and	O
with	O
much	O
trepidation	O
I	O
saw	O
it	O
unpacked	O
,	O
and	O
if	O
my	O
worst	O
fears	O
were	O
not	O
realized	O
,	O
there	O
were	O
enough	O
disappointments	O
to	O
make	O
it	O
almost	O
unbearable	O
.	O

Chairs	O
too	O
large	O
for	O
the	O
rooms	O
-	O
everything	O
a	O
little	O
too	O
big	O
,	O
or	O
a	O
little	O
too	O
small	O
-	O
the	O
side	O
board	O
entirely	O
forgotten	O
-	O
and	O
I	O
had	O
to	O
get	O
into	O
the	O
carriage	O
with	O
Thubron	PERSON
,	O
and	O
drive	O
to	O
3	O
different	O
furniture	O
places	O
before	O
I	O
found	O
a	O
little	O
second	O
hand	O
buffet	O
that	O
freshened	O
and	O
polished	O
,	O
will	O
answer	O
for	O
this	O
winter	O
-	O
then	O
I	O
bought	O
finger	O
bowls	O
,	O
caraffes	O
-	O
liqeur	O
glasses	O
-	O
candlesticks	O
-	O
match	O
boxes	O
-	O
soap	O
dishes	O
etc.	O
etc.	O
etc.	O
.	O

Still	O
with	O
all	O
these	O
drawbacks	O
the	O
Beduin	O
is	O
so	O
comfortable	O
and	O
so	O
convenient	O
and	O
pretty	O
,	O
that	O
we	O
are	O
thoroughly	O
happy	O
that	O
on	O
Monday	O
morning	O
we	O
will	O
take	O
possession	O
of	O
her	O
,	O
and	O
at	O
last	O
start	O
up	O
the	O
river	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
had	O
real	O
Cairo	LOCATION
winter	O
weather	O
for	O
10	O
days	O
-	O
high	O
winds	O
,	O
clouds	O
,	O
occasional	O
sharp	O
rains	O
.	O

These	O
things	O
would	O
not	O
be	O
unbearable	O
-	O
were	O
it	O
not	O
for	O
the	O
discomfort	O
of	O
indoors	O
in	O
such	O
weather	O
.	O

We	O
would	O
never	O
think	O
it	O
possible	O
at	O
home	O
to	O
sit	O
in	O
a	O
room	O
where	O
the	O
thermometer	O
stood	O
at	O
62	O
°	O
only	O
.	O

But	O
my	O
thermometer	O
has	O
been	O
just	O
there	O
for	O
several	O
days	O
.	O

There	O
is	O
in	O
each	O
of	O
our	O
big	O
rooms	O
,	O
a	O
tiny	O
,	O
ornamented	O
accidental	O
fireplace	O
,	O
between	O
two	O
of	O
the	O
big	O
windows	O
-	O
these	O
are	O
strictly	O
ornamental	O
,	O
and	O
are	O
almost	O
hidden	O
by	O
the	O
magnificent	O
satin	O
draperies	O
of	O
the	O
windows	O
.	O

But	O
two	O
or	O
PAGE	O
81	O
three	O
days	O
ago	O
when	O
the	O
wind	O
was	O
high	O
and	O
cold	O
,	O
I	O
asked	O
the	O
waiter	O
if	O
we	O
could	O
have	O
a	O
fire	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
was	O
made	O
,	O
much	O
to	O
the	O
cost	O
of	O
our	O
comfort	O
,	O
for	O
the	O
only	O
draught	O
was	O
out	O
into	O
the	O
room	O
-	O
and	O
if	O
the	O
fuel	O
had	O
been	O
anything	O
but	O
charcoal	O
,	O
the	O
consequences	O
might	O
have	O
been	O
disastrous	O
-	O
as	O
it	O
was	O
,	O
all	O
the	O
wooden	O
mantle	O
was	O
scorched	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
windows	O
had	O
to	O
be	O
opened	O
to	O
clear	O
the	O
room	O
.	O

We	O
learned	O
afterwards	O
that	O
there	O
were	O
no	O
openings	O
at	O
the	O
top	O
to	O
these	O
chimneys	O
-	O
so	O
that	O
the	O
fireplaces	O
were	O
purely	O
pieces	O
of	O
ornamental	O
furniture	O
.	O

Dahabeah	O
``	O
Beduin	O
''	O
.	O

Monday	O
,	O
Jan.	O
11	O
.	O

1897	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
actually	O
in	O
possession	O
-	O
have	O
started	O
-	O
and	O
made	O
15	O
miles	O
to	O
Bedrasheen	LOCATION
,	O
where	O
we	O
are	O
now	O
lying	O
.	O

Mary	PERSON
and	O
I	O
flew	O
about	O
this	O
morning	O
doing	O
last	O
things	O
-	O
we	O
lunched	O
at	O
the	O
Gesireh	O
,	O
but	O
went	O
down	O
before	O
lunch	O
on	O
the	O
terrace	O
,	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
Beduin	O
,	O
under	O
convoy	O
of	O
the	O
tug	O
,	O
go	O
by	O
,	O
on	O
her	O
way	O
to	O
above	O
the	O
bridge	O
,	O
which	O
opens	O
at	O
one	O
o'clock	O
.	O

Just	O
as	O
we	O
reached	O
the	O
terrace	O
,	O
I	O
saw	O
away	O
down	O
the	O
river	O
,	O
the	O
tug	O
pulling	O
out	O
,	O
and	O
our	O
``	O
Beduin	O
''	O
stately	O
,	O
tall	O
,	O
and	O
shapely	O
in	O
her	O
tow	O
.	O

Several	O
people	O
gathered	O
on	O
the	O
terrace	O
to	O
see	O
her	O
go	O
by	O
-	O
and	O
I	O
heard	O
her	O
pronounced	O
the	O
``	O
handsomest	O
craft	O
on	O
the	O
river	O
''	O
.	O

Immediately	O
after	O
lunch	O
,	O
when	O
poor	O
Theodore	PERSON
had	O
finished	O
all	O
his	O
backsheeshs	O
,	O
we	O
drove	O
above	O
the	O
bridge	O
,	O
and	O
went	O
aboard	O
.	O

There	O
was	O
hurry	O
and	O
scrambling	O
for	O
15	O
minutes	O
,	O
as	O
our	O
trunks	O
were	O
literally	O
turned	O
upside	O
down	O
,	O
and	O
sent	O
back	O
empty	O
to	O
the	O
hotel	O
to	O
be	O
kept	O
for	O
us	O
,	O
until	O
we	O
came	O
down	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
midst	O
of	O
it	O
,	O
Mrs.	O
and	O
Miss	O
Taylor	PERSON
arrived	O
for	O
a	O
parting	O
visit	O
.	O

Then	O
there	O
was	O
the	O
``	O
debbil	O
to	O
pay	O
''	O
as	O
dear	O
old	O
Salah	PERSON
would	O
say	O
,	O
as	O
Theodore	PERSON
PAGE	O
82	O
discovered	O
that	O
the	O
men	O
on	O
the	O
tug	O
did	O
not	O
know	O
that	O
they	O
were	O
to	O
go	O
further	O
than	O
above	O
the	O
bridge	O
,	O
and	O
were	O
aghast	O
at	O
the	O
idea	O
of	O
taking	O
us	O
as	O
far	O
as	O
Assiut	LOCATION
;	O
they	O
had	O
no	O
food	O
-	O
no	O
blankets	O
-	O
no	O
preparations	O
,	O
but	O
go	O
they	O
had	O
to	O
,	O
and	O
with	O
many	O
a	O
heartfelt	O
blessing	O
from	O
us	O
all	O
to	O
the	O
impossible	O
Thubron	PERSON
,	O
we	O
started	O
at	O
3:40	O
this	O
P.M.	O
I	O
have	O
been	O
working	O
like	O
a	O
slave	O
all	O
the	O
afternoon	O
,	O
and	O
am	O
too	O
tired	O
to	O
see	O
or	O
think	O
,	O
but	O
we	O
are	O
happy	O
,	O
if	O
not	O
yet	O
in	O
order	O
.	O

Jan.	O
12	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
made	O
about	O
18	O
miles	O
-	O
and	O
are	O
somewhere	O
between	O
Bedreschein	LOCATION
and	O
Wasta	O
.	O

The	O
tug	O
proves	O
a	O
worthless	O
thing	O
.	O

She	O
can	O
make	O
about	O
2	O
miles	O
with	O
us	O
,	O
an	O
hour	O
,	O
without	O
any	O
assistance	O
from	O
us	O
-	O
but	O
if	O
we	O
have	O
a	O
wind	O
that	O
at	O
all	O
fills	O
our	O
sails	O
,	O
we	O
sail	O
right	O
on	O
to	O
her	O
and	O
she	O
has	O
to	O
cast	O
off	O
.	O

Various	O
``	O
désagrémens	O
''	O
have	O
developed	O
themselves	O
,	O
the	O
most	O
important	O
of	O
which	O
is	O
old	O
Henna	PERSON
,	O
our	O
cook	O
,	O
who	O
was	O
with	O
us	O
for	O
2	O
winters	O
on	O
the	O
Herodotus	ORGANIZATION
has	O
taken	O
fright	O
at	O
the	O
range	O
in	O
his	O
kitchen	O
,	O
and	O
thinks	O
he	O
can	O
do	O
nothing	O
with	O
it	O
,	O
although	O
he	O
makes	O
much	O
better	O
bread	O
with	O
it	O
,	O
than	O
I	O
have	O
ever	O
known	O
him	O
do	O
before	O
.	O

And	O
,	O
we	O
greatly	O
need	O
the	O
forgotten	O
sideboard	O
-	O
and	O
many	O
rather	O
necessary	O
things	O
have	O
been	O
overlooked	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
so	O
pretty	O
and	O
convenient	O
,	O
that	O
we	O
are	O
quite	O
ashamed	O
of	O
ourselves	O
in	O
complaining	O
of	O
anything	O
.	O

My	O
room	O
is	O
entirely	O
charming	O
-	O
and	O
so	O
are	O
all	O
the	O
bedrooms	O
in	O
their	O
pretty	O
chintzs	O
and	O
simple	O
fittings	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
saloon	O
would	O
be	O
a	O
charming	O
interior	O
anywhere	O
-	O
with	O
its	O
Morris	PERSON
green	O
brocades	O
and	O
art	O
fabrics	O
.	O

Then	O
the	O
big	O
upper	O
deck	O
is	O
entirely	O
perfection	O
,	O
with	O
its	O
pretty	O
rugs	O
,	O
its	O
big	O
brown	O
PAGE	O
83	O
wicker	O
hooded	O
chairs	O
and	O
easy	O
chairs	O
,	O
with	O
their	O
bright	O
yellow	O
and	O
black	O
cushions	O
and	O
pillows	O
in	O
bandana	O
stuffs	O
.	O

But	O
best	O
of	O
all	O
,	O
the	O
Beduin	O
has	O
proved	O
a	O
rattling	O
good	O
sailor	O
,	O
and	O
there	O
can	O
be	O
no	O
happier	O
man	O
on	O
earth	O
than	O
our	O
Rais	PERSON
Fuli	PERSON
,	O
who	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
in	O
his	O
life	O
is	O
1st	O
Captain	O
.	O

He	O
has	O
been	O
twice	O
with	O
us	O
as	O
2d	O
Captain	O
and	O
we	O
have	O
always	O
said	O
he	O
should	O
be	O
captain	O
of	O
our	O
dahabeah	O
when	O
it	O
was	O
built	O
.	O

He	O
is	O
such	O
a	O
fine	O
specimen	O
of	O
a	O
calm	O
,	O
serene	O
Mohammedan	O
,	O
and	O
has	O
a	O
gentle	O
personal	O
dignity	O
I	O
have	O
never	O
seen	O
equalled	O
.	O

He	O
is	O
a	O
Nubian	O
,	O
knows	O
the	O
river	O
thoroughly	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
could	O
trust	O
him	O
with	O
everything	O
we	O
have	O
.	O

The	O
boat	O
will	O
now	O
be	O
his	O
house	O
summer	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
winter	O
-	O
and	O
he	O
will	O
get	O
￡	O
3	O
.	O

a	O
month	O
and	O
during	O
the	O
summer	O
feed	O
himself	O
-	O
I	O
think	O
I	O
am	O
as	O
pleased	O
as	O
he	O
is	O
.	O

He	O
has	O
chosen	O
an	O
admirable	O
crew	O
-	O
I	O
never	O
saw	O
so	O
good	O
a	O
one	O
on	O
the	O
Nile	O
-	O
and	O
in	O
their	O
brown	O
cardigans	O
with	O
``	O
Beduin	O
''	O
in	O
blue	O
letters	O
across	O
the	O
breast	O
,	O
they	O
look	O
very	O
well	O
.	O

Jan.	O
13	O
.	O

Made	O
23	O
miles	O
-	O
are	O
now	O
lying	O
near	O
Wasta	LOCATION
-	O
day	O
calm	O
,	O
with	O
some	O
head	O
wind	O
-	O
heavy	O
storm	O
of	O
wind	O
during	O
the	O
night	O
-	O
very	O
busy	O
settling	O
.	O

Jan.	O
14	O
.	O

Beautiful	O
warm	O
weather	O
-	O
though	O
my	O
self-registering	O
barometer	O
on	O
my	O
little	O
verandah	O
went	O
down	O
to	O
40	O
°	O
during	O
the	O
night	O
.	O

Passed	O
Benisoef	O
about	O
noon	O
-	O
ran	O
until	O
8	O
o'clock	O
this	O
evening	O
,	O
-	O
made	O
23	O
miles	O
today	O
.	O

PAGE	O
84	O
Jan.	O
15th	O
.	O

A	O
long	O
run	O
today	O
-	O
starting	O
at	O
6	O
A.M.	O
and	O
bringing	O
up	O
at	O
7	O
o'clock	O
P.M.	O
within	O
3	O
miles	O
of	O
Golasseheh	LOCATION
-	O
busy	O
all	O
day	O
-	O
made	O
57	O
miles	O
.	O

Jan.	O
16	O
.	O

I	O
wakened	O
before	O
it	O
was	O
light	O
this	O
morning	O
and	O
heard	O
the	O
rippling	O
of	O
the	O
water	O
that	O
showed	O
how	O
fast	O
we	O
were	O
slipping	O
along	O
-	O
but	O
,	O
a	O
little	O
after	O
7	O
o'clock	O
we	O
ran	O
into	O
a	O
dense	O
fog	O
-	O
I	O
never	O
saw	O
such	O
a	O
sight	O
before	O
on	O
the	O
Nile	O
-	O
and	O
we	O
pulled	O
up	O
awhile	O
until	O
the	O
hot	O
sun	O
had	O
dissipated	O
it	O
.	O

We	O
passed	O
Minieh	PERSON
at	O
11	O
o'clock	O
-	O
and	O
Beni	PERSON
Hassan	PERSON
this	O
afternoon	O
and	O
are	O
now	O
lying	O
at	O
Rhodah	LOCATION
having	O
made	O
51	O
miles	O
.	O

Some	O
high	O
wind	O
today	O
from	O
the	O
right	O
quarter	O
-	O
and	O
we	O
have	O
had	O
to	O
cast	O
the	O
tug	O
off	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
wind	O
has	O
been	O
fitful	O
.	O

Have	O
passed	O
such	O
lovely	O
palm	O
fringed	O
shores	O
.	O

This	O
morning	O
the	O
usual	O
begging	O
saint	O
from	O
Der	O
el-Tayr	O
,	O
or	O
Mountain	O
of	O
the	O
Bird	O
,	O
swam	O
out	O
to	O
us	O
-	O
and	O
demanded	O
the	O
usual	O
toll	O
.	O

The	O
boat	O
is	O
now	O
in	O
perfect	O
order	O
-	O
and	O
I	O
am	O
now	O
resting	O
from	O
my	O
labors	O
.	O

Thermometer	O
registered	O
last	O
night	O
45	O
°	O
and	O
today	O
at	O
2	O
o'clock	O
72	O
°	O
.	O

I	O
had	O
my	O
little	O
stove	O
lighted	O
and	O
brought	O
into	O
my	O
room	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
this	O
morning	O
.	O

Jan.	O
17	O
.	O

Second	O
Sunday	O
after	O
Epiphany	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
only	O
made	O
20	O
miles	O
today	O
.	O

There	O
has	O
been	O
but	O
little	O
wind	O
,	O
and	O
what	O
there	O
was	O
,	O
from	O
the	O
wrong	O
quarter	O
.	O

Something	O
was	O
the	O
matter	O
with	O
the	O
tug	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
had	O
to	O
stop	O
for	O
3	O
hours	O
to	O
have	O
her	O
tickered	O
.	O

PAGE	O
85	O
We	O
are	O
now	O
within	O
4	O
miles	O
of	O
Gebel	LOCATION
Abou	LOCATION
Fedah	LOCATION
-	O
day	O
has	O
been	O
overcast	O
,	O
and	O
a	O
little	O
cool	O
.	O

Thermometer	O
last	O
night	O
42	O
°	O
-	O
today	O
72	O
°	O
.	O

A	O
remarkable	O
sunset	O
-	O
really	O
the	O
most	O
wonderful	O
and	O
gorgeous	O
in	O
its	O
beauty	O
I	O
ever	O
saw	O
.	O

Jan.	O
18	O
.	O

A	O
very	O
disappointing	O
day	O
.	O

Thubrons	O
wretched	O
little	O
tug	O
has	O
given	O
out	O
entirely	O
,	O
and	O
been	O
abandoned	O
by	O
us	O
.	O

The	O
Engineer	O
reported	O
early	O
this	O
morning	O
a	O
leak	O
in	O
the	O
boiler	O
-	O
but	O
as	O
that	O
has	O
been	O
the	O
case	O
for	O
several	O
days	O
,	O
it	O
seemed	O
to	O
be	O
no	O
reason	O
that	O
we	O
should	O
not	O
go	O
on	O
in	O
the	O
same	O
slow	O
way	O
.	O

So	O
Theodore	PERSON
went	O
aboard	O
the	O
tug	O
-	O
found	O
that	O
the	O
engineer	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
``	O
see	O
in	O
the	O
boiler	O
''	O
as	O
he	O
said	O
,	O
had	O
taken	O
off	O
the	O
cylinder	O
head	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
found	O
a	O
loose	O
nut	O
kicking	O
about	O
somewhere	O
,	O
and	O
said	O
if	O
he	O
moved	O
their	O
lives	O
would	O
be	O
in	O
danger	O
.	O

There	O
was	O
nothing	O
to	O
do	O
but	O
to	O
leave	O
her	O
,	O
which	O
we	O
did	O
,	O
declining	O
to	O
give	O
the	O
man	O
2	O
oars	O
as	O
he	O
wished	O
us	O
to	O
do	O
,	O
to	O
paddle	O
back	O
to	O
Cairo	LOCATION
.	O

Day	O
warm	O
and	O
beautiful	O
-	O
sailed	O
for	O
nearly	O
2	O
hours	O
in	O
a	O
very	O
light	O
wind	O
and	O
think	O
we	O
have	O
made	O
about	O
10	O
miles	O
.	O

On	O
deck	O
until	O
nearly	O
7	O
o'clock	O
,	O
watching	O
the	O
radiant	O
moon-rise	O
and	O
the	O
colors	O
on	O
the	O
Gebel	ORGANIZATION
Abu-Fedah	ORGANIZATION
chain	O
.	O

Jan.	O
19	O
.	O

We	O
began	O
tracking	O
a	O
little	O
after	O
seven	O
o'clock	O
this	O
morning	O
-	O
a	O
very	O
little	O
south	O
wind	O
made	O
it	O
hard	O
work	O
for	O
our	O
poor	O
fellows	O
-	O
but	O
in	O
spite	O
of	O
it	O
,	O
we	O
have	O
made	O
9	O
or	O
10	O
miles	O
.	O

The	O
English	O
dahabeah	O
Thames	O
passed	O
us	O
in	O
tow	O
about	O
dark	O
.	O

Our	O
people	O
inquired	O
about	O
our	O
tug	O
,	O
and	O
PAGE	O
86	O
they	O
answered	O
they	O
had	O
passed	O
her	O
near	O
Hager	PERSON
Kandil	PERSON
,	O
floating	O
down	O
to	O
Cairo	LOCATION
.	O

A	O
pleasant	O
little	O
walk	O
this	O
A.M.	O
along	O
the	O
banks	O
of	O
the	O
Bar	LOCATION
Jusef	LOCATION
canal	O
-	O
larks	O
singing	O
-	O
wheat	O
to	O
my	O
knees	O
.	O

Jan.	O
20	O
.	O

A	O
trying	O
day	O
as	O
far	O
as	O
getting	O
on	O
-	O
warm	O
,	O
still	O
and	O
a	O
haze	O
that	O
about	O
noon	O
assumed	O
a	O
rather	O
threatening	O
look	O
.	O

Our	O
fellows	O
have	O
tracked	O
and	O
pulled	O
to	O
the	O
anchor	O
-	O
and	O
in	O
this	O
fashion	O
we	O
have	O
been	O
creeping	O
past	O
the	O
Abu	LOCATION
Fedah	LOCATION
cliffs	O
this	O
afternoon	O
.	O

A	O
strong	O
north	O
wind	O
sprang	O
up	O
and	O
helped	O
us	O
along	O
,	O
though	O
the	O
weather	O
was	O
so	O
threatening	O
we	O
did	O
not	O
dare	O
hoist	O
a	O
sail	O
.	O

About	O
6	O
o'clock	O
the	O
gale	O
broke	O
upon	O
us	O
-	O
but	O
no	O
rain	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
are	O
safely	O
tied	O
up	O
for	O
the	O
night	O
under	O
the	O
lee	O
of	O
a	O
high	O
bank	O
.	O

The	O
air	O
has	O
cleared	O
and	O
the	O
moon	O
shows	O
faintly	O
from	O
a	O
veil	O
of	O
light	O
clouds	O
.	O

Jan.	O
21	O
.	O

We	O
began	O
sailing	O
at	O
8	O
o'clock	O
this	O
morning	O
with	O
a	O
strong	O
north	O
wind	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
Beduin	O
had	O
her	O
first	O
good	O
opportunity	O
to	O
test	O
her	O
true	O
sailing	O
qualities	O
.	O

She	O
behaved	O
splendidly	O
to	O
the	O
great	O
delight	O
of	O
her	O
Captain	O
and	O
her	O
crew	O
,	O
to	O
say	O
nothing	O
of	O
her	O
owner	O
.	O

She	O
sailed	O
on	O
the	O
wind	O
in	O
so	O
fine	O
a	O
fashion	O
,	O
that	O
the	O
crew	O
were	O
enthusiastic	O
.	O

I	O
found	O
the	O
wind	O
too	O
strong	O
on	O
deck	O
,	O
and	O
went	O
below	O
to	O
the	O
entrance	O
deck	O
,	O
where	O
I	O
stood	O
sometime	O
watching	O
the	O
sailors	O
,	O
who	O
were	O
laughing	O
and	O
cheering	O
apostrophising	O
the	O
wind	O
-	O
then	O
the	O
boat	O
-	O
then	O
shaking	O
hands	O
in	O
congratulation	O
.	O

We	O
careered	O
and	O
made	O
more	O
motion	O
than	O
I	O
have	O
ever	O
felt	O
on	O
the	O
PAGE	O
87	O
Nile	O
-	O
but	O
then	O
we	O
had	O
never	O
sailed	O
like	O
that	O
in	O
such	O
a	O
wind	O
before	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
midst	O
of	O
our	O
triumphal	O
progress	O
in	O
making	O
a	O
difficult	O
bend	O
of	O
the	O
river	O
we	O
came	O
in	O
collision	O
with	O
a	O
working	O
or	O
ferry	O
boat	O
,	O
anchored	O
just	O
at	O
the	O
point	O
.	O

Her	O
boom	O
scraped	O
our	O
sides	O
a	O
little	O
to	O
the	O
great	O
distress	O
of	O
Rais	PERSON
Fuli	PERSON
-	O
but	O
no	O
real	O
harm	O
done	O
.	O

In	O
swinging	O
round	O
to	O
avoid	O
as	O
much	O
as	O
possible	O
the	O
shock	O
of	O
the	O
contact	O
,	O
we	O
went	O
aground	O
on	O
the	O
sand	O
-	O
and	O
it	O
was	O
3	O
hours	O
before	O
we	O
got	O
off	O
,	O
so	O
that	O
we	O
did	O
not	O
reach	O
Assiut	LOCATION
until	O
after	O
5	O
P.M.	O
-	O
too	O
late	O
to	O
go	O
into	O
the	O
town	O
-	O
Theodore	LOCATION
,	O
Clarence	PERSON
and	O
Jones	PERSON
set	O
off	O
for	O
the	O
P.O.	O
.	O

We	O
found	O
waiting	O
for	O
us	O
,	O
the	O
2	O
tables	O
from	O
Hatoun	LOCATION
's	O
for	O
which	O
we	O
had	O
written	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
box	O
of	O
table	O
linen	O
from	O
Paris	LOCATION
.	O

The	O
``	O
Thames	O
''	O
lying	O
opposite	O
Assiut	LOCATION
.	O

We	O
made	O
about	O
30	O
miles	O
today	O
.	O

Jan.	O
22	O
.	O

Mary	PERSON
and	O
I	O
took	O
Abdul	PERSON
this	O
morning	O
,	O
and	O
rowed	O
down	O
to	O
the	O
town	O
,	O
and	O
took	O
a	O
carriage	O
there	O
.	O

We	O
made	O
a	O
few	O
little	O
purchases	O
-	O
drove	O
through	O
the	O
bazaars	O
,	O
to	O
the	O
imminent	O
risk	O
it	O
seemed	O
to	O
me	O
of	O
the	O
lives	O
of	O
everybody	O
there	O
-	O
certainly	O
to	O
their	O
great	O
discomfort	O
.	O

These	O
carriages	O
are	O
an	O
innovation	O
.	O

I	O
have	O
never	O
seen	O
them	O
before	O
.	O

In	O
trying	O
to	O
find	O
some	O
flower	O
pots	O
,	O
I	O
came	O
across	O
a	O
young	O
Egyptian	O
in	O
European	O
dress	O
,	O
who	O
got	O
into	O
the	O
carriage	O
with	O
us	O
,	O
and	O
took	O
us	O
to	O
his	O
garden	O
,	O
where	O
he	O
gave	O
us	O
everything	O
that	O
was	O
in	O
bloom	O
,	O
which	O
was	O
not	O
much	O
,	O
as	O
the	O
gardens	O
are	O
at	O
this	O
season	O
practically	O
dead	O
as	O
to	O
flowers	O
.	O

Among	O
other	O
things	O
he	O
gave	O
us	O
2	O
remarkable	O
fruits	O
I	O
had	O
never	O
seen	O
before	O
,	O
which	O
he	O
called	O
``	O
Kishta	O
''	O
or	O
cream	O
.	O

It	O
seems	O
it	O
is	O
an	O
imported	O
delicacy	O
PAGE	O
88	O
from	O
the	O
West	LOCATION
Indies	LOCATION
-	O
the	O
Anona	O
squamosa	O
.	O

I	O
got	O
my	O
pots	O
-	O
but	O
we	O
were	O
not	O
allowed	O
to	O
pay	O
for	O
anything	O
-	O
our	O
young	O
host	O
being	O
an	O
amateur	O
gardiner	O
,	O
and	O
as	O
polite	O
and	O
kind	O
as	O
he	O
could	O
be	O
.	O

After	O
many	O
thanks	O
,	O
we	O
left	O
him	O
and	O
came	O
home	O
,	O
it	O
being	O
too	O
late	O
to	O
go	O
to	O
the	O
American	ORGANIZATION
College	ORGANIZATION
as	O
I	O
had	O
intended	O
,	O
to	O
inquire	O
about	O
the	O
2	O
American	O
women	O
doctors	O
who	O
have	O
lately	O
arrived	O
and	O
about	O
whom	O
I	O
wish	O
to	O
know	O
something	O
.	O

There	O
was	O
no	O
wind	O
to	O
get	O
away	O
-	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
the	O
``	O
Ramesis	O
the	O
Great	O
''	O
from	O
up	O
the	O
river	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
''	O
Ramesis	O
''	O
from	O
Cairo	LOCATION
arrived	O
,	O
and	O
were	O
near	O
us	O
.	O

On	O
the	O
former	O
were	O
the	O
Case	O
family	O
from	O
Boston	LOCATION
,	O
people	O
who	O
were	O
on	O
the	O
Gens	O
,	O
and	O
whom	O
Theodore	PERSON
knew	O
.	O

They	O
came	O
aboard	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
Beduin	O
.	O

An	O
evening	O
of	O
wonderful	O
beauty	O
and	O
color	O
-	O
with	O
a	O
late	O
full	O
moon	O
rising	O
over	O
the	O
placid	O
water	O
.	O

There	O
are	O
splendid	O
trees	O
-	O
palms	O
and	O
scents	O
all	O
about	O
Assiut	LOCATION
.	O

Jan.	O
23d	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
still	O
in	O
sight	O
of	O
Assiut	LOCATION
-	O
though	O
we	O
have	O
made	O
5	O
miles	O
by	O
tracking	O
and	O
pulling	O
to	O
the	O
anchor	O
-	O
the	O
wind	O
when	O
there	O
was	O
any	O
,	O
being	O
dead	O
ahead	O
.	O

Mary	PERSON
and	O
I	O
have	O
been	O
spending	O
the	O
afternoon	O
on	O
my	O
pleasant	O
little	O
verandah	O
-	O
reading	O
and	O
working	O
.	O

Jan.	O
24	O
.	O

Third	O
Sunday	O
after	O
Epiphany	O
.	O

A	O
day	O
of	O
almost	O
perfect	O
calm	O
-	O
by	O
tracking	O
and	O
polling	O
and	O
using	O
the	O
occasional	O
little	O
puffs	O
of	O
wind	O
,	O
we	O
have	O
made	O
15	O
miles	O
.	O

Such	O
beautiful	O
opalescent	O
effects	O
all	O
day	O
-	O
the	O
whole	O
world	O
done	O
in	O
pearly	O
,	O
pink	O
,	O
gray	O
heat	O
.	O

PAGE	O
89	O
Jan.	O
25	O
.	O

Another	O
day	O
like	O
yesterday	O
-	O
until	O
about	O
6	O
o'clock	O
the	O
wind	O
came	O
up	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
got	O
about	O
an	O
hour	O
's	O
sailing	O
-	O
which	O
with	O
the	O
pulling	O
to	O
anchor	O
,	O
tracking	O
and	O
poling	O
,	O
brought	O
us	O
within	O
10	O
miles	O
of	O
Tahtah	LOCATION
-	O
making	O
12	O
miles	O
altogether	O
.	O

The	O
Mena	ORGANIZATION
,	O
flying	O
the	O
English	O
flag	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
Elephantine	O
flying	O
the	O
French	O
flag	O
,	O
passed	O
us	O
today	O
-	O
and	O
tonight	O
we	O
are	O
tied	O
up	O
just	O
above	O
the	O
latter	O
.	O

Mercury	O
today	O
-	O
80	O
°	O
.	O

Jan.	O
26	O
.	O

A	O
more	O
successful	O
day	O
-	O
a	O
good	O
wind	O
this	O
afternoon	O
having	O
brought	O
us	O
30	O
miles	O
and	O
we	O
are	O
tonight	O
5	O
miles	O
from	O
Sohag	LOCATION
-	O
passed	O
Tahtah	LOCATION
at	O
3	O
this	O
afternoon	O
-	O
I	O
have	O
been	O
the	O
whole	O
day	O
on	O
deck	O
-	O
very	O
hot	O
,	O
very	O
bright	O
-	O
flies	O
tormenting	O
-	O
but	O
an	O
air	O
,	O
pure	O
,	O
warm	O
and	O
exhilerating	O
,	O
that	O
seems	O
to	O
renew	O
one	O
's	O
life	O
-	O
and	O
such	O
colouring	O
!	O

The	O
great	O
cliffs	O
of	O
El	LOCATION
Haradeh	LOCATION
have	O
been	O
near	O
us	O
all	O
day	O
-	O
their	O
soft	O
yellow	O
,	O
with	O
heliotrope	O
,	O
and	O
ashes	O
of	O
roses	O
shadows	O
.	O

It	O
seems	O
a	O
bad	O
employment	O
of	O
time	O
to	O
read	O
,	O
or	O
work	O
,	O
or	O
look	O
at	O
anything	O
but	O
this	O
strange	O
country	O
-	O
with	O
its	O
simplicity	O
of	O
feature	O
,	O
the	O
changing	O
life	O
of	O
the	O
banks	O
of	O
the	O
river	O
,	O
-	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
interesting	O
things	O
is	O
the	O
ferry	O
boats	O
-	O
with	O
their	O
loads	O
of	O
men	O
,	O
women	O
,	O
children	O
,	O
and	O
every	O
description	O
of	O
animal	O
.	O

They	O
are	O
common	O
working	O
sail	O
boats	O
-	O
their	O
sails	O
sometimes	O
so	O
tattered	O
and	O
chiffonnée	O
that	O
one	O
wonders	O
there	O
can	O
be	O
any	O
propelling	O
power	O
about	O
them	O
.	O

Then	O
they	O
can	O
not	O
often	O
approach	O
the	O
low	O
shores	O
,	O
and	O
men	O
and	O
women	O
unceremoniously	O
kilt	O
up	O
their	O
clothes	O
and	O
wade	O
to	O
shore	O
,	O
driving	O
their	O
animals	O
before	O
them	O
,	O
or	O
dragging	O
them	O
PAGE	O
90	O
after	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
no	O
unusual	O
thing	O
to	O
see	O
donkeys	O
lifted	O
bodily	O
into	O
these	O
boats	O
and	O
the	O
other	O
day	O
we	O
were	O
much	O
diverted	O
by	O
seeing	O
3	O
camels	O
,	O
scolding	O
their	O
protests	O
,	O
lifted	O
in	O
as	O
it	O
were	O
in	O
sections	O
,	O
-	O
one	O
leg	O
at	O
a	O
time	O
.	O

Jan.	O
27	O
.	O

Started	O
this	O
morning	O
in	O
a	O
strong	O
wind	O
and	O
came	O
to	O
Sohag	LOCATION
just	O
as	O
breakfast	O
was	O
ready	O
.	O

Most	O
of	O
the	O
male	O
population	O
of	O
this	O
good	O
looking	O
thriving	O
town	O
were	O
ranged	O
along	O
the	O
bank	O
above	O
us	O
-	O
we	O
had	O
to	O
stop	O
for	O
mail	O
and	O
butter	O
,	O
which	O
took	O
about	O
an	O
hour	O
-	O
and	O
in	O
the	O
mean	O
time	O
we	O
bought	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
bright	O
Akmim	O
cloths	O
which	O
a	O
merchant	O
was	O
displaying	O
on	O
the	O
bank	O
.	O

They	O
used	O
to	O
be	O
made	O
in	O
Akmim	LOCATION
,	O
but	O
I	O
suspect	O
they	O
more	O
often	O
now	O
,	O
come	O
from	O
Birmingham	LOCATION
,	O
England	LOCATION
.	O

The	O
river	O
here	O
makes	O
a	O
very	O
bad	O
turn	O
,	O
and	O
north	O
and	O
south	O
seem	O
to	O
change	O
places	O
.	O

We	O
came	O
to	O
grief	O
here	O
once	O
before	O
in	O
the	O
Herodotus	O
-	O
and	O
again	O
this	O
morning	O
,	O
our	O
delay	O
of	O
an	O
hour	O
resulted	O
in	O
staying	O
all	O
day	O
near	O
Sohag	LOCATION
-	O
for	O
the	O
strong	O
wind	O
at	O
last	O
found	O
us	O
on	O
shore	O
about	O
2	O
miles	O
above	O
the	O
town	O
-	O
and	O
opposite	O
Akmim	O
.	O

The	O
wind	O
blew	O
a	O
hurricane	O
all	O
day	O
-	O
and	O
all	O
windows	O
and	O
doors	O
had	O
to	O
be	O
closed	O
to	O
keep	O
out	O
the	O
driving	O
fine	O
sand	O
.	O

Towards	O
evening	O
we	O
pulled	O
to	O
the	O
anchor	O
across	O
the	O
river	O
near	O
Akmim	LOCATION
-	O
and	O
would	O
rather	O
have	O
been	O
above	O
than	O
below	O
the	O
town	O
-	O
as	O
the	O
cholera	O
raged	O
at	O
this	O
place	O
during	O
the	O
summer	O
.	O

Made	O
9	O
miles	O
.	O

Jan.	O
28	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
made	O
35	O
miles	O
today	O
-	O
beginning	O
at	O
6:30	O
o'clock	O
with	O
a	O
PAGE	O
91	O
fair	O
wind	O
that	O
grew	O
so	O
strong	O
we	O
had	O
to	O
lie	O
by	O
at	O
Balliana	LOCATION
for	O
more	O
than	O
2	O
hours	O
.	O

Jan.	O
29	O
.	O

With	O
the	O
exception	O
of	O
Jan.	O
15	O
,	O
we	O
have	O
made	O
today	O
our	O
best	O
record	O
-	O
49	O
miles	O
-	O
and	O
are	O
lying	O
tonight	O
near	O
Keneh	LOCATION
.	O

Passed	O
the	O
Philetus	O
-	O
like	O
a	O
dream	O
.	O

Jan.	O
30	O
.	O

A	O
good	O
wind	O
this	O
morning	O
then	O
sailed	O
and	O
tracked	O
until	O
we	O
tied	O
up	O
for	O
the	O
night	O
,	O
having	O
made	O
32	O
miles	O
.	O

Jan.	O
31	O
.	O

Luxor	LOCATION
.	O

Fourth	O
Sunday	O
after	O
Epiphany	O
.	O

We	O
made	O
the	O
intervening	O
12	O
miles	O
between	O
our	O
landing	O
place	O
of	O
last	O
night	O
and	O
Luxor	LOCATION
at	O
4:30	O
-	O
having	O
had	O
a	O
variable	O
light	O
wind	O
all	O
day	O
-	O
sometimes	O
no	O
wind	O
,	O
when	O
we	O
tracked	O
and	O
poled	O
.	O

About	O
11	O
o'clock	O
,	O
we	O
descried	O
the	O
streamer	O
of	O
a	O
dahabieh	O
in	O
the	O
distance	O
-	O
then	O
her	O
sails	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
sails	O
of	O
3	O
more	O
-	O
to	O
our	O
great	O
delight	O
as	O
we	O
have	O
been	O
thirsting	O
for	O
a	O
foe	O
worthy	O
of	O
our	O
steel	O
.	O

We	O
crept	O
slowly	O
along	O
towards	O
them	O
,	O
making	O
Luxor	LOCATION
the	O
same	O
time	O
as	O
the	O
Manhattan	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
just	O
behind	O
the	O
Zenet-el	O
Nil	O
,	O
the	O
Sesostris	O
and	O
the	O
Ammon	PERSON
Ra	PERSON
-	O
in	O
front	O
of	O
which	O
last	O
we	O
tied	O
up	O
,	O
just	O
below	O
the	O
Castle	O
.	O

The	O
rest	O
went	O
into	O
the	O
town	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
stayed	O
to	O
enjoy	O
the	O
quiet	O
of	O
our	O
dahabeah	O
and	O
our	O
beautiful	O
deck	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
wonders	O
of	O
the	O
setting	O
sun	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
shadows	O
creeping	O
over	O
the	O
mountains	O
.	O

Heaps	O
of	O
letters	O
and	O
newspapers	O
.	O

PAGE	O
92	O
Feb.	O
3	O
.	O

Luxor	LOCATION
.	O

We	O
have	O
had	O
a	O
tremendously	O
high	O
wind	O
for	O
2	O
days	O
-	O
yesterday	O
neither	O
Mary	PERSON
nor	O
I	O
stirred	O
from	O
the	O
boat	O
.	O

Although	O
protected	O
by	O
the	O
high	O
bank	O
,	O
we	O
were	O
really	O
buffetted	O
about	O
and	O
the	O
waves	O
race	O
high	O
-	O
everything	O
was	O
kept	O
closed	O
-	O
doors	O
,	O
windows	O
,	O
screens	O
and	O
tambooshes	O
-	O
but	O
in	O
spite	O
of	O
all	O
the	O
dust	O
penetrated	O
everywhere	O
-	O
though	O
to	O
a	O
much	O
less	O
degree	O
than	O
in	O
any	O
other	O
boat	O
I	O
have	O
been	O
on	O
.	O

Across	O
the	O
river	O
,	O
the	O
sand	O
obscured	O
the	O
sight	O
of	O
the	O
mountains	O
at	O
times	O
-	O
and	O
I	O
was	O
sorry	O
for	O
the	O
Cookites	O
,	O
who	O
were	O
swarming	O
on	O
the	O
sands	O
,	O
starting	O
for	O
their	O
various	O
excursions	O
-	O
for	O
2	O
or	O
3	O
steamers	O
are	O
in	O
-	O
and	O
of	O
course	O
their	O
passengers	O
can	O
not	O
wait	O
for	O
more	O
favorable	O
weather	O
.	O

Mary	PERSON
and	O
I	O
this	O
morning	O
climbed	O
up	O
the	O
high	O
bank	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
intention	O
of	O
walking	O
back	O
into	O
the	O
country	O
-	O
but	O
our	O
skirts	O
blew	O
over	O
our	O
heads	O
,	O
our	O
hats	O
off	O
our	O
heads	O
-	O
and	O
our	O
eyes	O
were	O
blinded	O
with	O
sand	O
-	O
so	O
that	O
we	O
soon	O
gave	O
up	O
the	O
contest	O
and	O
came	O
home	O
,	O
glad	O
to	O
finish	O
our	O
walk	O
on	O
the	O
sheltered	O
deck	O
.	O

Salah	PERSON
came	O
to	O
see	O
us	O
soon	O
after	O
our	O
arrival	O
,	O
very	O
proud	O
of	O
us	O
,	O
and	O
of	O
our	O
sailing	O
record	O
.	O

He	O
is	O
almost	O
willing	O
to	O
let	O
us	O
beat	O
his	O
Zenet-el	PERSON
Nil	PERSON
-	PERSON
M.	PERSON
Goleinschief	PERSON
's	O
boat	O
,	O
of	O
which	O
he	O
has	O
charge	O
.	O

Old	O
Mohammed	PERSON
Mohassib	PERSON
also	O
came	O
one	O
evening	O
-	O
excessively	O
pleased	O
-	O
and	O
we	O
presented	O
our	O
little	O
gifts	O
to	O
him	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
reports	O
Karnak	LOCATION
in	O
the	O
hands	O
of	O
the	O
Excavation	ORGANIZATION
Society	ORGANIZATION
-	O
I	O
have	O
not	O
yet	O
seen	O
it	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Baldwin	PERSON
who	O
is	O
on	O
the	O
Ammon-Ra	O
,	O
with	O
his	O
wife	O
,	O
and	O
son-in-law	O
,	O
Dr.	O
Grinell	PERSON
-	O
was	O
here	O
today	O
.	O

Mrs.	O
Baldwin	PERSON
is	O
very	O
wretched	O
since	O
she	O
came	O
on	O
the	O
river	O
.	O

They	O
want	O
us	O
to	O
start	O
for	O
Assouan	PERSON
when	O
they	O
do	O
.	O

The	O
Fell	O
party	O
on	O
the	O
Zenet-el-Fil	O
go	O
back	O
to	O
Cairo	LOCATION
from	O
here	O
-	O
much	O
to	O
Salah	PERSON
's	O
PAGE	O
93	O
disgust	O
.	O

This	O
morning	O
we	O
had	O
a	O
visit	O
from	O
Rev.	O
Mr.	O
Huhatt	PERSON
-	O
the	O
English	O
clergyman	O
at	O
Luxor	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
Mr.	O
Coulson	PERSON
-	O
they	O
begged	O
us	O
to	O
go	O
to	O
the	O
Luxor	LOCATION
Hotel	LOCATION
to	O
a	O
``	O
Cinderella	O
Fancy	O
Dress	O
''	O
Ball	O
for	O
the	O
benefit	O
of	O
the	O
little	O
Hospital	O
here	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
made	O
no	O
promises	O
,	O
but	O
took	O
several	O
tickets	O
.	O

Ramadan	O
begins	O
today	O
-	O
very	O
early	O
this	O
year	O
.	O

Luxor	LOCATION
.	O

Feb.	O
5	O
.	O

Yesterday	O
afternoon	O
we	O
rode	O
over	O
to	O
Medinet	PERSON
Habout	PERSON
-	O
very	O
warm	O
going	O
-	O
this	O
splendid	O
temple	O
has	O
been	O
much	O
excavated	O
since	O
I	O
saw	O
it	O
last	O
.	O

Today	O
we	O
had	O
our	O
photographs	O
taken	O
by	O
old	O
Beato	PERSON
,	O
who	O
afterwards	O
came	O
into	O
the	O
boat	O
to	O
see	O
it	O
-	O
and	O
was	O
loud	O
in	O
praises	O
of	O
it	O
.	O

Then	O
we	O
pulled	O
across	O
the	O
river	O
to	O
the	O
gizereh	O
,	O
and	O
went	O
again	O
to	O
Medinet	PERSON
,	O
where	O
we	O
had	O
lunch	O
-	O
and	O
afterwards	O
rode	O
over	O
the	O
burning	O
desert	O
to	O
Der	LOCATION
el	LOCATION
Bahari	LOCATION
-	O
leaving	O
Mary	PERSON
at	O
Medinet	PERSON
to	O
finish	O
her	O
sketches	O
It	O
was	O
very	O
hot	O
-	O
and	O
I	O
am	O
well	O
tired	O
tonight	O
.	O

Feb.	O
6	O
.	O

We	O
did	O
not	O
much	O
want	O
to	O
leave	O
Luxor	LOCATION
this	O
morning	O
-	O
but	O
as	O
Mrs.	O
Baldwin	PERSON
has	O
religious	O
scruples	O
about	O
starting	O
on	O
Sunday	O
-	O
it	O
was	O
today	O
or	O
next	O
week	O
-	O
and	O
as	O
Theodore	PERSON
is	O
anxious	O
to	O
test	O
the	O
sailing	O
qualities	O
of	O
the	O
Beduin	O
with	O
the	O
Ammon-Re	O
,	O
Cooks	O
best	O
and	O
largest	O
boat	O
,	O
we	O
left	O
about	O
noon	O
,	O
twenty	O
minutes	O
or	O
more	O
after	O
they	O
were	O
under	O
way	O
-	O
the	O
wind	O
was	O
very	O
light	O
,	O
but	O
in	O
an	O
hour	O
we	O
had	O
easily	O
overtaken	O
and	O
passed	O
her	O
,	O
to	O
the	O
intense	O
disgust	O
of	O
her	O
men	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
delight	O
of	O
our	O
own	O
.	O

Indeed	O
Rais	PERSON
Fuli	PERSON
,	O
with	O
his	O
calm	O
,	O
serene	O
manner	O
repressed	O
the	O
too	O
PAGE	O
94	O
exultant	O
manner	O
of	O
our	O
men	O
-	O
though	O
it	O
must	O
have	O
been	O
the	O
triumph	O
of	O
his	O
own	O
life	O
.	O

About	O
6	O
o'clock	O
after	O
much	O
tracking	O
we	O
pulled	O
up	O
near	O
Erment	LOCATION
where	O
we	O
now	O
are	O
.	O

I	O
was	O
rather	O
sorry	O
to	O
leave	O
Luxor	LOCATION
so	O
soon	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
one	O
very	O
busy	O
day	O
while	O
there	O
-	O
to	O
Karnak	LOCATION
in	O
the	O
morning	O
-	O
the	O
races	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
-	O
Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Huhatt	PERSON
,	O
Mr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Brown	PERSON
-	O
Miss	O
Scott	O
-	O
and	O
Miss	O
Norton	PERSON
,	O
to	O
tea	O
at	O
5	O
o'clock	O
,	O
and	O
Laura	PERSON
Billings	PERSON
and	O
her	O
sister	O
and	O
Mr.	O
Fahenstock	PERSON
of	O
New	LOCATION
York	LOCATION
to	O
dine	O
in	O
the	O
evening	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
a	O
lovely	O
dinner	O
-	O
and	O
I	O
had	O
some	O
splendid	O
red	O
roses	O
from	O
the	O
Luxor	LOCATION
Hotel	LOCATION
.	O

This	O
morning	O
before	O
leaving	O
,	O
I	O
went	O
to	O
the	O
Roman	O
Catholic	O
Italian	O
Convent	O
,	O
to	O
see	O
if	O
it	O
were	O
possible	O
to	O
arrange	O
for	O
Zenobia	PERSON
,	O
my	O
little	O
arab	O
child	O
here	O
in	O
whom	O
we	O
have	O
been	O
much	O
interested	O
,	O
to	O
enter	O
the	O
school	O
.	O

I	O
had	O
an	O
interview	O
with	O
the	O
Mother	O
Superior	O
,	O
or	O
rather	O
Mary	PERSON
had	O
,	O
for	O
she	O
could	O
speak	O
only	O
Italian	O
.	O

We	O
found	O
the	O
cleanest	O
,	O
quietest	O
place	O
I	O
have	O
ever	O
seen	O
in	O
Luxor	LOCATION
-	O
pleasant	O
airy	O
courts	O
,	O
good	O
gardens	O
-	O
and	O
everything	O
so	O
spotlessly	O
clean	O
-	O
the	O
the	O
Superior	O
herself	O
,	O
clean	O
,	O
fat	O
and	O
sweet	O
as	O
she	O
could	O
be	O
-	O
and	O
strongly	O
reminding	O
us	O
of	O
``	O
The	O
Abbess	O
''	O
of	O
Moroni	LOCATION
-	O
a	O
photograph	O
of	O
which	O
I	O
brought	O
with	O
me	O
from	O
home	O
.	O

Zenobia	PERSON
,	O
her	O
father	O
,	O
and	O
her	O
sister	O
,	O
now	O
married	O
-	O
the	O
sweet	O
child	O
of	O
2	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
were	O
at	O
the	O
boat	O
this	O
morning	O
.	O

The	O
sister	O
well	O
clothed	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
usual	O
Arab	O
fashion	O
-	O
veiled	O
as	O
becomes	O
a	O
married	O
woman	O
-	O
and	O
Zenobia	PERSON
as	O
pretty	O
and	O
taking	O
,	O
and	O
round	O
and	O
brown	O
,	O
as	O
she	O
used	O
to	O
be	O
.	O

I	O
fear	O
it	O
will	O
be	O
impossible	O
to	O
get	O
her	O
into	O
the	O
Italian	O
school	O
-	O
but	O
I	O
may	O
succeed	O
with	O
the	O
American	O
Mission	O
school	O
when	O
I	O
go	O
down	O
.	O

I	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
lift	O
the	O
child	O
somewhat	O
out	O
of	O
her	O
dirt	O
and	O
poverty	O
.	O

For	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
at	O
Luxor	LOCATION
,	O
I	O
rode	O
in	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
carriages	O
,	O
PAGE	O
95	O
2	O
or	O
3	O
of	O
which	O
are	O
supplied	O
by	O
the	O
Hotel	ORGANIZATION
-	O
and	O
I	O
felt	O
almost	O
ashamed	O
of	O
myself	O
-	O
one	O
does	O
n't	O
like	O
to	O
see	O
such	O
unnecessary	O
innovations	O
.	O

Feb.	O
7	O
.	O

Fifth	O
Sunday	O
after	O
Epiphany	O
.	O

We	O
stopped	O
a	O
short	O
time	O
at	O
the	O
Erment	O
garden	O
to	O
get	O
oranges	O
and	O
lemons	O
this	O
morning	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
Ammon-Ra	O
passed	O
ahead	O
-	O
light	O
wind	O
and	O
calms	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
day	O
.	O

We	O
overtook	O
the	O
Ammon-Ra	O
and	O
sailed	O
her	O
out	O
of	O
sight	O
.	O

Tied	O
up	O
at	O
Esneh	LOCATION
at	O
7:30	O
-	O
but	O
the	O
wind	O
coming	O
out	O
strong	O
at	O
9	O
o'clock	O
,	O
we	O
pulled	O
up	O
our	O
stakes	O
,	O
and	O
were	O
off	O
and	O
did	O
not	O
stop	O
until	O
one	O
o'clock	O
,	O
when	O
we	O
pulled	O
up	O
at	O
Al-Kab	O
having	O
made	O
in	O
all	O
41	O
miles	O
.	O

The	O
nights	O
have	O
now	O
a	O
wonderful	O
beauty	O
.	O

A	O
little	O
new	O
moon	O
appeared	O
3	O
nights	O
ago	O
-	O
and	O
Venus	PERSON
is	O
resplendent	O
-	O
and	O
so	O
is	O
Sirius	ORGANIZATION
.	O

Yesterday	O
and	O
today	O
warm	O
.	O

Feb.	O
8th	O
.	O

Did	O
not	O
sail	O
early	O
this	O
morning	O
-	O
and	O
as	O
we	O
began	O
tracking	O
about	O
11	O
,	O
the	O
Ammon-Ra	O
appeared	O
in	O
sight	O
.	O

At	O
2	O
o'clock	O
we	O
pulled	O
up	O
at	O
Al-Kab	O
,	O
to	O
see	O
Mr.	O
Somers-Clarke	PERSON
-	O
who	O
is	O
living	O
there	O
on	O
his	O
dahabeah	O
at	O
work	O
at	O
excavations	O
.	O

He	O
came	O
on	O
the	O
Beduin	O
for	O
a	O
short	O
visit	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
was	O
quite	O
an	O
hour	O
before	O
we	O
got	O
away	O
,	O
the	O
A.R.	O
being	O
by	O
that	O
time	O
more	O
than	O
a	O
mile	O
in	O
advance	O
-	O
before	O
an	O
hour	O
had	O
gone	O
by	O
,	O
we	O
had	O
caught	O
and	O
passed	O
her	O
.	O

Passed	O
Edfou	O
about	O
5	O
o'clock	O
-	O
what	O
beautiful	O
wide	O
country	O
-	O
what	O
splendid	O
great	O
domes	O
of	O
sycamore	O
trees	O
!	O

We	O
have	O
come	O
about	O
5	O
miles	O
above	O
Edfou	LOCATION
-	O
and	O
have	O
made	O
24	O
miles	O
today	O
.	O

The	O
Beduin	O
seems	O
to	O
sail	O
almost	O
without	O
wind	O
-	O
so	O
smoothly	O
she	O
glided	O
along	O
PAGE	O
96	O
mile	O
after	O
mile	O
this	O
evening	O
,	O
through	O
the	O
glittering	O
moon	O
lit	O
water	O
,	O
without	O
a	O
ripple	O
,	O
other	O
than	O
she	O
made	O
.	O

Feb.	O
9	O
.	O

I	O
do	O
not	O
know	O
how	O
we	O
have	O
made	O
23	O
miles	O
today	O
-	O
it	O
has	O
been	O
so	O
calm	O
with	O
so	O
little	O
wind	O
-	O
but	O
at	O
7	O
o'clock	O
we	O
passed	O
Silsilis	O
,	O
and	O
are	O
now	O
lying	O
2	O
miles	O
above	O
-	O
such	O
a	O
perfect	O
night	O
and	O
so	O
warm	O
.	O

We	O
crept	O
silently	O
along	O
by	O
the	O
dangerous	O
Silsileh	O
rocks	O
,	O
as	O
it	O
was	O
growing	O
dark	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
never	O
saw	O
a	O
more	O
beautiful	O
scene	O
-	O
the	O
water	O
without	O
a	O
ripple	O
-	O
everything	O
bathed	O
in	O
moonlight	O
-	O
and	O
Venus	PERSON
almost	O
as	O
bright	O
as	O
the	O
moon	O
.	O

Ammon-Ra	O
came	O
up	O
later	O
and	O
tied	O
up	O
behind	O
us	O
-	O
and	O
before	O
we	O
had	O
finished	O
dinner	O
Dr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Grinell	PERSON
came	O
over	O
.	O

Busy	O
all	O
day	O
,	O
writing	O
and	O
working	O
,	O
having	O
succeeded	O
in	O
rousing	O
myself	O
out	O
of	O
my	O
long	O
indolence	O
.	O

Feb.	O
10	O
.	O

A	O
hot	O
calm	O
day	O
-	O
a	O
little	O
tracking	O
this	O
A.M.	O
then	O
laid	O
up	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
Ammon-Ra	O
just	O
behind	O
us	O
.	O

Thermometer	O
at	O
86	O
°	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
.	O

At	O
7	O
came	O
a	O
good	O
wind	O
and	O
we	O
were	O
off	O
,	O
and	O
sailed	O
until	O
9	O
o'clock	O
-	O
2	O
miles	O
above	O
Kom	LOCATION
Ombo	LOCATION
which	O
was	O
beautiful	O
as	O
we	O
passed	O
it	O
in	O
the	O
moonlight	O
-	O
made	O
15	O
miles	O
.	O

Feb.	O
11	O
.	O

Thuesday	O
.	O

Assouan	O
.	O

Arrived	O
at	O
10:30	O
this	O
morning	O
-	O
having	O
started	O
at	O
6	O
o'clock	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
Ammon-Ra	O
and	O
Manhattan	LOCATION
within	O
sight	O
behind	O
us	O
-	O
and	O
made	O
23	O
miles	O
in	O
4	O
hours	O
-	O
having	O
lost	O
sight	O
of	O
both	O
boats	O
.	O

Passed	O
the	O
Gazelle	O
PAGE	O
97	O
just	O
below	O
Assouan	LOCATION
on	O
her	O
way	O
down	O
.	O

Found	O
the	O
``	O
Sesestris	O
''	O
,	O
``	O
Istan	O
''	O
,	O
``	O
Philetus	O
''	O
and	O
``	O
Thames	O
''	O
here	O
at	O
Elephantine	O
-	O
and	O
now	O
that	O
the	O
``	O
Ammon-Ra	O
''	O
and	O
``	O
Manhattan	LOCATION
''	O
have	O
arrived	O
,	O
we	O
make	O
7	O
dahabeahs	O
here	O
.	O

The	O
Philetus	O
started	O
this	O
afternoon	O
for	O
the	O
ascent	O
of	O
the	O
Cataract	O
.	O

Sailed	O
in	O
the	O
felucca	O
towards	O
the	O
Cataract	O
,	O
rowing	O
home	O
.	O

This	O
scenery	O
and	O
these	O
rocks	O
never	O
lose	O
in	O
vividness	O
of	O
expression	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
same	O
beautiful	O
afterglow	O
,	O
that	O
I	O
always	O
associate	O
with	O
Assouan	PERSON
.	O

Feb.	O
12	O
.	O

Went	O
over	O
to	O
Philae	O
by	O
train	O
-	O
Mary	PERSON
and	O
I	O
-	O
with	O
all	O
our	O
entourage	O
of	O
servants	O
and	O
sailors	O
and	O
hampers	O
-	O
Theodore	PERSON
and	O
Clarence	PERSON
following	O
later	O
on	O
their	O
donkeys	O
,	O
in	O
time	O
for	O
lunch	O
.	O

I	O
found	O
Yemma	PERSON
waiting	O
for	O
me	O
,	O
having	O
heard	O
through	O
one	O
of	O
our	O
sailors	O
that	O
we	O
would	O
arrive	O
.	O

He	O
is	O
little	O
grown	O
-	O
and	O
is	O
really	O
a	O
very	O
efficient	O
little	O
guide	O
-	O
Dendowi	O
too	O
,	O
the	O
unapproachable	O
-	O
who	O
appropriated	O
Mary	PERSON
for	O
the	O
day	O
.	O

Newmans	O
not	O
here	O
this	O
year	O
.	O

Mary	PERSON
at	O
once	O
selected	O
an	O
eligible	O
spot	O
for	O
painting	O
and	O
set	O
to	O
work	O
-	O
and	O
after	O
wandering	O
about	O
and	O
photographing	O
all	O
the	O
children	O
and	O
Mohammet	PERSON
the	O
sailor	O
,	O
I	O
established	O
myself	O
in	O
the	O
long	O
colonnade	O
near	O
Mary	PERSON
,	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
sun	O
,	O
and	O
wind	O
-	O
and	O
read	O
-	O
while	O
Jones	PERSON
and	O
Ibrahim	PERSON
got	O
the	O
lunch	O
ready	O
-	O
I	O
made	O
Yemma	PERSON
and	O
the	O
children	O
sing	O
for	O
me	O
-	O
and	O
when	O
I	O
grew	O
tired	O
of	O
their	O
shouting	O
,	O
I	O
begged	O
them	O
to	O
sing	O
me	O
something	O
soft	O
and	O
low	O
-	O
and	O
they	O
sang	O
squatted	O
on	O
the	O
ground	O
about	O
me	O
,	O
the	O
song	O
I	O
always	O
call	O
the	O
cataract	O
song	O
-	O
as	O
one	O
hears	O
it	O
about	O
here	O
all	O
the	O
time	O
-	O
they	O
sang	O
it	O
softly	O
-	O
in	O
a	O
constantly	O
recurring	O
refrain	O
,	O
putting	O
their	O
heads	O
on	O
their	O
hand	O
to	O
express	O
PAGE	O
98	O
sleep	O
-	O
I	O
asked	O
Yemma	PERSON
what	O
the	O
song	O
was	O
,	O
and	O
they	O
all	O
replied	O
that	O
it	O
was	O
the	O
``	O
Dongola	LOCATION
``	O
song	O
-	O
and	O
when	O
I	O
asked	O
what	O
it	O
meant	O
,	O
Yemma	PERSON
replied	O
that	O
it	O
was	O
a	O
slumber	O
song	O
-LRB-	O
though	O
of	O
course	O
these	O
are	O
not	O
his	O
words	O
-RRB-	O
that	O
the	O
mother	O
was	O
singing	O
the	O
baby	O
to	O
sleep	O
-	O
and	O
was	O
telling	O
him	O
not	O
to	O
be	O
afraid	O
,	O
although	O
there	O
was	O
war	O
and	O
fighting	O
in	O
Dongola	LOCATION
,	O
here	O
it	O
was	O
safe	O
and	O
quiet	O
-	O
to	O
sleep	O
and	O
not	O
fear	O
.	O

I	O
thought	O
it	O
very	O
pretty	O
,	O
but	O
I	O
believe	O
one	O
song	O
is	O
used	O
for	O
various	O
words	O
.	O

After	O
lunch	O
we	O
walked	O
about	O
,	O
and	O
climbed	O
to	O
the	O
roof	O
of	O
the	O
temple	O
-	O
where	O
of	O
course	O
the	O
views	O
were	O
delicious	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
birds	O
eye	O
view	O
of	O
the	O
island	O
gave	O
a	O
very	O
good	O
idea	O
of	O
the	O
extent	O
of	O
Capt.	O
Lyons	PERSON
work	O
and	O
explorations	O
of	O
last	O
year	O
.	O

Dr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Grinnell	PERSON
also	O
lunched	O
out	O
there	O
but	O
they	O
were	O
in	O
Pharaoh	O
's	O
Bed	O
.	O

We	O
came	O
home	O
by	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
Cataract	O
boats	O
-	O
bringing	O
Yemma	PERSON
and	O
Dendowi	PERSON
with	O
us	O
to	O
show	O
them	O
the	O
boat	O
-	O
then	O
sent	O
them	O
back	O
.	O

They	O
were	O
such	O
amusing	O
little	O
guests	O
.	O

Feb	O
17	O
.	O

Before	O
5	O
o'clock	O
this	O
morning	O
,	O
I	O
heard	O
the	O
preparations	O
for	O
departure	O
.	O

Our	O
splendid	O
big	O
boom	O
was	O
taken	O
down	O
the	O
day	O
we	O
spent	O
at	O
Philae	O
-	O
and	O
for	O
2	O
or	O
3	O
days	O
the	O
boat	O
has	O
been	O
getting	O
ready	O
for	O
her	O
downward	O
journey	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
had	O
a	O
lovely	O
week	O
at	O
Assouan	LOCATION
-	O
the	O
pleasantest	O
I	O
have	O
ever	O
known	O
-	O
at	O
our	O
same	O
old	O
landing	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
same	O
views	O
before	O
us	O
,	O
we	O
felt	O
quite	O
at	O
home	O
.	O

Assouan	PERSON
has	O
greatly	O
improved	O
since	O
we	O
were	O
here	O
,	O
the	O
river	O
front	O
has	O
been	O
faced	O
with	O
stone	O
,	O
and	O
steps	O
made	O
here	O
and	O
there	O
to	O
the	O
water	O
.	O

The	O
main	O
street	O
following	O
the	O
river	O
bank	O
is	O
now	O
clean	O
,	O
and	O
quite	O
well	O
built	O
,	O
with	O
some	O
good	O
government	O
houses	O
,	O
PAGE	O
99	O
which	O
with	O
the	O
hotel	O
,	O
give	O
a	O
very	O
bright	O
,	O
clean	O
look	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
very	O
quiet	O
almost	O
no	O
soldiers	O
at	O
the	O
garrison	O
-	O
all	O
having	O
gone	O
to	O
the	O
front	O
.	O

I	O
like	O
the	O
air	O
here	O
better	O
than	O
any	O
place	O
along	O
the	O
river	O
-	O
it	O
is	O
so	O
pure	O
and	O
so	O
entirely	O
from	O
the	O
desert	O
,	O
there	O
being	O
so	O
little	O
vegetation	O
here	O
.	O

A	O
day	O
or	O
two	O
after	O
we	O
arrived	O
,	O
Prof.	O
Sayce	PERSON
and	O
Lord	O
Fitz-Hardinge	PERSON
came	O
to	O
call	O
.	O

The	O
Fitz-Hardinges	O
have	O
the	O
little	O
Thames	O
which	O
they	O
built	O
years	O
ago	O
-	O
and	O
Prof.	O
Sayce	PERSON
on	O
his	O
Istar	ORGANIZATION
,	O
was	O
just	O
behind	O
us	O
.	O

A	O
nice	O
,	O
entertaining	O
young	O
fellow	O
with	O
the	O
Fitz-Hardinges	O
,	O
Dr.	O
Bridgman	PERSON
,	O
who	O
found	O
him	O
an	O
enthusiastic	O
gardener	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
only	O
person	O
I	O
ever	O
met	O
who	O
could	O
tell	O
me	O
anything	O
about	O
horticulture	O
in	O
Egypt	LOCATION
.	O

We	O
had	O
Prof.	O
Sayce	PERSON
one	O
evening	O
to	O
dinner	O
-	O
and	O
found	O
him	O
very	O
interesting	O
-	O
telling	O
us	O
a	O
great	O
many	O
things	O
we	O
wanted	O
to	O
know	O
.	O

We	O
left	O
Lord	O
Fitz-Hardinge	PERSON
very	O
ill	O
-	O
with	O
threatened	O
pneumonia	O
.	O

He	O
has	O
during	O
the	O
past	O
year	O
succeeded	O
to	O
the	O
title	O
,	O
we	O
having	O
formerly	O
known	O
of	O
him	O
as	O
Hon.	O
Mr.	O
Berkeley	PERSON
.	O

With	O
this	O
title	O
which	O
is	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
oldest	O
in	O
England	LOCATION
,	O
dating	O
from	O
the	O
time	O
of	O
King	O
Stephen	PERSON
,	O
he	O
has	O
become	O
owner	O
of	O
Berkeley	ORGANIZATION
Castle	ORGANIZATION
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
interesting	O
historical	O
Castles	O
of	O
England	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
also	O
to	O
an	O
income	O
of	O
￡	O
70,00	O
a	O
year	O
.	O

He	O
has	O
no	O
children	O
,	O
he	O
and	O
his	O
wife	O
are	O
past	O
60	O
-	O
have	O
very	O
quiet	O
tastes	O
-	O
devoted	O
to	O
church	O
work	O
-	O
schools	O
and	O
charities	O
,	O
and	O
terribly	O
depressed	O
by	O
this	O
change	O
of	O
fortune	O
,	O
which	O
breaks	O
up	O
old	O
habits	O
,	O
and	O
entails	O
so	O
much	O
state	O
and	O
responsibility	O
for	O
which	O
they	O
have	O
no	O
liking	O
.	O

The	O
next	O
heir	O
,	O
is	O
Lord	ORGANIZATION
Berkeley	ORGANIZATION
of	ORGANIZATION
Oxford	ORGANIZATION
-	O
a	O
man	O
no	O
longer	O
young	O
-	O
no	O
children	O
,	O
and	O
who	O
cares	O
only	O
for	O
chemistry	O
and	O
geology	O
-	O
and	O
devoutly	O
dreads	O
the	O
day	O
when	O
he	O
shall	O
succeed	O
.	O

-	O
Next	O
to	O
him	O
is	O
an	O
unmarried	O
woman	O
not	O
young	O
,	O
the	O
oldest	O
of	O
9	O
children	O
of	O
a	O
clergyman	O
,	O
who	O
has	O
just	O
600	O
￡	O
s	O
PAGE	O
100	O
to	O
spend	O
a	O
year	O
!	O

Prof.	O
Sayce	PERSON
on	O
the	O
Istar	ORGANIZATION
,	O
started	O
down	O
at	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
we	O
did	O
this	O
morning	O
-	O
but	O
he	O
told	O
us	O
yesterday	O
,	O
that	O
he	O
would	O
float	O
faster	O
than	O
we	O
could	O
,	O
as	O
his	O
boat	O
is	O
heavy	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
keel	O
-	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
heavy	O
,	O
old	O
fashioned	O
wooden	O
boats	O
,	O
which	O
would	O
not	O
have	O
the	O
ghost	O
of	O
a	O
chance	O
with	O
us	O
in	O
sailing	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
floated	O
against	O
the	O
wind	O
,	O
but	O
with	O
so	O
little	O
progress	O
that	O
at	O
7	O
this	O
morning	O
we	O
stopped	O
judging	O
we	O
have	O
made	O
about	O
15	O
miles	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
lying	O
in	O
the	O
cove	O
of	O
the	O
bend	O
of	O
the	O
river	O
,	O
at	O
anchor	O
,	O
some	O
distance	O
from	O
shore	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
``	O
Istar	O
''	O
near	O
below	O
,	O
her	O
lights	O
showing	O
hospitably	O
against	O
this	O
desert	O
shore	O
.	O

The	O
night	O
most	O
resplendent	O
,	O
the	O
moon	O
full	O
and	O
the	O
great	O
yellow	O
sand	O
drifts	O
over	O
the	O
mountain	O
sides	O
,	O
glowing	O
with	O
almost	O
as	O
much	O
color	O
as	O
they	O
do	O
by	O
day	O
.	O

I	O
would	O
not	O
have	O
my	O
blinds	O
closed	O
,	O
and	O
slept	O
with	O
all	O
the	O
curtains	O
back	O
from	O
the	O
windows	O
that	O
I	O
might	O
get	O
all	O
the	O
outside	O
beauty	O
possible	O
-	O
and	O
waking	O
several	O
times	O
during	O
the	O
night	O
,	O
I	O
sat	O
up	O
in	O
my	O
bed	O
and	O
looked	O
out	O
at	O
it	O
all	O
.	O

What	O
beautiful	O
,	O
resplendent	O
loneliness	O
!	O

Feb.	O
18	O
.	O

We	O
made	O
about	O
3	O
miles	O
,	O
starting	O
at	O
half	O
past	O
6	O
this	O
morning	O
,	O
but	O
this	O
wretched	O
north	O
wind	O
increasing	O
we	O
gave	O
it	O
up	O
,	O
and	O
lay	O
again	O
in	O
the	O
stream	O
as	O
the	O
shore	O
was	O
so	O
sandy	O
-	O
the	O
Istar	ORGANIZATION
almost	O
a	O
mile	O
below	O
us	O
.	O

Prof.	O
Sayce	PERSON
sent	O
over	O
a	O
note	O
,	O
asking	O
us	O
to	O
come	O
to	O
tea	O
-	O
which	O
we	O
did	O
going	O
down	O
in	O
the	O
felucca	O
-	O
very	O
hard	O
rowing	O
against	O
the	O
wind	O
,	O
even	O
with	O
the	O
current	O
,	O
and	O
there	O
really	O
were	O
waves	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
a	O
charming	O
visit	O
Prof.	O
S.	PERSON
Showing	PERSON
us	O
some	O
of	O
his	O
interesting	O
works	O
on	O
Egypt	LOCATION
-	O
Belzoni	LOCATION
's	O
splendid	O
great	O
volume	O
,	O
with	O
hand	O
painted	O
pictures	O
of	O
the	O
temples	O
and	O
PAGE	O
101	O
tombs	O
-	O
his	O
rendering	O
of	O
the	O
hieroglyphs	O
,	O
being	O
remarkably	O
accurate	O
,	O
though	O
at	O
that	O
time	O
there	O
was	O
no	O
key	O
to	O
them	O
-	O
and	O
of	O
course	O
he	O
was	O
ignorant	O
of	O
their	O
meaning	O
-	O
and	O
it	O
was	O
like	O
copying	O
any	O
other	O
detail	O
of	O
decoration	O
.	O

The	O
great	O
Napeonic	O
work	O
,	O
of	O
the	O
French	O
Scientific	O
Expedition	O
which	O
I	O
had	O
never	O
seen	O
before	O
-	O
the	O
travels	O
of	O
Ligh	LOCATION
,	O
the	O
Englishman	O
a	O
copy	O
of	O
which	O
Howard	PERSON
Amory	PERSON
gave	O
me	O
from	O
his	O
grandfather	O
's	O
library	O
,	O
and	O
others	O
-	O
one	O
an	O
account	O
of	O
travel	O
written	O
by	O
and	O
Italian	O
``	O
del	O
Valle	O
''	O
in	O
16	O
____	O
.	O

The	O
Istar	ORGANIZATION
is	O
a	O
big	O
,	O
old	O
fashioned	O
boat	O
,	O
and	O
looked	O
most	O
comfortable	O
-	O
20	O
ft.	O
wide	O
.	O

We	O
and	O
Cooks	O
new	O
boats	O
are	O
17	O
ft.	O
This	O
width	O
gives	O
her	O
a	O
beautiful	O
saloon	O
,	O
and	O
a	O
wide	O
corridor	O
to	O
the	O
stern	O
cabin	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
also	O
very	O
large	O
,	O
and	O
fitted	O
as	O
a	O
library	O
-	O
with	O
bookcases	O
to	O
the	O
ceiling	O
-	O
a	O
charming	O
,	O
scholarly	O
room	O
-	O
and	O
here	O
Prof.	O
S.	PERSON
says	O
he	O
really	O
does	O
his	O
work	O
for	O
the	O
whole	O
year	O
.	O

Another	O
wonderful	O
night	O
but	O
the	O
wind	O
as	O
strong	O
as	O
ever	O
-	O
and	O
we	O
are	O
rocking	O
uncomfortably	O
-	O
indeed	O
I	O
never	O
rocked	O
so	O
much	O
on	O
the	O
river	O
as	O
we	O
have	O
been	O
doing	O
all	O
day	O
.	O

Friday	O
.	O

Feb.	O
19	O
.	O

We	O
began	O
the	O
morning	O
very	O
early	O
with	O
a	O
light	O
wind	O
,	O
but	O
it	O
soon	O
changed	O
into	O
a	O
big	O
blow	O
-	O
and	O
we	O
were	O
soon	O
driven	O
upon	O
the	O
lee	O
bank	O
,	O
where	O
we	O
pounded	O
up	O
and	O
down	O
in	O
the	O
sand	O
,	O
until	O
Theodore	PERSON
suggested	O
an	O
anchor	O
put	O
out	O
at	O
the	O
stern	O
when	O
we	O
were	O
more	O
comfortable	O
.	O

I	O
have	O
just	O
finished	O
reading	O
Stevenson	PERSON
's	O
``	O
South-Sea	O
Sketches	O
''	O
,	O
and	O
a	O
second	O
reading	O
of	O
his	O
Vailima	LOCATION
Letters	O
-	O
and	O
are	O
now	O
going	O
to	O
read	O
Ebb	O
Tide	O
.	O

A	O
great	O
blow	O
going	O
on	O
.	O

PAGE	O
102	O
Feb.	O
20	O
.	O

I	O
had	O
quite	O
an	O
attack	O
of	O
neuralgia	O
or	O
rheumatism	O
in	O
my	O
back	O
and	O
chest	O
last	O
night	O
,	O
which	O
kept	O
me	O
from	O
sleeping	O
-	O
and	O
finding	O
when	O
my	O
morning	O
cup	O
of	O
tea	O
was	O
brought	O
me	O
at	O
7	O
o'clock	O
-	O
that	O
the	O
gale	O
was	O
still	O
blowing	O
and	O
the	O
boat	O
rocking	O
,	O
I	O
decided	O
after	O
having	O
my	O
bath	O
to	O
go	O
back	O
to	O
bed	O
,	O
and	O
have	O
my	O
breakfast	O
.	O

Wind	O
continued	O
all	O
day	O
,	O
and	O
weather	O
hopeless	O
.	O

I	O
began	O
reading	O
Prof.	O
Sayce	PERSON
's	O
``	O
Egypt	LOCATION
of	O
the	O
Hebrews	O
''	O
.	O

Last	O
night	O
we	O
got	O
away	O
from	O
our	O
lee	O
shore	O
,	O
and	O
took	O
refuge	O
on	O
the	O
opposite	O
side	O
of	O
the	O
river	O
,	O
where	O
we	O
are	O
now	O
lying	O
,	O
more	O
quietly	O
.	O

Read	O
aloud	O
a	O
long	O
time	O
in	O
Milner	PERSON
's	O
``	O
England	LOCATION
in	O
Egypt	LOCATION
''	O
.	O

Feb.	O
21	O
.	O

Sexagesima	O
Sunday	O
.	O

The	O
men	O
rowed	O
,	O
or	O
we	O
floated	O
all	O
the	O
latter	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
night	O
until	O
7	O
this	O
morning	O
,	O
when	O
I	O
saw	O
Kom	ORGANIZATION
Ombo	ORGANIZATION
directly	O
in	O
front	O
of	O
us	O
.	O

A	O
fine	O
all	O
around	O
view	O
of	O
it	O
,	O
perched	O
so	O
high	O
on	O
its	O
cliff	O
-	O
we	O
pulled	O
up	O
soon	O
,	O
and	O
after	O
breakfast	O
went	O
up	O
to	O
the	O
Temple	O
-	O
it	O
is	O
charming	O
in	O
its	O
height	O
,	O
though	O
not	O
specially	O
interesting	O
;	O
and	O
is	O
certainly	O
very	O
much	O
swept	O
and	O
garnished	O
.	O

The	O
wind	O
falling	O
,	O
we	O
decided	O
not	O
to	O
linger	O
,	O
but	O
pushed	O
off	O
,	O
just	O
as	O
Gage	PERSON
's	O
Steamer	O
``	O
Memphis	LOCATION
''	O
was	O
coming	O
up	O
to	O
her	O
landing	O
.	O

Passed	O
the	O
Istar	O
lying	O
by	O
a	O
little	O
below	O
Kom	ORGANIZATION
Ombo	ORGANIZATION
.	O

This	O
is	O
our	O
5th	O
day	O
from	O
Assouan	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
we	O
have	O
only	O
covered	O
29	O
miles	O
.	O

Feb.	O
22	O
.	O

Monday	O
.	O

We	O
were	O
off	O
before	O
6	O
o'clock	O
this	O
morning	O
-	O
rowing	O
-	O
and	O
in	O
the	O
face	O
of	O
the	O
north	O
wind	O
which	O
still	O
holds	O
with	O
more	O
or	O
less	O
fitfullness	O
-	O
PAGE	O
103	O
we	O
passed	O
Silsilis	PERSON
about	O
3	O
o'clock	O
-	O
but	O
did	O
not	O
stop	O
,	O
as	O
we	O
are	O
so	O
belated	O
.	O

About	O
an	O
hour	O
afterwards	O
we	O
had	O
gained	O
very	O
much	O
upon	O
the	O
Istar	O
-	O
and	O
our	O
men	O
were	O
pulling	O
lustily	O
-	O
when	O
the	O
order	O
from	O
the	O
Rais	PERSON
was	O
suddenly	O
given	O
to	O
stop	O
,	O
and	O
in	O
a	O
moment	O
after	O
,	O
we	O
went	O
rather	O
hard	O
upon	O
a	O
sand	O
bank	O
-	O
which	O
delayed	O
us	O
about	O
an	O
hour	O
-	O
when	O
we	O
went	O
on	O
until	O
7	O
o'clock	O
-	O
apparently	O
by	O
the	O
light	O
of	O
Venus	PERSON
,	O
almost	O
as	O
good	O
as	O
a	O
moon	O
.	O

We	O
tied	O
up	O
at	O
a	O
pleasant	O
bank	O
under	O
some	O
scent	O
trees	O
,	O
having	O
come	O
between	O
3	O
and	O
4	O
miles	O
below	O
Silsilis	LOCATION
-	O
making	O
today	O
15	O
miles	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
so	O
easy	O
to	O
tell	O
who	O
is	O
keeping	O
Ramadan	O
.	O

Quite	O
a	O
proportion	O
of	O
crew	O
are	O
and	O
they	O
are	O
so	O
solemn	O
and	O
melancholy	O
.	O

Our	O
nice	O
Mathar	LOCATION
,	O
the	O
2d	O
captain	O
,	O
has	O
n't	O
even	O
a	O
smile	O
-	O
Rais	PERSON
Fuli	PERSON
,	O
and	O
he	O
,	O
and	O
5	O
or	O
6	O
of	O
the	O
crew	O
,	O
are	O
carefully	O
keeping	O
it	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
.	O

Feb.	O
23	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
allowed	O
ourselves	O
just	O
a	O
month	O
from	O
today	O
to	O
reach	O
Cairo	LOCATION
-	O
there	O
will	O
be	O
so	O
much	O
to	O
do	O
there	O
about	O
changes	O
in	O
the	O
boat	O
,	O
and	O
getting	O
her	O
ready	O
to	O
leave	O
her	O
,	O
that	O
the	O
10	O
days	O
between	O
March	O
23	O
and	O
April	O
3d	O
when	O
we	O
leave	O
for	O
Hrindisi	PERSON
will	O
not	O
be	O
more	O
than	O
we	O
need	O
.	O

But	O
this	O
north	O
wind	O
must	O
cease	O
blowing	O
!	O

This	O
morning	O
we	O
started	O
out	O
before	O
6	O
-	O
and	O
when	O
Ainely	PERSON
came	O
to	O
my	O
room	O
,	O
she	O
reported	O
the	O
Istar	O
some	O
distance	O
in	O
advance	O
of	O
us	O
,	O
and	O
another	O
dahabeah	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
wondering	O
if	O
it	O
can	O
be	O
the	O
Gazelle	LOCATION
,	O
which	O
left	O
Assouan	LOCATION
,	O
the	O
day	O
we	O
arrived	O
.	O

Yesterday	O
the	O
Nephtis	O
passed	O
up	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
Duke	ORGANIZATION
of	ORGANIZATION
Hamilton	ORGANIZATION
on	O
board	O
.	O

His	O
own	O
flag	O
I	O
suppose	O
at	O
the	O
mast	O
,	O
yellow	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
grimping	O
lion	O
-	O
very	O
effective	O
.	O

He	O
has	O
only	O
lately	O
succeeded	O
to	O
the	O
title	O
we	O
were	O
told	O
-	O
and	O
jumped	O
from	O
PAGE	O
104	O
a	O
lieutenant	O
in	O
the	O
navy	O
to	O
his	O
present	O
titles	O
and	O
possessions	O
.	O

A	O
pleasant	O
thing	O
.	O

Reached	O
El	O
Kab	O
-	O
36	O
miles	O
.	O

Wednesday	O
.	O

Feb.	O
24	O
.	O

Morning	O
calm	O
-	O
did	O
not	O
start	O
until	O
10	O
o'clock	O
-	O
as	O
we	O
had	O
hoped	O
to	O
se	O
Mr.	O
Somers-Clarke	PERSON
.	O

I	O
wanted	O
very	O
much	O
to	O
see	O
his	O
boat	O
.	O

But	O
we	O
found	O
he	O
and	O
Prof.	O
Sayce	PERSON
had	O
gone	O
early	O
to	O
the	O
tombs	O
,	O
so	O
after	O
a	O
little	O
inspection	O
of	O
the	O
old	O
town	O
,	O
we	O
came	O
away	O
-	O
and	O
have	O
with	O
difficulty	O
,	O
against	O
a	O
head	O
wind	O
made	O
15	O
miles	O
.	O

Thursday	O
.	O

Feb.	O
25	O
.	O

We	O
floated	O
down	O
2	O
miles	O
to	O
Esneh	LOCATION
early	O
this	O
morning	O
-	O
and	O
all	O
the	O
rest	O
went	O
off	O
in	O
the	O
felucca	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
temple	O
-	O
which	O
I	O
do	O
n't	O
care	O
for	O
-	O
Jones	PERSON
and	O
Henna	PERSON
went	O
marketing	O
-	O
and	O
they	O
all	O
joined	O
us	O
again	O
at	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
the	O
town	O
.	O

Our	O
men	O
have	O
rowed	O
tremendously	O
this	O
afternoon	O
,	O
hoping	O
to	O
bring	O
us	O
to	O
Luxor	LOCATION
tonight	O
-	O
but	O
at	O
11	O
o'clock	O
the	O
wind	O
grew	O
so	O
strong	O
that	O
we	O
tied	O
up	O
within	O
sight	O
of	O
the	O
Luxor	LOCATION
lights	O
-	O
having	O
made	O
36	O
miles	O
.	O

Friday	O
.	O

Feb.	O
26	O
.	O

We	O
came	O
to	O
our	O
old	O
place	O
near	O
the	O
Castle	O
early	O
this	O
morning	O
.	O

High	O
wind	O
has	O
been	O
blowing	O
all	O
day	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
did	O
not	O
ride	O
out	O
to	O
Karnac	LOCATION
with	O
them	O
this	O
afternoon	O
-	O
though	O
we	O
walked	O
into	O
town	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
went	O
to	O
the	O
American	O
Mission	O
to	O
ask	O
about	O
the	O
little	O
arab	O
girl	O
``	O
Nubia	LOCATION
''	O
and	O
the	O
chances	O
of	O
sending	O
her	O
to	O
school	O
.	O

I	O
saw	O
Mrs.	O
Nichols	PERSON
in	O
her	O
pleasant	O
PAGE	O
105	O
clean	O
rooms	O
-	O
and	O
she	O
could	O
not	O
give	O
me	O
any	O
encouragement	O
.	O

Asked	O
her	O
and	O
Mr.	O
Nichols	PERSON
to	O
come	O
to	O
tea	O
this	O
afternoon	O
-	O
and	O
had	O
a	O
very	O
pleasant	O
visit	O
.	O

They	O
are	O
soon	O
going	O
to	O
America	LOCATION
for	O
a	O
vacation	O
year	O
,	O
having	O
spent	O
7	O
years	O
here	O
.	O

Only	O
4	O
dahabeahs	O
here	O
-	O
the	O
Hyksos	ORGANIZATION
,	O
Anna	PERSON
,	O
Gamilla	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
one	O
other	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Huhatt	PERSON
came	O
to	O
play	O
chess	O
.	O

Saturday	O
,	O
Feb.	O
27	O
.	O

Today	O
the	O
Cheops	LOCATION
,	O
Columbia	ORGANIZATION
and	O
Ammon-Ra	O
came	O
down	O
.	O

All	O
went	O
over	O
early	O
to	O
the	O
Tombs	O
of	O
the	O
Kings	ORGANIZATION
for	O
the	O
day	O
-	O
I	O
could	O
not	O
face	O
the	O
idea	O
of	O
such	O
a	O
long	O
excursion	O
in	O
this	O
heat	O
-	O
so	O
stayed	O
on	O
the	O
boat	O
all	O
day	O
-	O
and	O
had	O
a	O
rest	O
and	O
did	O
all	O
manner	O
of	O
delightful	O
little	O
independent	O
things	O
.	O

Intensely	O
hot	O
-	O
I	O
had	O
``	O
Nubia	LOCATION
''	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
morning	O
with	O
me	O
,	O
but	O
she	O
was	O
such	O
a	O
restless	O
little	O
colt	O
,	O
I	O
had	O
to	O
send	O
her	O
away	O
at	O
12	O
o'clock	O
-	O
quite	O
happy	O
with	O
numerous	O
possessions	O
-	O
the	O
chief	O
of	O
which	O
was	O
a	O
pair	O
of	O
red	O
shoes	O
-	O
which	O
Mohammed	PERSON
Schaiyeh	PERSON
,	O
my	O
singer	O
,	O
bought	O
for	O
her	O
in	O
the	O
town	O
.	O

The	O
family	O
came	O
back	O
at	O
6:30	O
-	O
powdered	O
with	O
dust	O
,	O
and	O
tired	O
,	O
and	O
clamouring	O
for	O
lemonade	O
and	O
tea	O
-	O
having	O
had	O
a	O
delightful	O
day	O
.	O

The	O
Osiris	O
came	O
in	O
this	O
afternoon	O
and	O
is	O
lying	O
close	O
behind	O
us	O
.	O

Quinquagesima	O
Sunday	O
.	O

Feb.	O
28	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
thought	O
of	O
getting	O
off	O
today	O
,	O
but	O
there	O
was	O
no	O
wind	O
,	O
and	O
Mr.	O
Baldwin	PERSON
wants	O
us	O
to	O
wait	O
for	O
him	O
tomorrow	O
.	O

I	O
did	O
not	O
leave	O
the	O
boat	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
the	O
wind	O
very	O
high	O
.	O

Mrs.	O
Constantine	PERSON
Read	PERSON
and	O
her	O
cousin	O
made	O
us	O
a	O
visit	O
,	O
and	O
Mr.	O
Shephard	PERSON
and	O
his	O
sister	O
of	O
the	O
PAGE	O
106	O
Hyksos	ORGANIZATION
also	O
came	O
.	O

He	O
,	O
the	O
Engineer	O
of	O
the	O
new	O
railroad	O
.	O

Mohammed	PERSON
Mohassib	PERSON
also	O
came	O
.	O

March	O
1st	O
.	O

Monday	O
.	O

We	O
did	O
not	O
get	O
away	O
until	O
7	O
o'clock	O
this	O
morning	O
-	O
and	O
had	O
not	O
lost	O
sight	O
of	O
the	O
town	O
when	O
a	O
very	O
hard	O
north	O
wind	O
sprang	O
up	O
,	O
and	O
after	O
trying	O
to	O
float	O
,	O
gave	O
it	O
up	O
and	O
anchored	O
,	O
until	O
about	O
4	O
o'clock	O
,	O
when	O
it	O
came	O
out	O
a	O
little	O
to	O
the	O
south	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
gladly	O
spread	O
our	O
sails	O
,	O
and	O
had	O
soon	O
come	O
to	O
a	O
big	O
turn	O
in	O
the	O
river	O
which	O
brought	O
the	O
wind	O
on	O
our	O
side	O
,	O
so	O
that	O
we	O
could	O
not	O
keep	O
off	O
the	O
bank	O
.	O

Found	O
here	O
tied	O
up	O
,	O
under	O
the	O
same	O
circumstances	O
,	O
the	O
Osiris	O
which	O
left	O
Luxor	LOCATION
the	O
day	O
before	O
us	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
Ammon-Ra	O
who	O
got	O
away	O
an	O
hour	O
before	O
us	O
this	O
morning	O
-	O
and	O
here	O
we	O
all	O
are	O
for	O
the	O
night	O
.	O

Two	O
Mecca	ORGANIZATION
pilgrims	O
going	O
to	O
Mecca	LOCATION
stopped	O
on	O
the	O
bank	O
above	O
us	O
after	O
the	O
sun	O
had	O
gone	O
down	O
,	O
to	O
break	O
the	O
long	O
fast	O
of	O
the	O
day	O
and	O
eat	O
their	O
evening	O
meal	O
.	O

They	O
were	O
dressed	O
entirely	O
in	O
white	O
,	O
and	O
had	O
a	O
donkey	O
,	O
carrying	O
their	O
luggage	O
.	O

March	O
2d	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
.	O

A	O
very	O
early	O
start	O
this	O
morning	O
and	O
rowing	O
and	O
floating	O
in	O
company	O
with	O
the	O
Ammon-Ra	O
and	O
the	O
Osiris	O
,	O
we	O
reached	O
Keneh	LOCATION
about	O
3	O
o'clock	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
rest	O
started	O
in	O
the	O
felucca	O
,	O
before	O
we	O
reached	O
the	O
opposite	O
landing	O
for	O
Denderah	PERSON
,	O
and	O
we	O
floated	O
down	O
below	O
and	O
waited	O
for	O
them	O
.	O

Very	O
hot	O
for	O
2	O
hours	O
-	O
found	O
the	O
Columbia	LOCATION
at	O
Denderah	LOCATION
.	O

They	O
reported	O
on	O
coming	O
home	O
,	O
very	O
unruly	O
donkey	O
boys	O
,	O
and	O
very	O
exciting	O
rows	O
with	O
them	O
.	O

All	O
the	O
morning	O
we	O
were	O
just	O
in	O
advance	O
of	O
the	O
Osiris	O
,	O
PAGE	O
107	O
and	O
she	O
floated	O
most	O
unpleasantly	O
near	O
us	O
-	O
two	O
or	O
three	O
times	O
we	O
were	O
actually	O
in	O
collision	O
side	O
by	O
side	O
,	O
and	O
great	O
commotion	O
among	O
the	O
crews	O
.	O

Lord	O
St.	PERSON
Oswald	PERSON
is	O
on	O
her	O
.	O

They	O
all	O
came	O
back	O
in	O
an	O
hour	O
and	O
a	O
half	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
floated	O
and	O
rowed	O
3	O
or	O
4	O
miles	O
farther	O
down	O
-	O
and	O
tied	O
up	O
with	O
strong	O
wind	O
blowing	O
from	O
the	O
north	O
,	O
at	O
6:30	O
.	O

I	O
enjoyed	O
a	O
walk	O
on	O
deck	O
while	O
they	O
were	O
away	O
-	O
looking	O
at	O
the	O
splendid	O
desert	O
mountains	O
across	O
the	O
river	O
beyond	O
Keneh	LOCATION
.	O

What	O
a	O
hot	O
,	O
desolate	O
spot	O
Keneh	PERSON
must	O
have	O
been	O
last	O
summer	O
,	O
when	O
the	O
cholera	O
raged	O
so	O
violently	O
!	O

I	O
have	O
never	O
been	O
in	O
the	O
town	O
but	O
once	O
-	O
and	O
it	O
lies	O
so	O
back	O
from	O
the	O
river	O
that	O
it	O
can	O
not	O
be	O
well	O
seen	O
.	O

I	O
suppose	O
just	O
now	O
the	O
Mecca	LOCATION
pilgrims	O
are	O
crowding	O
them	O
on	O
their	O
way	O
to	O
Mecca	LOCATION
-	O
I	O
should	O
like	O
to	O
have	O
ridden	O
into	O
the	O
town	O
today	O
,	O
and	O
out	O
a	O
way	O
upon	O
the	O
Koser	PERSON
road	O
.	O

The	O
descriptions	O
of	O
this	O
desert	O
route	O
have	O
always	O
fascinated	O
me	O
.	O

We	O
think	O
we	O
have	O
made	O
31	O
miles	O
today	O
.	O

Wednesday	O
.	O

March	O
3	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
Ash	O
Wednesday	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
last	O
of	O
the	O
30	O
days	O
of	O
Ramadan	O
-	O
for	O
which	O
we	O
are	O
truly	O
thankful	O
-	O
for	O
Rais	PERSON
Fuli	PERSON
-	O
2	O
Rais	PERSON
Mattar	PERSON
-	O
Moomond	O
the	O
big	O
Mohammed	PERSON
,	O
and	O
Baken	PERSON
the	O
little	O
sailor	O
,	O
all	O
keep	O
it	O
rigourously	O
.	O

They	O
represent	O
the	O
very	O
pick	O
of	O
the	O
crew	O
-	O
and	O
things	O
will	O
now	O
be	O
more	O
cheerful	O
.	O

This	O
had	O
been	O
a	O
distracting	O
day	O
.	O

Such	O
a	O
mix	O
as	O
we	O
,	O
the	O
Osiris	O
,	O
the	O
Ammon-Ra	O
,	O
the	O
Columbia	LOCATION
and	O
several	O
large	O
working	O
boats	O
have	O
been	O
in	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
day	O
.	O

I	O
have	O
never	O
known	O
such	O
an	O
experience	O
-	O
the	O
wind	O
has	O
been	O
from	O
the	O
north	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
time	O
.	O

Our	O
crew	O
have	O
worked	O
splendidly	O
at	O
their	O
oars	O
,	O
and	O
beaten	O
all	O
the	O
others	O
PAGE	O
108	O
out	O
and	O
out	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
a	O
splendid	O
triumph	O
.	O

The	O
gale	O
increased	O
and	O
at	O
5	O
o'clock	O
we	O
tied	O
up	O
,	O
followed	O
by	O
all	O
the	O
others	O
-	O
and	O
we	O
are	O
strung	O
along	O
the	O
bank	O
,	O
within	O
2	O
or	O
3	O
miles	O
of	O
Kasr-el	O
Sayd	O
.	O

After	O
we	O
landed	O
we	O
went	O
to	O
visit	O
the	O
Baldwins	ORGANIZATION
.	O

We	O
have	O
made	O
25	O
miles	O
-	O
and	O
are	O
rolling	O
a	O
little	O
uneasily	O
in	O
the	O
wind	O
.	O

Thursday	O
.	O

March	O
4	O
.	O

Made	O
about	O
5	O
miles	O
early	O
this	O
morning	O
-	O
heavy	O
gale	O
from	O
the	O
north	O
has	O
made	O
it	O
impossible	O
to	O
stir	O
since	O
8	O
o'clock	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
3	O
miles	O
below	O
Kasr	LOCATION
el-Sayd	LOCATION
.	O

Friday	O
.	O

March	O
5	O
.	O

Started	O
at	O
5	O
o'clock	O
this	O
morning	O
-	O
and	O
before	O
I	O
got	O
up	O
,	O
while	O
enjoying	O
my	O
book	O
and	O
cup	O
of	O
tea	O
,	O
we	O
passed	O
the	O
bridge	O
at	O
Nagh-el-Hamadi	O
.	O

Ammon-Ra	O
and	O
Osiris	O
ahead	O
of	O
us	O
.	O

Saturday	O
.	O

March	O
6	O
.	O

Our	O
men	O
began	O
rowing	O
at	O
1	O
o'clock	O
this	O
morning	O
-	O
reached	O
Balliana	LOCATION
at	O
10:30	O
and	O
started	O
immediately	O
for	O
Abydos	ORGANIZATION
.	O

That	O
pleasant	O
ride	O
of	O
7	O
miles	O
out	O
and	O
7	O
back	O
,	O
never	O
seemed	O
so	O
tiresome	O
-	O
for	O
the	O
very	O
worst	O
donkeys	O
of	O
all	O
the	O
notorious	O
bad	O
donkeys	O
of	O
Abydos	LOCATION
or	O
rather	O
Balliana	PERSON
fell	O
to	O
our	O
lot	O
.	O

The	O
day	O
was	O
tremendously	O
hot	O
-	O
the	O
natives	O
specially	O
tormenting	O
.	O

I	O
arrived	O
at	O
the	O
temple	O
more	O
dead	O
than	O
alive	O
-	O
and	O
by	O
3:30	O
we	O
were	O
in	O
our	O
saddles	O
again	O
-	O
and	O
I	O
came	O
home	O
resolving	O
PAGE	O
109	O
never	O
to	O
do	O
that	O
expedition	O
again	O
.	O

The	O
Ammon-Ra	O
and	O
Osiris	O
did	O
not	O
stop	O
-	O
but	O
the	O
Chensu	LOCATION
-LRB-	O
English	O
-RRB-	O
and	O
the	O
Columbia	LOCATION
-LRB-	O
American	O
Jews	O
-RRB-	O
did	O
,	O
and	O
went	O
to	O
the	O
Temple	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
having	O
the	O
most	O
beautiful	O
little	O
new	O
moon	O
imaginable	O
.	O

For	O
the	O
first	O
two	O
nights	O
it	O
had	O
the	O
resplendent	O
beams	O
almost	O
within	O
its	O
bow	O
.	O

The	O
last	O
winter	O
we	O
were	O
here	O
on	O
the	O
river	O
we	O
used	O
constantly	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
Zodiacal	O
lights	O
-	O
but	O
I	O
have	O
not	O
seen	O
it	O
this	O
time	O
.	O

I	O
saw	O
in	O
the	O
Abydos	LOCATION
fields	O
today	O
,	O
the	O
most	O
beautiful	O
light	O
vivid	O
green	O
birds	O
-	O
large	O
as	O
our	O
robin	O
,	O
but	O
more	O
slender	O
and	O
elegant	O
.	O

1st	O
Sunday	O
in	O
Lent	O
.	O

March	O
7	O
.	O

Made	O
from	O
6	O
A.M.	O
to	O
8	O
P.M.	O
27-1/2	O
miles	O
-	O
are	O
now	O
at	O
Akmim	LOCATION
.	O

Monday	O
.	O

March	O
8	O
.	O

Started	O
early	O
,	O
and	O
made	O
Sohag	LOCATION
by	O
9	O
o'clock	O
-	O
where	O
we	O
stopped	O
to	O
get	O
coal	O
and	O
provisions	O
and	O
our	O
mail	O
.	O

By	O
11	O
o'clock	O
P.M.	O
had	O
come	O
6	O
miles	O
below	O
Sohag	LOCATION
-	O
making	O
the	O
whole	O
day	O
11	O
miles	O
.	O

North	O
wind	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
.	O

March	O
9	O
.	O

Made	O
2	O
miles	O
today	O
early	O
-	O
tied	O
up	O
since	O
in	O
a	O
gale	O
-	O
wind	O
a	O
little	O
west	O
of	O
north	O
-	O
so	O
that	O
we	O
are	O
hoping	O
it	O
may	O
move	O
around	O
to	O
the	O
south	O
.	O

We	O
would	O
like	O
so	O
much	O
to	O
have	O
one	O
record	O
day	O
of	O
gentle	O
south	O
wind	O
!	O

Chonsu	PERSON
passed	O
us	O
,	O
being	O
so	O
heavy	O
,	O
she	O
floats	O
fast	O
.	O

Columbia	LOCATION
still	O
behind	O
.	O

Had	O
a	O
row	O
in	O
the	O
felucca	O
.	O

PAGE	O
110	O
Wednesday	O
.	O

March	O
10	O
.	O

Early	O
this	O
morning	O
,	O
we	O
managed	O
to	O
make	O
about	O
10	O
yards	O
-	O
but	O
the	O
wind	O
increasing	O
we	O
tied	O
up	O
again	O
-	O
and	O
now	O
lying	O
just	O
as	O
we	O
did	O
all	O
day	O
yesterday	O
at	O
the	O
mercy	O
of	O
the	O
wind	O
,	O
blowing	O
across	O
miles	O
of	O
sand	O
.	O

For	O
days	O
the	O
sky	O
has	O
been	O
full	O
of	O
clouds	O
and	O
last	O
evening	O
they	O
were	O
so	O
ominous	O
,	O
that	O
I	O
hoped	O
the	O
night	O
would	O
bring	O
rain	O
,	O
and	O
perhaps	O
break	O
this	O
deadly	O
magic	O
spell	O
of	O
north	O
wind	O
-	O
but	O
it	O
has	O
been	O
even	O
worse	O
today	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
had	O
the	O
boat	O
as	O
tightly	O
closed	O
as	O
possible	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
air	O
everywhere	O
has	O
been	O
thick	O
with	O
this	O
fine	O
,	O
impalpable	O
sand	O
.	O

Thursday	O
.	O

March	O
11	O
.	O

Still	O
lying	O
at	O
the	O
same	O
spot	O
,	O
and	O
a	O
gale	O
still	O
blowing	O
-	O
impossible	O
to	O
be	O
on	O
deck	O
except	O
for	O
a	O
walk	O
near	O
sunset	O
-	O
so	O
much	O
sand	O
still	O
flying	O
-	O
rugs	O
cushions	O
etc.	O
all	O
folded	O
and	O
packed	O
away	O
.	O

Friday	O
.	O

March	O
12	O
.	O

Got	O
away	O
at	O
6	O
o'clock	O
and	O
rowed	O
and	O
floated	O
until	O
about	O
10	O
-	O
when	O
the	O
wind	O
grew	O
into	O
such	O
a	O
sudden	O
gale	O
,	O
we	O
pulled	O
with	O
difficulty	O
to	O
the	O
shore	O
-	O
where	O
some	O
work	O
boats	O
had	O
taken	O
refuge	O
.	O

Soon	O
after	O
the	O
Nephtys	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
Duke	ORGANIZATION
of	ORGANIZATION
Hamilton	ORGANIZATION
,	O
and	O
a	O
tug	O
came	O
down	O
the	O
river	O
,	O
and	O
came	O
to	O
the	O
shore	O
just	O
below	O
us	O
.	O

3	O
miles	O
today	O
.	O

Saturday	O
-	O
March	O
13	O
.	O

Started	O
in	O
a	O
light	O
wind	O
at	O
6	O
A.M.	O
at	O
11	O
it	O
was	O
blowing	O
such	O
a	O
gale	O
that	O
we	O
tied	O
up	O
at	O
the	O
high	O
cliffs	O
about	O
2	O
miles	O
above	O
and	O
opposite	O
PAGE	O
111	O
Tahtah	O
.	O

Just	O
where	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
group	O
of	O
palms	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
white	O
little	O
mosque	O
against	O
the	O
yellow	O
cliffs	O
.	O

Luckily	O
it	O
was	O
not	O
a	O
hot	O
day	O
,	O
or	O
the	O
reflection	O
from	O
those	O
towering	O
limestone	O
cliffs	O
would	O
have	O
been	O
insufferable	O
.	O

But	O
how	O
the	O
wind	O
has	O
blown	O
-	O
in	O
our	O
sheltered	O
position	O
however	O
we	O
got	O
no	O
sand	O
.	O

The	O
canvass	O
on	O
the	O
river	O
side	O
,	O
and	O
over	O
the	O
deck	O
,	O
and	O
at	O
the	O
back	O
were	O
put	O
up	O
-	O
leaving	O
the	O
land	O
side	O
with	O
its	O
pretty	O
sights	O
open	O
-	O
and	O
under	O
the	O
hooded	O
seats	O
,	O
the	O
deck	O
was	O
charming	O
for	O
sitting	O
.	O

All	O
the	O
others	O
went	O
to	O
walk	O
,	O
but	O
I	O
took	O
mine	O
on	O
the	O
clean	O
deck	O
.	O

The	O
Columbia	ORGANIZATION
came	O
in	O
sight	O
this	O
morning	O
,	O
and	O
drew	O
up	O
just	O
above	O
us	O
.	O

At	O
6:30	O
we	O
both	O
went	O
off	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
bright	O
moonlight	O
,	O
the	O
wind	O
having	O
fallen	O
very	O
much	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
men	O
are	O
still	O
rowing	O
.	O

-LRB-	O
They	O
rowed	O
until	O
12:30	O
,	O
thus	O
making	O
27	O
miles	O
-RRB-	O
.	O

Second	O
Sunday	O
in	O
Lent	O
.	O

March	O
14	O
.	O

Started	O
early	O
rowing	O
.	O

North	O
wind	O
strong	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
day	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
now	O
tied	O
up	O
2	O
miles	O
above	O
Assiut	LOCATION
-	O
the	O
lights	O
of	O
the	O
town	O
plainly	O
to	O
be	O
seen	O
.	O

Columbia	LOCATION
near	O
us	O
.	O

A	O
superb	O
sunset	O
.	O

Monday	O
,	O
March	O
15	O
.	O

Between	O
marketing	O
,	O
getting	O
in	O
coke	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
mail	O
,	O
we	O
were	O
at	O
Assiut	LOCATION
,	O
until	O
after	O
one	O
o'clock	O
.	O

The	O
afternoon	O
a	O
regular	O
gale	O
blowing	O
,	O
made	O
2	O
miles	O
at	O
8	O
o'clock	O
.	O

PAGE	O
112	O
Tuesday	O
.	O

March	O
16	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
now	O
beginning	O
to	O
calculate	O
the	O
distance	O
made	O
from	O
1:30	O
P.M.	O
of	O
each	O
day	O
.	O

Since	O
that	O
time	O
last	O
night	O
we	O
have	O
made	O
32	O
miles	O
-	O
and	O
have	O
passed	O
the	O
troublesome	O
Gebel	PERSON
Abufedah	PERSON
,	O
and	O
are	O
anchored	O
in	O
the	O
stream	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
an	O
almost	O
full	O
moon	O
now	O
,	O
and	O
lovely	O
effects	O
this	O
evening	O
.	O

Wednesday	O
.	O

March	O
17	O
.	O

Made	O
21	O
miles	O
-	O
were	O
blown	O
ashore	O
in	O
the	O
strong	O
wind	O
early	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
near	O
Haggi	LOCATION
Kandul	LOCATION
-	O
and	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
noisy	O
children	O
and	O
rough	O
looking	O
men	O
hung	O
about	O
the	O
boat	O
making	O
it	O
hideous	O
with	O
their	O
clamour	O
.	O

We	O
got	O
away	O
from	O
that	O
unpleasant	O
neighborhood	O
and	O
floated	O
down	O
until	O
10	O
o'clock	O
.	O

Such	O
a	O
radiant	O
night	O
!	O

Thursday	O
.	O

March	O
18	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
made	O
25	O
miles	O
in	O
the	O
last	O
24	O
hours	O
-	O
the	O
day	O
being	O
the	O
calmest	O
we	O
have	O
had	O
and	O
the	O
hottest	O
.	O

We	O
were	O
all	O
driven	O
down	O
stairs	O
after	O
luncheon	O
by	O
the	O
heat	O
.	O

Passed	O
Beni	PERSON
Hassan	PERSON
at	O
one	O
o'clock	O
-	O
but	O
did	O
not	O
stop	O
-	O
as	O
we	O
are	O
so	O
belated	O
.	O

Every	O
day	O
Theodore	PERSON
says	O
``	O
tomorrow	O
''	O
I	O
shall	O
telegraph	O
for	O
a	O
tug	O
,	O
if	O
the	O
south	O
sind	O
does	O
n't	O
come	O
.	O

Each	O
day	O
we	O
hopefully	O
look	O
for	O
it	O
-	O
and	O
we	O
would	O
even	O
welcome	O
a	O
Khamseen	O
.	O

We	O
reached	O
Minieh	PERSON
at	O
7	O
o'clock	O
and	O
got	O
our	O
mail	O
,	O
and	O
will	O
lie	O
here	O
all	O
night	O
.	O

The	O
full	O
moon	O
was	O
wonderfully	O
beautiful	O
and	O
the	O
night	O
so	O
soft	O
.	O

A	O
heavy	O
mist	O
however	O
lying	O
along	O
the	O
river	O
.	O

PAGE	O
113	O
Friday	O
.	O

March	O
19	O
.	O

An	O
early	O
start	O
,	O
and	O
rowing	O
and	O
occasional	O
sailing	O
,	O
or	O
lying	O
by	O
when	O
the	O
wind	O
was	O
too	O
strong	O
,	O
has	O
brought	O
us	O
to	O
within	O
3	O
miles	O
of	O
Fashen	O
-	O
making	O
since	O
1:30	O
,	O
44	O
miles	O
,	O
or	O
61-1/2	O
from	O
Minieh	LOCATION
this	O
morning	O
-	O
a	O
strange	O
,	O
wonderful	O
sunset	O
-	O
and	O
a	O
cloudy	O
night	O
.	O

Saturday	O
-	O
March	O
20	O
.	O

Started	O
at	O
6	O
A.M.	O
made	O
Benisoef	O
about	O
1:30	O
-	O
and	O
a	O
drifting	O
and	O
sailing	O
delightfully	O
along	O
before	O
a	O
light	O
wind	O
,	O
all	O
the	O
afternoon	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
now	O
lying	O
7	O
miles	O
from	O
Wasta	LOCATION
,	O
-	O
54-1/2	O
miles	O
since	O
1:30	O
yesterday	O
,	O
and	O
25	O
miles	O
since	O
1:30	O
today	O
.	O

Medum	O
in	O
sight	O
.	O

Third	O
Sunday	O
in	O
Lent	O
.	O

March	O
21st	O
.	O

An	O
early	O
start	O
in	O
a	O
good	O
wind	O
brought	O
us	O
along	O
so	O
surprisingly	O
that	O
we	O
were	O
near	O
Bedrascheen	LOCATION
at	O
10:30	O
,	O
having	O
discovered	O
some	O
minutes	O
before	O
that	O
beautiful	O
view	O
of	O
the	O
dome	O
and	O
slender	O
minarets	O
of	O
Mohammed	PERSON
Ali	PERSON
-	O
shining	O
in	O
the	O
sun	O
above	O
the	O
thick	O
haze	O
,	O
looking	O
like	O
some	O
enchanted	O
palace	O
.	O

The	O
sailing	O
was	O
so	O
fine	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
Beduin	O
showing	O
her	O
paces	O
so	O
splendidly	O
,	O
that	O
we	O
suddenly	O
decided	O
we	O
would	O
not	O
stop	O
for	O
the	O
visit	O
to	O
Sakkarah	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
kept	O
on	O
for	O
the	O
Museum	O
landing	O
at	O
Ghizeh	LOCATION
.	O

The	O
sky	O
being	O
full	O
of	O
great	O
clouds	O
,	O
very	O
unlike	O
Egypt	LOCATION
-	O
all	O
the	O
morning	O
the	O
blue	O
sky	O
making	O
such	O
delightful	O
contrasts	O
with	O
their	O
great	O
swelling	O
white	O
domes	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
pyramids	O
of	O
Lisht	LOCATION
,	O
Dashur	PERSON
,	O
and	O
Sakkarah	PERSON
showing	O
splendidly	O
-	O
until	O
quite	O
in	O
a	O
moment	O
the	O
clouds	O
grew	O
dirty	O
and	O
the	O
atmosphere	O
thick	O
,	O
the	O
wind	O
increased	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
were	O
blown	O
to	O
the	O
bank	O
,	O
with	O
PAGE	O
114	O
great	O
effort	O
escaping	O
collision	O
with	O
the	O
rocky	O
foundation	O
of	O
a	O
big	O
sakiyeh	O
on	O
the	O
top	O
of	O
which	O
as	O
usual	O
a	O
blindfolded	O
bullock	O
was	O
walking	O
round	O
and	O
round	O
his	O
wheel	O
.	O

Here	O
we	O
have	O
been	O
ever	O
since	O
,	O
the	O
wind	O
growing	O
into	O
a	O
gale	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
opposite	O
shore	O
almost	O
hidden	O
by	O
the	O
clouds	O
of	O
sand	O
blowing	O
across	O
its	O
sandy	O
waste	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
quite	O
sheltered	O
here	O
from	O
it	O
,	O
though	O
we	O
get	O
enough	O
of	O
it	O
as	O
the	O
atmosphere	O
is	O
so	O
charged	O
with	O
it	O
and	O
when	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
it	O
began	O
softly	O
to	O
rain	O
,	O
the	O
drops	O
seemed	O
like	O
mud	O
,	O
and	O
made	O
a	O
fine	O
mess	O
of	O
our	O
clean	O
windows	O
.	O

The	O
waves	O
beat	O
so	O
high	O
and	O
roughly	O
on	O
the	O
lee	O
shore	O
against	O
which	O
we	O
lay	O
,	O
that	O
the	O
two	O
feluccas	O
,	O
were	O
in	O
danger	O
,	O
and	O
our	O
men	O
worked	O
almost	O
stripped	O
,	O
for	O
2	O
hours	O
before	O
they	O
were	O
bailed	O
and	O
lifted	O
to	O
a	O
place	O
of	O
safety	O
.	O

In	O
my	O
stern	O
room	O
the	O
uproar	O
was	O
tremendous	O
-	O
Theodore	PERSON
and	O
Clarence	PERSON
went	O
for	O
a	O
walk	O
,	O
but	O
were	O
driven	O
home	O
by	O
the	O
wind	O
and	O
rain	O
,	O
and	O
there	O
was	O
a	O
great	O
fracas	O
on	O
deck	O
,	O
getting	O
everything	O
under	O
canvass	O
,	O
safe	O
from	O
the	O
wet	O
.	O

The	O
men	O
are	O
always	O
so	O
funny	O
with	O
a	O
rain	O
-	O
like	O
children	O
with	O
a	O
snow	O
storm	O
,	O
and	O
never	O
seem	O
quite	O
to	O
know	O
what	O
to	O
do	O
-	O
67	O
miles	O
to	O
1:30	O
today	O
.	O

At	O
11	O
o'clock	O
this	O
evening	O
,	O
I	O
saw	O
two	O
or	O
three	O
stars	O
showing	O
.	O

Monday	O
,	O
March	O
22d	O
.	O

We	O
attempted	O
to	O
get	O
on	O
this	O
A.M.	O
at	O
6	O
o'clock	O
and	O
succeeded	O
only	O
in	O
making	O
a	O
start	O
and	O
were	O
driven	O
to	O
shore	O
about	O
Old	O
Cairo	LOCATION
-	O
tremendous	O
wind	O
,	O
and	O
rain	O
almost	O
amounting	O
to	O
hail	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
-	O
and	O
with	O
our	O
new	O
decks	O
so	O
warped	O
,	O
we	O
came	O
to	O
great	O
grief	O
-	O
the	O
boat	O
leaking	O
in	O
many	O
places	O
-	O
so	O
that	O
when	O
Theodore	PERSON
and	O
Clarence	PERSON
came	O
back	O
from	O
Cairo	LOCATION
,	O
where	O
they	O
went	O
and	O
had	O
lunch	O
and	O
came	O
back	O
late	O
in	O
the	O
PAGE	O
115	O
afternoon	O
-	O
they	O
found	O
us	O
with	O
curtains	O
taken	O
down	O
from	O
the	O
windows	O
,	O
and	O
bowls	O
and	O
pans	O
standing	O
about	O
everywhere	O
.	O

They	O
were	O
so	O
pleased	O
to	O
get	O
home	O
-	O
they	O
were	O
ineffably	O
amiable	O
-	O
said	O
it	O
seemed	O
after	O
Cairo	LOCATION
like	O
Paradise	O
.	O

Tuesday	O
.	O

March	O
23	O
.	O

We	O
made	O
the	O
Museum	O
landing	O
at	O
Ghizeh	LOCATION
this	O
morning	O
early	O
-	O
and	O
fortunately	O
we	O
were	O
to	O
have	O
accomplished	O
it	O
-	O
for	O
the	O
wind	O
has	O
increased	O
in	O
violence	O
-	O
it	O
has	O
been	O
a	O
gale	O
all	O
day	O
-	O
and	O
it	O
is	O
cold	O
and	O
disagreeable	O
-	O
a	O
bad	O
March	O
day	O
for	O
any	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

We	O
spent	O
a	O
pleasant	O
morning	O
however	O
at	O
the	O
Museum	O
-	O
and	O
had	O
it	O
all	O
to	O
ourselves	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
and	O
Clarence	PERSON
have	O
been	O
into	O
Cairo	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
report	O
it	O
dismal	O
.	O

Wednesday	O
.	O

March	O
24	O
.	O

A	O
gale	O
all	O
day	O
-	O
with	O
rain	O
now	O
and	O
then	O
.	O

Morning	O
at	O
the	O
Museum	O
-	O
Salah	PERSON
came	O
out	O
to	O
see	O
us	O
.	O

Thursday	O
.	O

March	O
25	O
.	O

Very	O
busy	O
all	O
the	O
morning	O
with	O
the	O
various	O
work	O
people	O
coming	O
to	O
the	O
boat	O
.	O

Carpenters	O
,	O
painters	O
,	O
upholsterer	O
,	O
sail	O
makers	O
.	O

Mary	PERSON
and	O
I	O
drove	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
-	O
charming	O
and	O
warmer	O
-	O
Cairo	LOCATION
very	O
pretty	O
with	O
flowering	O
shrubs	O
and	O
vines	O
-	O
very	O
quiet	O
and	O
empty	O
.	O

Poor	O
Abdul	PERSON
had	O
been	O
quite	O
ill	O
for	O
some	O
days	O
,	O
and	O
so	O
suffering	O
that	O
we	O
sent	O
for	O
Dr.	O
Sandwith	PERSON
yesterday	O
,	O
who	O
said	O
he	O
must	O
go	O
to	O
the	O
hospital	O
for	O
a	O
few	O
days	O
.	O

So	O
this	O
PAGE	O
116	O
morning	O
the	O
men	O
with	O
Jones	PERSON
,	O
took	O
him	O
down	O
in	O
the	O
felucca	O
-	O
being	O
able	O
to	O
go	O
quite	O
to	O
its	O
doors	O
in	O
the	O
boat	O
.	O

He	O
is	O
a	O
great	O
loss	O
to	O
us	O
just	O
at	O
present	O
not	O
being	O
simply	O
the	O
valued	O
servant	O
,	O
but	O
interpreter	O
.	O

Fortunately	O
we	O
have	O
fallen	O
back	O
on	O
Salah	PERSON
,	O
who	O
fortunately	O
has	O
no	O
engagement	O
just	O
now	O
,	O
and	O
comes	O
out	O
to	O
us	O
every	O
day	O
.	O

Excessively	O
warm	O
.	O

I	O
have	O
never	O
been	O
in	O
Cairo	LOCATION
when	O
so	O
warm	O
.	O

Friday	O
.	O

March	O
26	O
.	O

Mrs.	O
Taylor	PERSON
and	O
Florence	LOCATION
came	O
this	O
morning	O
and	O
made	O
a	O
visit	O
,	O
and	O
were	O
very	O
pleasant	O
-	O
putting	O
us	O
en	O
rapport	O
with	O
everything	O
in	O
and	O
about	O
Cairo	LOCATION
-	O
asking	O
us	O
to	O
dine	O
on	O
Saturday	O
with	O
them	O
at	O
the	O
Gesireh	O
to	O
meet	O
Sir	O
John	PERSON
Scott	PERSON
,	O
who	O
wants	O
to	O
know	O
Theodore	PERSON
,	O
and	O
whom	O
Theodore	PERSON
is	O
very	O
keen	O
to	O
meet	O
.	O

Sir	O
John	PERSON
is	O
Judicial	O
Advisor	O
to	O
the	O
Khedive	O
,	O
and	O
did	O
excellent	O
work	O
in	O
India	LOCATION
before	O
coming	O
here	O
to	O
help	O
straighten	O
out	O
Egyptian	O
affairs	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
afternoon	O
went	O
to	O
the	O
races	O
-	O
which	O
were	O
rather	O
slow	O
-	O
met	O
Mrs.	O
Hamilton	PERSON
Lang	PERSON
and	O
her	O
daughter	O
-	O
saw	O
Gen.	O
Kitchener	PERSON
,	O
the	O
Sirdâr	O
and	O
other	O
notables	O
.	O

Fourth	O
Sunday	O
in	O
Lent	O
.	O

March	O
28	O
.	O

I	O
was	O
ill	O
all	O
day	O
yesterday	O
,	O
and	O
could	O
not	O
go	O
to	O
dinner	O
with	O
Mrs.	O
Taylor	PERSON
-	O
which	O
was	O
reported	O
very	O
pleasant	O
.	O

This	O
afternoon	O
Dr.	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Sandwith	PERSON
came	O
to	O
tea	O
-	O
and	O
Mrs.	O
Taylor	PERSON
and	O
Florence	LOCATION
,	O
and	O
her	O
fiancé	O
Mr.	O
Morice	PERSON
to	O
dine	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
a	O
nice	O
evening	O
.	O

PAGE	O
117	O
Tuesday	O
,	O
March	O
30	O
.	O

Cairo	LOCATION
.	O

We	O
came	O
over	O
to	O
Shepheards	LOCATION
this	O
afternoon	O
-	O
and	O
are	O
in	O
the	O
corner	O
room	O
we	O
had	O
5	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
when	O
Fielding	O
was	O
with	O
us	O
.	O

Then	O
it	O
was	O
cold	O
and	O
we	O
had	O
a	O
fire	O
in	O
the	O
big	O
sitting	O
room	O
.	O

Now	O
it	O
is	O
so	O
hot	O
,	O
that	O
we	O
have	O
all	O
the	O
windows	O
open	O
at	O
night	O
and	O
shut	O
during	O
the	O
day	O
to	O
keep	O
out	O
the	O
heat	O
.	O

But	O
it	O
is	O
very	O
noisy	O
and	O
smelly	O
.	O

I	O
do	O
not	O
like	O
it	O
,	O
although	O
my	O
balcony	O
opens	O
on	O
the	O
pretty	O
garden	O
.	O

Hotel	O
quite	O
empty	O
-	O
very	O
tired	O
from	O
yesterday	O
-	O
packing	O
and	O
arranging	O
.	O

Wednesday	O
,	O
March	O
31	O
.	O

Over	O
at	O
the	O
boat	O
which	O
still	O
lies	O
at	O
Ghizeh	LOCATION
-	O
and	O
where	O
our	O
Rais	PERSON
intends	O
to	O
stay	O
all	O
summer	O
because	O
it	O
is	O
so	O
much	O
cooler	O
.	O

Delightful	O
drive	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
.	O

Thursday	O
,	O
April	O
1st	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
and	O
Clarence	PERSON
went	O
to	O
the	O
Courts	ORGANIZATION
of	ORGANIZATION
Justice	ORGANIZATION
this	O
morning	O
with	O
Sir	O
John	PERSON
Scott	PERSON
and	O
Mr.	O
Morice	PERSON
,	O
and	O
were	O
much	O
interested	O
.	O

Abdul	PERSON
came	O
back	O
from	O
the	O
hospital	O
,	O
very	O
weak	O
and	O
thin	O
,	O
but	O
almost	O
well	O
.	O

A	O
bothersome	O
time	O
for	O
days	O
getting	O
all	O
the	O
carpets	O
,	O
curtains	O
,	O
stuffs	O
,	O
etc.	O
of	O
the	O
boat	O
safely	O
packed	O
away	O
from	O
dangers	O
of	O
moths	O
and	O
vermin	O
.	O

The	O
boat	O
reeks	O
with	O
the	O
smell	O
of	O
Naphthaline	LOCATION
and	O
Camphor	O
.	O

The	O
poor	O
Beduin	O
,	O
so	O
changed	O
-	O
closed	O
and	O
dark	O
,	O
with	O
her	O
thick	O
brown	O
summer	O
awnings	O
enshrouding	O
her	O
-	O
all	O
the	O
men	O
gone	O
but	O
Rais	PERSON
Fuli	PERSON
,	O
and	O
Arbuk	PERSON
,	O
the	O
nice	O
little	O
crew	O
cook	O
,	O
who	O
stays	O
with	O
the	O
Captain	O
-	O
and	O
Abdul	PERSON
,	O
who	O
will	O
live	O
with	O
Fuli	PERSON
on	O
the	O
boat	O
,	O
and	O
look	O
after	O
the	O
inside	O
cleaning	O
-	O
as	O
he	O
PAGE	O
118	O
reads	O
and	O
writes	O
English	O
,	O
it	O
will	O
be	O
very	O
convenient	O
for	O
us	O
-	O
and	O
Rais	PERSON
Fuli	PERSON
is	O
immensely	O
glad	O
to	O
have	O
him	O
.	O

The	O
Taylors	ORGANIZATION
sailed	O
for	O
Marseilles	LOCATION
today	O
in	O
the	O
Clyde	O
.	O

Friday	O
,	O
April	O
2d	O
.	O

We	O
were	O
obliged	O
to	O
go	O
again	O
to	O
the	O
boat	O
to	O
confer	O
with	O
the	O
old	O
French	O
painter	O
as	O
to	O
the	O
colours	O
for	O
the	O
outside	O
.	O

Then	O
goodbye	O
to	O
all	O
-	O
and	O
a	O
delightful	O
drive	O
.	O

Theodore	PERSON
and	O
Clarence	PERSON
on	O
their	O
horses	O
with	O
us	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
way	O
.	O

The	O
air	O
has	O
been	O
quite	O
delightful	O
for	O
2	O
days	O
-	O
all	O
our	O
friends	O
beg	O
us	O
to	O
stay	O
for	O
the	O
charming	O
April	O
weather	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
off	O
tomorrow	O
morning	O
for	O
Alexandria	LOCATION
and	O
sail	O
for	O
Brindisi	LOCATION
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
.	O

Rome	LOCATION
.	O

Bristol	LOCATION
Hotel	LOCATION
.	O

April	O
15	O
.	O

A	O
long	O
interval	O
in	O
this	O
journal	O
.	O

We	O
left	O
Alexandria	LOCATION
the	O
afternoon	O
of	O
the	O
3d	O
in	O
the	O
fine	O
new	O
S.S.	LOCATION
Bohemia	LOCATION
for	O
Brindisi	LOCATION
.	O
